<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Renuka Vyavahare on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/renuka-vyavahare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Renuka Vyavahare on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 08:37:59 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/renuka-vyavahare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 08:37:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To win over her best friends and wriggle out of a sticky situation, poor little rich girl Pia Jaisingh (Khushi Kapoor) convinces her new classmate, a career-driven Arjun Mehta (Ibrahim Ali Khan) to be her rental boyfriend. The Instagram love story looks perfect on reels until things get real between the two. You can predict this story as soon as it begins. It follows the tropes of any teen romance. Pia offers Rs 25K a week to Arjun, an aspiring lawyer to get him to pretend as her boyfriend. She’s a wealthy Delhi girl; he’s from Greater Noida. He thinks love is a distraction, she thinks her world revolves around love. Her family’s patriarchal, his parents are liberal. Despite the differences, the two make a deal. She soft launches him on her socials before the big reveal. What happens when the two catch feelings?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chhaava</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 09:28:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on Shivaji Sawant&amp;rsquo;s Marathi novel, Chhaava (lion&amp;rsquo;s cub) aims to acknowledge the bravery of Shambhu Raje (Sambhaji Maharaj played by Vicky Kaushal), that most history books haven’t been able to. There’s more to him than being Shivaji’s son who was betrayed by his own men, captured and brutally executed by Aurangzeb (played by Akshaye Khanna). The film sheds light on why he was widely revered by his people and feared by rivals in the nine years that he held the Maratha throne. Still reeling from the loss of his father, Sambhaji and Sersenapati Hambirrao Mohite (essayed by Ashutosh Rana) invaded Mughal stronghold Burhanpur right under their nose. For the nine years that followed, Sambhaji trampled on Mughals’ expansion plans making him a thorn in their side. Sambhaji’s bravery overcame the betrayal he faced by his own people until he was ambushed and captured in Sangameshwar. Even his brutal execution couldn’t kill his warrior spirit and fight for Swaraj.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Want to Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:10:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In denial initially, this traumatic health crisis, numbs the pain of everything else in comparison including a broken marriage and financial downfall. What follows is countless hospital visits and an unpredictable future which tests the relationship Arjun shares with his daughter Reya.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Arjun is bruised not broken. There’s a certain nonchalance about Shoojit Sircar’s (Piku, October) gaze as a storyteller. It grows on you slowly and steadily. As it happens in life too, emotions are not always verbalised or expressed freely. There’s a lot of withholding and long pauses, which can be perceived as detachment or aloofness but it’s just him using silence and monotony to lead you to that breaking point. The one, you don’t see coming. There’s a certain stillness to story progression and yet you find yourself immersed in every scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All We Imagine as Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:18:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Payal Kapadia’s enchanting ode to sisterhood and the glaring contrasts of Mumbai has a tranquil charm to it. There’s a certain tenderness and ease to the flow in storytelling that makes you see the city in a new light, even if you have been a Mumbaikar all your life. Watching Kapadia’s three protagonists setting themselves free from societal and psychological shackles to embrace their desires, gives you that warm fuzzy feeling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 20:23:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/here/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Life happens while you&amp;rsquo;re busy making other plans’. ‘Here’ is a moving love letter to life and fleeting time. The iconic Forrest Gump team (Hanks, Wright, Zemeckis) reunites after 30 years to give us yet another poignant human story on the evolution and circle of life. While one constantly looks ahead, the story urges you to live in the present, live ‘here’, where every beginning is the end and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:30:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping with the theme of the franchise, Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 also pits an unassuming cheeky protagonist against a spooky haveli with a buried past. The century-old mansion needs to be restored to its former glory and sold, but Manjulika’s terrorising presence in it forbids the owners from doing so. The royal family in dire need of resources, seeks Rooh baba’s intervention. The fraudster takes up the lucrative offer only to find himself tangled in a mess as he discovers two dark forces who claim to be Manjulika.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:15:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twins Saumya and Shailee (Kriti Sanon in a double role, this is not a spoiler) are like chalk and cheese. One gets married to hot-headed Dhruv Sood, (television actor Shaheer Sheikh) the privileged man with a volatile temper and political connect who owns a paragliding business in the hills. All’s well on the surface until an unlikely crime makes police officer VJ (Kajol) question everything about this family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do Patti is deceptive. In an ideal scenario, this could have worked wonders as a thriller but that’s not the case here. Do Patti is deceptive as a film, not as a mystery. You are led on and lured into believing that there’s more to this long-winding twin sister saga but it’s all a damp squib. For some strange reason, you pin your hopes on the big twist that might redeem the situation but that wish stays unfulfilled as it&amp;rsquo;s predictable and underwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vicky Vidya Ka Woh Wala Video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 12:32:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set in the late 90’s, the pre-Instagram era, when ‘get ready with me’ reels were non-existent, privacy had a different meaning. Without having the platform to post their private life anywhere, couples voluntarily recording their intimate moments was still a rare phenomenon. So on paper, the film’s script sounds promising. What happens when this private video belonging to a middle-class couple from Rishikesh goes missing? What are the repercussions and can they retrieve it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
