<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sachin Chatte on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/sachin-chatte/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sachin Chatte on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 16:04:15 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/sachin-chatte/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 16:04:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Empuraan, the sequel to the 2019 Malayalam film Lucifer, is a high-budget, globe-trotting actioner reminiscent of productions from YRF or the Tamil and Telugu film industry. The success of its predecessor has elevated the scale and ambition of this installment. However, with such ambition often comes the risk of overlooking essential elements in favor of a grander vision. In this instance, the screenplay suffers due to an emphasis on extravagant action, where style frequently overshadows substance.&#xA;At nearly three hours in length, the film initially packs in a great deal of content but later tends to meander. Prithviraj, who has transitioned from actor to director, possesses the vision necessary for a project of this magnitude, yet the foundational material must be robust. The film clearly aims to appeal to mass audiences, featuring slow-motion sequences and other stylistic choices. While there is nothing inherently wrong with this approach, it occasionally aspires to get serious,, and the fusion of these elements does not always produce the desired effect. It is helpful to recall key details from Lucifer, which was released five years ago. The narrative reintroduces international crime syndicates and the underworld, with Khureshi (Mohanlal) returning to the fray. Regrettably, the local character Stephen Nedumpally, also portrayed by Mohanlal and central to the action in Lucifer, takes a back seat in this sequel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alien: Romulus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/alien-romulus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:48:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/alien-romulus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Alien franchise has been active for over four decades now, starting from 1979, and has seen at least three big names associated with it as directors. Ridley Scott started it all as a director followed by James Cameron and then David Fincher made the third installment in 1992. The subsequent three films were underwhelming even though Scott returned as the director for the last two films.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alien: Romulus is the seventh film in the franchise (not counting the two crossover films) and brings back memories of the first two films, in a good way. Directed by Fede Alvarez (of Don’t Breathe and the new Evil Dead fame), Romulus sticks to the basics without complicating the plot too much. It reminds us of the thrills and chills that Scott and Cameron delivered in the first two films and makes up for these elements that were sorely missing in Prometheus and Covenant. Those last two films had too much talk and little action. But Alvarez is clear about the tone and direction in which he wants to take Romulus – the mantra is to keep it simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:46:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Pushpa naam nahi hain, Pushpa matlab brand hain”, (Pushpa is not just a name; it signifies a brand) states Srivalli, portrayed by Rashmika Mandanna, in this sequel anticipated to shatter all box office records. This statement prompts reflection on whether it is the character speaking or if the filmmakers are conveying their confidence through her words. Following the success of Pushpa (2021), the sequel is grander in every aspect, running an exhausting 200 minutes, though it does not necessarily surpass its predecessor. The filmmakers have amplified every successful element from the first installment, leaving no stone unturned in terms of scale and ambition. However, the narrative, or lack of it, remains unchanged—if the first part emphasised “Pushpa flower nahin, fire hai main”, the second part shifts to portraying him as a wildfire, whatever that may imply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:28:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a good time to a make a ‘horror-comedy’ in Hindi cinema, in this case, rehash a film with a sequel of an established franchise. In this genre, you don’t really have to focus on the horror part (the audience laughs at it anyway, in many cases, it is nervous laughter) and for the comedy part, you just have to put a few characters in a ‘horror’ situation and voila, the comedy element is sorted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:26:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rohit Shetty’s cop universe has gone for the jugular this time. Following the lukewarm reception of Simmba (2018) and Sooryavanshi (2021), he has reintroduced his flagship character, Singham, while also incorporating other familiar figures in Singham Again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:52:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amal Neerad&amp;rsquo;s Bougainvillea features an impressive cast, including Kunchacko Boban, Jyothirmay, and Fahadh Faasil; however, the film ultimately flatters to deceive. Faasil is relegated to a tertiary role, likely either to help out his friends or for a fat paycheck – probably the former. Pitched as a psychological thriller, the film becomes exasperating due to its screenplay and overall execution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a film of this nature, a concise narrative is essential, along with an assumption that the audience possesses a degree of intelligence—an area where Bougainvillea falters. Neerad&amp;rsquo;s method involves showing then explaining, and then repeating the &amp;lsquo;show part again for those who may still not have grasped it. For example, the film repeatedly informs viewers about the kidnapping of three girls. Once the perpetrator is revealed – something that becomes evident well before the actual disclosure – there is little value in depicting all three kidnappings in flashback, as the method remains consistent and ultimately becomes irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:48:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Wild Robot, inspired by Peter Brown&amp;rsquo;s 2016 novel of the same&#xA;name, is a film that skillfully balances its emotional elements, resulting in a gratifying experience for both children and adults. While the notion of a robot experiencing emotions is not entirely original, it is the narrative and its execution that truly set this film apart. Achieving the right emotional resonance, whether from a human or a robot, is crucial, and Chris Sanders has struck gold with this film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 19:03:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drawing inspiration from Dharma Productions&amp;rsquo; own film Gumraah (1993), which was itself influenced by the miniseries Bangkok Hilton (1989), Jigra features Alia Bhatt in the lead role of a prison-break drama. The original source material was not particularly strong; in the earlier film, Sanjay Dutt portrayed a hero rescuing his beloved Sri Devi from a Hong Kong prison, whereas in this adaptation, the narrative shifts to a brother-sister dynamic where the sister must save her brother.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
