<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Good American Family on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/good-american-family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Good American Family on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 09:02:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/good-american-family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Good American Family</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/good-american-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 09:02:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/good-american-family/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There have several documentaries and series dissecting the curious case of Natalia Grace, a young Ukrainian girl with dwarfism adopted by an American couple. Later, the couple, Kristen and Michael Barnett, allege that they&amp;rsquo;ve been misled and Natalia is actually an adult. The adoption drama, which later escalates into a legal trial, is detailed in the new JioHotstar series, Good American Family, led by Ellen Pompeo and Mark Duplass. The tone of the series feels similar to a horror film or a car crash, when you know that the inevitable is upon you soon. Kristen (Ellen Pompeo) and Michael Barnett (Mark Duplass) already have a strained marriage, raising three boys, including one with autism. They are seeking to adopt a young girl to complete their family. Kristen is shown as a selfless Midwestern mother, running a rec center for special needs and raising her autistic son, who is considered a prodigy. Meanwhile, Michael is shown as slightly more needy and unable to handle the larger pressures of life. Their marriage is one crack away from splitting when Natalia Grace (Imogen Faith Reid) enters their home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
