<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Monkey on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-monkey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Monkey on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:56:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-monkey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Monkey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-monkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:56:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-monkey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The film based on a short story by Stephen King gives a take of its own but twist of comedy and creativity liberties to cover for a feature film&amp;rsquo;s run time. Directed by Osgood Perkins known for his recent release Longlegs, has turned for another horror but this time it comes with a comedy twist. The film led by Theo James follows the story of twins, who didn&amp;rsquo;t get much from their father, but a haunted Monkey toy. But its not a toy, its like an &amp;lsquo;Evil thing&amp;rsquo;. Everyone is the safest when the monkey isn&amp;rsquo;t beating the drum it came with, but the amount of gore in the film, nobody is safe. The film begins with Adam Scott aka Petey Shelburn Sr trying his best to return the Monkey to a shop but is unable to as its next victim as soon as it plays the drums, a chain reaction ends up claiming the live of the shop owner. Leaving it behind isn&amp;rsquo;t enough for Petey and he decides to use a flame thrower to melt it down but years later it safely finds its way to Petey&amp;rsquo;s twin kids. It is unclear what happened to Petey, but with everything that goes on in the film, it really could have ended any way for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
