<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Companion on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/companion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Companion on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 23:32:06 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/companion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Companion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/companion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 23:32:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/companion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EARLY ON in Drew Hancock’s Companion, two young women named Iris (Sophie Thatcher) and Kat (Megan Suri) have a prickly moment on a boozy night. When Iris asks why Kat — a close friend of Iris’ new lover Josh (Jack Quaid) — doesn’t like her, a tipsy Kat says she just doesn’t like the ‘idea’ of her. “You make me feel replaceable,” she continues. The conceit of this confession is two-pronged. Iris is deeply in love with her new boyfriend Josh, but Kat is in an abusive relationship with a controlling Russian man; the obvious implication is that Kat is bitter. But the real implication emerges a scene or two later, when the film reveals that Iris (“Siri” when spelt backwards) is actually a companion robot. Up until then, it speaks volumes that the average male viewer may not be able to tell. Iris loves Josh so much that she is subservient to him — she wants to please him by hanging out with his friends on a weekend getaway, she craves to see him smile, and sex for them is basically Josh grunting and rolling over to sleep. It’s all too familiar. So Kat saying she feels &amp;ldquo;replaceable&amp;rdquo; by Iris is the film admitting that — in a world captured by the male gaze — a woman robot is no different from a woman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
