<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rahul Desai on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/rahul-desai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rahul Desai on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:49:06 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/rahul-desai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sikandar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:49:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given Hindi cinema’s twin obsession with nepotism and nationalism, it’s hard not to be nostalgic about a dopey Salman Khan movie. The badness of a family entertainer like Sikandar is harmless, vintage, candid, pure almost. It has no ulterior motive, no genre, no affiliations; it’s a festival release, but the festival may as well be a Salman Khan release. It’s just there: a 150-minute montage of intro shots and ad slogans parading as punchlines. In other words, Sikandar is a dying breed of Bollywood vice. I’ve kind of missed it. The brain melts, but at least the spirit stays intact. It’s so critic-proof that I’m heaving a sigh of relief as I write this — there’s no prospect of offending anyone because nobody cares. Happy days. Both its villains are bald, so hair propaganda is the closest it comes to taking a stand. The closest it comes to being political is Khan playing a Rajkot resident who (occasionally) speaks Gujarati, a language that gives him a direct line to New Delhi. The closest it comes to meta referencing is when this godly hero delivers its actor’s thoughts while punishing an errant minister: “I don’t know about PM or CM, I can easily be an MLA or MP, but I’m not interested. Don’t force me to be interested”. It’s so strong on fan service that when Khan breaks the fourth wall during an action sequence, he doesn’t look at the camera; the camera looks at him. It even reverses the anxiety around modern technology: the acting all around is so robotic that AI would in fact humanise it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Bag</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:03:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-bag/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the sexiest thrillers aren’t about the plot. They invite the viewer to slice through a perfectly sculpted body—not murderously, of course—and try to find a tiny, beating heart within. The sleekness of the body matters. And perhaps no contemporary filmmaker encourages such surgical eroticism more than Steven Soderbergh. His movies are so wildly watchable — even when they’re not great — because the style itself is the substance. Black Bag is perhaps his most complete work in a decade; it’s a London-set spy thriller where the very concept of espionage becomes a parable for the devaluation of trust in modern-day relationships. Soderbergh and writer David Koepp don’t come at it from a nostalgic back-in-our-day space. If anything, they fetishise what it takes to keep a tradition alive in an institution that’s rigged against the anatomy of faith. The framework is clever. The film revolves around a cold-blooded British intelligence agent, George (Michael Fassbender), who must investigate a top-secret leak and find the traitor among his colleagues. The details are not important; let’s just say there’s the standard threat of a nuclear meltdown and dissolved governments. One of the five suspects, however, is Kathryn (Cate Blanchett), his wife and fellow intelligence agent. George and Kathryn are kind of an urban legend in the spy world — not because they’re excellent at what they do, but because they’re married and intensely committed to each other in a vocation that requires duplicity, roleplay and moral ambiguity. They’re a social anomaly, so much so that a dinner invite to their home feels like a “visit to our parents”. It’s a marriage so solid that when George goes up to Kathryn’s floor, everyone in her meeting (including her superior) automatically pauses — you can almost hear the mental eyerolls in the room. They’re used to it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delulu Express</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/delulu-express/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 09:58:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/delulu-express/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching a Zakir Khan stand-up special is like watching that funny friend from your childhood actually find his true calling. It’s sort of moving, because you know for a fact that none of those friends took their talent seriously. Society simply reduces them to a personality type — the witty guy, the joker, the attention seeker, the mischief monger, the crowd pleaser, the yapper. If anything, they barely recognise it as a talent. Khan’s sets often feel like an authentication of such transient, everyday humour. His languid delivery expands the most ordinary details into mini-narratives of being alive. Which is to say: Zakir Khan isn’t a comedian; he’s a very good storyteller with comic timing. He isn’t really funny; he’s funnily real.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Santosh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/santosh-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:55:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/santosh-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Santosh is two movies. The first is rooted in how Santosh, meaning “contentment” or “happiness”, is traditionally a man’s name. This underdog movie is about Santosh Saini (Shahana Goswami), a 28-year-old widow who inherits her late husband’s police job. As a new woman constable, Santosh strives to make a name in the notoriously masculine field of law enforcement. She finds a mentor in Geeta Sharma (Sunita Rajwar), a veteran cop who has over the years become a symbol of feminism and gender empowerment. Together, they investigate the brutal rape and murder of a 15-year-old girl. Santosh impresses her superiors, transcends her “compassionate appointment” (or bereavement quota) image, reclaims her own identity, and chases the case. This is the film that a specific India believes in: an inspiring coming-of-age story, a narrative of human fortitude, a gritty tale of patriarchy smashing and female agency. Santosh herself believes in it. It’s her against the world. But this is also the film that’s sold to this India. One that’s bereft of complexity, truth, ambiguity and labels. Ignorance, as they say, is bliss — or contentment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanneda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 23:38:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kanneda, the title of this eight-episode drama, is “Canada” pronounced with a Punjabi twang. The theme is clear — an Indian immigrant story that unfolds in the awkward cultural gap between Kanneda and Canada. The setting is Vancouver in the 1990s; the narrator helpfully tells us that racism is rampant and Punjabis continue to be treated as second-class citizens. The central character is Nirmal ‘Nimma’ Chahal (Parmish Verma), a young and hotheaded chap who slowly mutates from fairytale to cautionary tale. It’s a familiar journey: Nimma starts off honest (a rugby scholarship to kickstart a music career), before losing faith in the system and getting into the drugs-and-gangster business. Flashbacks allegedly suggest that his family left Punjab during the 1984 Anti-Sikh riots, but his trauma looks anything but generational.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khakee: The Bengal Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/khakee-the-bengal-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:39:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/khakee-the-bengal-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like Khakee: The Bihar Chapter (2022), creator Neeraj Pandey’s standalone sequel Khakee: The Bengal Chapter represents the awkward second rung of crime thriller television — too trashy to be taken seriously, too serious to be pulpy, too long to be bingeable, and too predictable to be culturally specific. It’s more or less an old-school Prakash Jha potboiler stretched into long-form entertainment. A loaded ensemble and the illusion of a grassroots narrative are supposed to offset the generic tone, a cyclical plot and a repetitive landscape. This time, the focus is Kolkata in the early 2000s, where a no-nonsense IPS officer arrives to clean up a city ripe with bloody gang wars, sinister politicians and confused cops. A reporter exclaims: “Is the City of Joy now the City of Bhoy (fear)?”. Thankfully, the show explicitly mentions the timeframe at some point, because this is the one city that makes it hard to distinguish a period setting from a modern one. Timelessness is an aesthetic here; I assumed it was 2025 until I spotted a character holding a Nokia 6600 (which still made it look like 2022). Unfortunately, rumours of a Sourav Ganguly cameo in this seven-episode drama remain rumours, despite there being plenty of scope for a princely outsider with shirt-twirling charisma leading a team of gritty underdogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/adolescence-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 10:07:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/adolescence-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first part of Adolescence opens with a 13-year-old boy, Jamie (Owen Cooper), being arrested on suspicion of murder. It’s early morning. The family home is raided by the police; DI Luke Bascombe (Ashley Walters) and DS Misha Frank (Faye Marsay) take Jamie to the police station. Jamie tearfully goes through the detainment process. He is strip-searched, his father Eddie (Stephen Graham) agrees to be his ‘appropriate adult’ and a local solicitor arrives to represent Jamie. The two cops then interrogate the boy. For much of this episode, as grown-up viewers, we are wired to watch these proceedings through the lens of one question: Did he do it? At some level, we experience it as an investigative thriller: a murder mystery where the suspense lies in the answer. When Jamie quietly tells his dad that he is innocent, it’s hard not to believe the kid. He sounds truthful. It’s probably all a mistake and he’s protecting a wayward friend or elder. We look at the father as a portrait of complicity, too — closely judging every word, glance and gesture of his. DI Bascombe mentions a previous juvenile case where none of them noticed years of sexual abuse. But the end of the episode shows that Jamie did do it. He brutally stabbed his schoolmate Katie to death in a carpark the previous night. The cops had proof all along. His guilt was never in doubt. There is no confession. The anti-climax lies in the eyes of the beholder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Happy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/be-happy-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 07:55:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/be-happy-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you watch Hindi cinema for a living (or a loving), chances are you will be cursed with the Red Flag Syndrome. What is this syndrome, you ask? (You didn’t ask, but I’m telling you anyway because clunky exposition is in my DNA). Being able to identify red flags in a film — or being able to see through a story within the first few scenes — used to be a superpower. But now it’s almost a crime, like X-ray vision for perverse superheroes: you’re accused of seeing the film naked. It took me all of 30 seconds to commit this crime with Be Happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Diplomat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 07:52:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;he Diplomat has all the elements of a solid thriller. The drama is Argo (2012) and Bridge of Spies (2015)-coded, where one government agent must negotiate the safe return of a citizen trapped in a seemingly hostile country. The premise is almost ready-made. The film is inspired by the true story of Uzma Ahmed (played by Sadia Khateeb), a woman who arrives at the Indian embassy in Islamabad desperately seeking refuge; she claims to have been tricked into marrying an abusive Pakistani man who kept her captive in the mountains. Deputy High Commissioner J.P. Singh (John Abraham) takes charge, determined to guide her through a maze of media scrutiny, red tape, court trials and political tensions. All he has are words and aura, in addition to the support of the Minister of External Affairs (based on the late Sushma Swaraj) from New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humans in the Loop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/humans-in-the-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 07:59:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/humans-in-the-loop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great concept can be a curse. Take the one-liner of Humans in the Loop, for instance. An Adivasi single mother named Nehma (Sonal Madhushankar) starts working as a ‘data labeller,’ a job that requires her to train AI models to recognise the world in pictures and videos. This one-liner alone is so fertile — so ripe with cultural parables and documentary minimalism — that it’s hard to imagine a fictional film that expands on it. What can a feature-length story express that isn’t already implicit?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Waking of a Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:34:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In cricket, when the fielding team challenges an LBW (Leg Before Wicket) call, the DRS (Decision Review System) comes into play. This DRS process is a lot like reviewing a film or show. Every stage corresponds to real-world parameters. First, the third umpire checks if it’s a legal delivery — the equivalent of checking if the craft and shot-taking and basic staging are fundamentally sound. Then they move onto Snickometer to see if there’s an edge off the bat or glove — the equivalent of checking if the storytelling is engaging. Finally, Ball Tracking is used to project the trajectory of the delivery. Even here, it doesn’t matter if the ball is hitting the stumps, it has to pitch in line — the equivalent of checking if the intent and politics of the narrative add up. If all checks out, the on-field decision can be reversed and the batsman is ruled out — the equivalent of defying an anti-art industry and making a good show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:18:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a wonder that after 12 years of professional film criticism and finding creative ways to pan ghastly Bollywood movies, the deepest thought that entered my head after watching Nadaaniyan was: “I want to kick this film”. Such a primal, crude urge. Kick, really? So much for all those analytical skills and fancy words. All those carefully constructed rants and sarcastic takedowns. It’s the kind of thought that’s second to an animalistic grunt. I should do better. I should be calmer. But hey, at least I’m calling myself out here. At least I’m admitting that my brain is broken and incapable of making sense. That makes me ‘Self-Aware’. And self-awareness is a superpower that we often abuse to weaponise our flaws. In this day and age, an idiot that knows they’re an idiot is automatically wise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dupahiya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dupahiya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:04:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dupahiya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember watching the first season of Panchayat (2020) and thinking: Wow, this is going to change things. And it did. It altered the way we perceived “comedy” as a serious genre. It was very exciting to see a simple, slice-of-life environment — the iconic fictional village of Phulera and its bittersweet characters — seared into the modern streaming lexicon. But I’d be lying if I said I was blindly optimistic. At the back of my mind, there was this fear — a fear derived from years of watching Hindi cinema overkill a new sensation. Nobody knows how to quit while they’re ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazxy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crazxy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:33:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crazxy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a thriller opens with a long single-take shot, it’s a signal of intent. For a film called Crazxy — the spelling can be triggering until you realise it has something to do with an extra chromosome — this signal is very necessary. The shot starts on an &amp;lsquo;Ethical Dilemma of Surgery’ book, snakes across the posh apartment and follows its inhabitant, Abhimanyu Sood (Sohum Shah), as he leaves with a bag of cash to his garage. Jesper Kyd’s music is a hybrid of an Ennio Morricone spaghetti-western score and an ‘80s Bachchan potboiler. Within the next five minutes, we learn that this hassled man is a doctor, the amount of money is five crores, it’s April Fool’s Day, his angry boss is waiting at the hospital, and Abhimanyu has Haryanvi driving genes (he takes on a rowdy Gurgaon biker to return a middle finger). It’s clear that Crazxy means business. It’s also clear that Crazxy is better than its title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:19:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fictional translations of ready-made underdog journeys make me nervous. As do independent themes getting the mainstream treatment. A recent example is Taika Waititi’s Next Goal Wins (2023), a sports comedy about “the weakest football team in the world” that reduced its source material (a fantastic 2014 documentary) to a checklist of sef-conscious tropes. In terms of concept and design, Superboys of Malegaon ticks both boxes. Directed by Reema Kagti and written by Varun Grover, the 131-minute feature is inspired by Faiza Ahmad Khan’s Supermen of Malegaon (2012), a charming 65-minute documentary that revolves around the cinema-crazy residents of a small Maharashtrian town who start their own DIY-filmmaking ecosystem of Bollywood spoofs. I remember watching Khan’s documentary and marvelling at how it married the objectivity of journalism with the subjectivity of emotion. It allowed the story to tell itself, while trusting the ‘characters’ to underline its humour with cultural meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Companion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/companion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 23:32:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/companion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;EARLY ON in Drew Hancock’s Companion, two young women named Iris (Sophie Thatcher) and Kat (Megan Suri) have a prickly moment on a boozy night. When Iris asks why Kat — a close friend of Iris’ new lover Josh (Jack Quaid) — doesn’t like her, a tipsy Kat says she just doesn’t like the ‘idea’ of her. “You make me feel replaceable,” she continues. The conceit of this confession is two-pronged. Iris is deeply in love with her new boyfriend Josh, but Kat is in an abusive relationship with a controlling Russian man; the obvious implication is that Kat is bitter. But the real implication emerges a scene or two later, when the film reveals that Iris (“Siri” when spelt backwards) is actually a companion robot. Up until then, it speaks volumes that the average male viewer may not be able to tell. Iris loves Josh so much that she is subservient to him — she wants to please him by hanging out with his friends on a weekend getaway, she craves to see him smile, and sex for them is basically Josh grunting and rolling over to sleep. It’s all too familiar. So Kat saying she feels &amp;ldquo;replaceable&amp;rdquo; by Iris is the film admitting that — in a world captured by the male gaze — a woman robot is no different from a woman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kuch Sapney Apne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kuch-sapney-apne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:24:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kuch-sapney-apne/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some movies break your heart when they’re not good. A chunk of filmmaker-activist Sridhar Rangayan’s filmography — which focuses on queer subjects and LGBTQ-themed stories — falls into this category. The chasm between intent and execution is as wide as the chasm between fact and fiction in Hindi historical biopics. Distinguishing between the two is important; criticising the craft of a film is not the same as panning its cause. If social significance alone were a yardstick for meaningful cinema, Rangayan’s latest (co-directed and co-written with Saagar Gupta), Kuch Sapney Apne, would be the Love Actually of the genre. A sequel to his previous feature, Evening Shadows (2018), Kuch Sapney Apne expands its multi-narrative snapshot of an orthodox South Indian family at the crossroads. The conflict is now married to its consequences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mere Husband Ki Biwi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mere-husband-ki-biwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:22:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mere-husband-ki-biwi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mere Husband Ki Biwi is such a generic and run-of-the-mill North Indian production that if it were edible, it’d be a half-crispy aloo paratha for breakfast. If it were a person, it’d be Rocky Randhawa (without the self-awareness) from Rocky Aur Rani Kii Prem Kahaani. If it were an emotion, it’d be the entitled rage of drivers at the Delhi-Gurgaon toll plaza. If it were a place, it’d be a breezy mustard field — but only as a painting in an upscale art gallery. I can go on, but you get the gist. It looks like every other entry in the genre: glossy, distant, intermittently alive but ultimately soulless. At least it’s environmentally conscious, because it recycles a whole book of tropes: the wise-ass best friend played by a comedian; a lustful Shakti Kapoor character; a quirky voice-over starting the film but disappearing after the introduction; an Amritsari girl who addresses her husband by either his surname, yaar, baby or baby yaar; a love triangle between a Chaddha, a Dhillon and a Khanna where two of them spend an entire half secretly competing with each other for the ‘prize’; a dozen slow-mo shots of them walking towards, past or away from each other with contempt and pride; an overseas almost-wedding; and so on and so (un)forth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oops! Ab Kya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/oops-ab-kya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:19:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/oops-ab-kya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the worst thing about Oops! Ab Kya? is its title. The eight-episode series is an Indian remake of Jane the Virgin, the hit American dramedy centered on the life of a chaste Latina virgin who becomes pregnant after a routine hospital visit turns into an artificial insemination accident. Oops! Ab Kya? (if I repeat this title enough, maybe it’ll stop sounding terrible) is a serviceable show on its own. It has a decent cast: Shweta Basu Prasad finally gets an author-backed role of sorts, while the supporting gang is gamely led by veterans like Sonali Kulkarni and Jaaved Jaaferi. The young-and-awkward Dice Media aesthetic lends itself naturally to the show’s unserious tone. For once, the artifice and DIY stagey-ness of its setting aren’t deal breakers. And it helps that the original show aims beyond its one-line gimmick: every character becomes a protagonist of their own little storyline. There’s not much to tell the main dish from the garnish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhoom Dhaam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:46:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hindi cinema can be middling in two ways. The first way is common — a movie settles for mediocrity despite a decent idea. The second way is not as common — a movie strives for mediocrity when the idea gets greedy. Dhoom Dhaam somehow manages to uphold both ways at once. It’s disappointing because it could’ve been better, but it’s also fine because it could’ve been worse. The one thing that’s undeniable, however, is the conveyor-belt nature of the modern streaming picture. Every time it threatens to be enjoyable, a peculiar factory-produced tone emerges. The story here is a romantic comedy: Mr. Chalk and Ms. Cheese have an arranged marriage only to belatedly discover their differences. They’re nothing like the eligible partners their families “advertised” them as. The more they learn about each other, the more complicated it becomes. Hidden faults jump out; either they’ll fall for each other or fall apart. The USP of Dhoom Dhaam is that this entire marital journey — which might take years or decades in the real world — is condensed into 24 chaotic hours featuring shady cops, possible gangsters, a masked robbery gone wrong, a mysterious package called Charlie, a horny dog, a kidnapped uncle, and a bunch of chases and escapes across Mumbai. In short, the cross-cultural romcom is accelerated by the black comedy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chhaava</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 17:44:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At its worst, the Tour de France turned moral decay into a non-factor. Doping among Lance Armstrong-era cyclists was so normalised that, perversely, the sport became a level-playing field. The logic being: if everybody cheats, is it even cheating anymore? It’s simply about who cheats — or performs — the best. The Bollywood period biopic is in a similar position today. It goes without saying that history and mythology are used as pawns to checkmate old-school notions of secularism. It goes without saying that the game being played is more modern. ‘Hidden’ themes like Islamophobia, bigotry, propaganda, erasure and jingoism are so normal that we barely notice them anymore. It’s the default pitch; that’s why “keeping the politics aside” is a common phrase. The irony is that, unlike the cyclists, such movies are so fundamentally broken that nobody wins. Cultural doping makes it a level-playing field of mediocrity and delusion. It’s like watching them race not to the finish line but straight off the top of a mountain. And not just any mountain, Mount Everest itself. Why stop there?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bobby Aur Rishi Ki Love Story</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bobby-aur-rishi-ki-love-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:28:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bobby-aur-rishi-ki-love-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m running out of polite ways to say that most Bollywood launch vehicles are vanity vans parading as commercial movies. I’m running out of impolite ways to say that most Hindi rom-coms feature nepotism hires and Gen Z characters who speak like outdated youngsters at a debutante ball imagined by out-of-touch boomers. I’m also running out of ways to say that I’m running out of ways. Kunal Kohli’s Bobby Aur Rishi Ki Love Story looks like it was written in 1995, shot in 2005, scored in 2015, edited in 1985, colour corrected in 1975 and released in 2025. Remember the annoying animated couple from Kohli’s hit, Hum Tum (2005)? Those two were still more realistic and less cringey than the live-action couple in this film, who do the walking-and-talking-in-Europe (or post-Brexit Britain) jig as if Dilwale Dulhania Le Jayenge and Before Sunrise were in-flight tourist videos rather than classic landscape changers. They start as enemies, become frenemies and turn into screechy soulmates — all with the artistic spirit of a paid vacation and the emotional awareness of an oblivious meme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anuja</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/anuja/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 13:10:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/anuja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On paper, Anuja is a noble project. It’s made in association with Salaam Baalak Trust, a Delhi-based non-profit organisation that supports street kids. It stars one of its children, Sajda Pathan, as a gifted nine-year-old garment factory worker who is conflicted between earning a livelihood and getting an education. It&amp;rsquo;s an Indian American production. It is backed by diaspora-global celebrities like Mindy Kaling, Priyanka Chopra Jonas and Guneet Monga Kapoor. And it&amp;rsquo;s about spirited orphans in a big bad world. Which is to say: Anuja is so noble that it&amp;rsquo;s only a project. At its best, it&amp;rsquo;s a creative presentation slide. At its worst, it&amp;rsquo;s less of a short film and more of a look-poor-people-hungry-people aesthetic. It brings back memories of the famous and infamous Slumdog Millionaire (2008) — and not in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Dreams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sweet-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 22:31:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sweet-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sweet Dreams has a sweet premise. It begins with a J.R.R. Tolkien quote, setting the stage for a fantasy-coded romcom. And it opens with a dreamy date between a flirty Diya (Mithila Palkar) and the cool Kennith (Amol Parashar) at a cafe. We soon learn that this is a shared dream between two strangers — a recurring habit for both — leading completely different lives. Kennith, an influencer and recycle artist, is newly single and he speaks to his psychiatrist (Faye D’Souza; a surprise-but-meek cameo) about this mysterious girl he keeps meeting in his dreams. He’s convinced she exists. Diya, a career drifter who writes and sings, is in an autopilot relationship with Ishant (Meiyang Chang); she, too, is baffled by how real and tangible her dreams feel. The film follows their attempts to find each other and (re)unite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:46:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to be disappointed with Sky Force. One, through the lens of its creators. Up until now, the production company Maddock Films — on a high following the dizzying success of its horror-comedy multiverse — has managed to innovate and stay interesting without conforming to mass trends and jingoistic patterns. It’s worth noting that Sky Force is its first real foray into this zone. But within the contours of the herd-mentality move, it tries something different. It chooses to dramatise a real-life story that’s equal parts war movie and investigative drama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:52:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Real Pain, starring Eisenberg and Kieran Culkin as cousins, is exactly the kind of film you imagine if Eisenberg and Culkin played cousins. It’s funny, awkward, edgy, poignant, light, chatty, alert, minor-key and Sundancey (an adjective for the brand of tragicomic American quirk that the snowy festival loves to showcase). There are echoes of the uptight mom and no-filter teen from the actor’s directorial debut, When You Finish Saving The World, in the uptight David (Eisenberg) and the free-spirited-but-troubled Benji (Culkin). Family man David and drifter Benji head to Poland to process their Jewish heritage through a guided Holocaust tour and, more importantly, visit their late camp-survivor grandmother’s childhood home. As in most movies, it’s the interiority of the oddball journey that matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:48:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Emergency, Kangana Ranaut plays Indira Gandhi who plays Kangana Ranaut. Let me explain. Ranaut performs as the former Prime Minister of India when the politician is flawed, cruel, paranoid, a nepotism hire, power-hungry, guilty, and the mother of Sanjay Gandhi. Her voice becomes high-pitched, uneven and shaky in these parts. But Indira Gandhi seems to perform as Ranaut when the woman is defiant, patriotic, headstrong, resilient, reverential towards the opposition (Janata Party leaders Jayaprakash Narayan and Atal Bihari Vajpayee), and the mother of the nation. Her voice becomes firm, furious and confident in these parts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paatal Lok S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:46:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A beloved political leader from Nagaland is found brutally murdered in Delhi. The timing is dubious. It’s on the eve of a landmark business summit between the ‘mainland’ and the ‘margins’: The central government is primed to invest thousands of crores into the development and tourism sector of Nagaland. Protests break out in Kohima; conflicts erupt between the slain man’s loyalists and the rebel factions against this soul-selling deal. The case is given to ACP Imran Ansari (Ishwak Singh), fresh from topping his IPS batch. The optics are irresistible: A Muslim officer must lead an investigation into the killing of an unprotected guest — an Indian outsider — in the capital. If things go wrong, Ansari is a readymade scapegoat. Meanwhile, jaded protagonist and Ansari’s ex-boss Hathi Ram Chaudhary (Jaideep Ahlawat) continues to bat in the minor league. He flirts with the idea of quitting, but an inconspicuous case of a missing husband puts him on a collision course with the high-profile investigation. Most officers are expected to do their job, but Hathi Ram is destined to do his duty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:03:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azaad is fit, handsome, muscular and agile. His flowy hair is the talk of the town. He plays hard to get. He looks away and sighs if he isn’t interested. He loves his whisky neat — and straight from the bottle. He sits on a bed when he’s tired. He loses his appetite when he’s sad; he eats only if his food is spiked with alcohol. He has expensive taste. He farts in a closed room. He isn’t afraid to defy outdated perceptions of masculinity: his eyes go glassy when he gets a whiff of his late companion’s scent from a turban. He remembers the day they met and necked. He remembers their adolescent-love song together: “Ab jeene ki koi wajah toh hai” (I now have a reason to live). He isn’t ashamed of weeping. He likes dancing. He loves racing, too. Azaad is an expressive action hero; this film is his big-budget launch vehicle. There’s only one problem though: Azaad is a horse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Roshans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-roshans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:38:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-roshans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard of “Prestige TV”: the term for quality long-form film-making, cinematic production values, A-list acting and complex screenwriting. But in the Netflix non-fiction universe, Prestige TV is a far more literal term. It stands for self-produced and self-congratulatory celebrity documentaries with infinite access that explore the sanitised prestige of fame. The symptoms: prestigious movie and music legacies, prestigious anecdotes, prestigious lives, prestigious prestige. You get the gist. Or maybe you didn’t. Think of the line from Christopher Nolan’s The Prestige (2006): “Making something disappear isn’t enough, you have to bring it back”. This hagiographic genre is all about bringing things back. Some call it the magic of movies, others call it a nostalgia grab.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fateh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/fateh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 20:42:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/fateh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can tell when someone—especially an actor—is directing their first action movie. The craft is more impressive than expressive. Sonu Sood’s Fateh, starring himself, has telltale signs. For instance, there’s that ambitious mirror shot in the beginning: The hero looks straight at his reflection but you can’t see the camera; it then floats through the glass like a ghost. There are the over-excited transitions and snazzy editing. At least twice, shots of spilled blood cut to ketchup on a plate; a cop ordering a steamed momo cuts to a villain eating a momo (“my long-time weakness”); a victim opens his mouth to scream and you hear a honking car. There’s an interval slate that reads “Brace yourself, you’ll need this break”. A pointless overseas sequence is inserted only so that a Hans Zimmer-composed track can be flaunted. A random close-up of a henchman’s ear is seen seconds before his severed ear is served on a plate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Badminton</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/badminton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 23:33:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/badminton/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given the times we live in, it’s a source of constant intrigue that Hindi cinema’s politically aware film-makers have to be smart about expressing themselves. They have to be subtler and sneakier with their views, but also stay just as accessible. You see a push-and-pull balance with the more prolific storytellers like Hansal Mehta, Sudhir Mishra and Anubhav Sinha. But cult-status directors like Anurag Kashyap and Dibakar Banerjee have found it visibly harder. At times, their opinions are nearly too pure. You can tell that they have so much to say—there’s a lot of emotion, passion, cynicism and awareness—but they’re running out of commercial road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pickle Factory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-pickle-factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 20:57:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-pickle-factory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Pickle Factory is what happens when The Office (U.S.) and Better Life Foundation (India) reluctantly get married (arranged) and have a pious, Doordarshan-loving child that refuses to grow up. It’s the kind of stagey and adolescent workplace comedy that went out of fashion years ago. You want it to work, of course, for several reasons. The 10-episode show revolves around the quirky employees of a family-run pickle company; imagine the readymade Hindi ‘achaar’ proverbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/doctors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:04:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/doctors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It often takes no more than five minutes to tell that a ten-episode series is going to be … not good. Yet, it’s my job to watch the whole thing. I can’t just abandon it the moment I realise it’s fundamentally flawed. So, I spend a day or two watching the next 395 minutes, hoping against hope that a miracle changes my mind. But, of course, it never comes—the craft is all wrong, the writing is dated, the music is uninspired, and the acting is everywhere. Yet, when a series is so long and stubborn and voluminous, one tends to develop a strange attachment to it. There’s no escape, so I simply make peace with—and normalise—the mediocrity at hand. It’s a reluctant bond, the kind you have with a month-long cough. But it’s a bond nevertheless, and when it ends, a part of your life ends. That’s what Doctors became to me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:33:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching a mass actioner is a bit like watching West Indies play T20 cricket. When it comes off, there’s no better sight in sports. It’s all fireworks and fury, natural showmanship and musical rhythm. It makes no sense, yet the joy is real. But when it doesn’t come off, it can look like one giant Steve Smith mishit: ugly, awkward, strange, abnormal. Baby John is an example. Nothing aligns. The timing is woefully off, the star wattage is awry, the sound mix is all over the place, the action is unimaginative, it’s 164 minutes of dated narrative tropes, and the money shots don’t add up. That’s the thing about the genre: it’s boom or bust. It’s high-risk, high-reward, high-everything filmmaking. West Indies either chases down 250 or gets skittled out for 45 — there is seldom an in-between version.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:09:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While watching Mufasa: The Lion King, all I could think about was this: 4 precious years of Barry Jenkins’ career were spent in front of Disney green screens and sound stages to not even create something madly original? Don’t get me wrong, I’m not against effects-driven or photo-realistically animated movies; visionaries like Peter Jackson and James Cameron have redefined the relationship between technology and storytelling over the years. But Disney? Another Lion King film? My viewing experience was laced with the frustration of realising that yet another Hollywood studio franchise was doing wasteful Hollywood things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jhansi Ka Rajkumar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jhansi-ka-rajkumar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 19:43:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jhansi-ka-rajkumar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even as an Ayushmann Khurrana-coded small-town comedy that’s a decade too late, Jhansi Ka Rajkumar feels dated. The film stars Gulshan Devaiah as Rajkumar, a stay-at-home dad struggling to adjust to a move from Delhi to Jhansi — or, more accurately, struggling to function in a judgmental society. His wife, Devayani (Namita Dubey), is the breadwinner with a government job. You know the drill. Gender role reversal. Ridicule. Stigma. Pressure to conform. Marital conflict. Speech. Resolution. This is basically a middle-class Ki &amp;amp; Ka (2016), just not as gimmicky and self-satisfied. But it’s also not as self-contained as Barun Sobti’s track in Raat Jawaan Hai, a show where the guy’s “progressive househusband” tag silently gnaws away at him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yo Yo Honey Singh: Famous</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yo-yo-honey-singh-famous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 18:49:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yo-yo-honey-singh-famous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yo Yo Honey Singh: Famous follows, fusses over and indulges Indian rapper Honey Singh on his comeback trail in 2023. He declares that he has returned from the dead for his fans. He looks rejuvenated. On cue, two young ragpickers at a traffic signal recognise and laud him for losing weight. The brief is simple: new body, new mind, new music videos after years of substance abuse, mental health issues and rehabilitation. Drugs are never mentioned, but the camera focuses on his physical tics and foot tapping enough to hint at it. This part is interspersed with his up-and-down journey up till this point: bits of his childhood, his early talent, his fame and fandom, and his widely chronicled collapse. The treatment is all too familiar. The lens becomes his mouthpiece. At some point, he stops being a person. He morphs into a neatly segregated storyline, an impenetrable idea that’s at once marketed and sold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Body</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/body/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 17:31:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once adulthood sets in, and once we’ve accumulated enough years, most of us have two types of recurring dreams (and nightmares). One revolves around the terror of remembering that the exam is tomorrow and we haven’t touched the school syllabus. The other is shaped by the horror of finding ourselves naked in routine situations, while being totally helpless about it. Both of these are trauma responses to our fraught relationship with society. Both feature a link between social conditioning and shame, but Abhijit Muzumdar’s Body confronts the steeper task of exploring the second dream. It’s a testing watch, but ultimately quite a rewarding one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despatch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 13:00:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despatch starts off as a journalist story. It’s 2012. Joy Bag (Manoj Bajpayee) is a veteran crime reporter for a Mumbai-based newspaper. Joy is in a joyless marriage with Shweta (Shahana Goswami), and he plans a future with Prerna (Arrchita Agarwaal), a colleague he’s been having an affair with; he is in search of his next big headline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The journalist story slowly morphs into a journalism story. It’s 2012. A leading daily is on the brink of the digital news era. Desperate to keep the print flame burning, its veteran crime reporter chases a dangerous scoop. Despite multiple warnings and personal setbacks, he keeps going. Despatch then exposes and reveals itself at once: Joy Bag emerges as a fictional surrogate for J. Dey, the Mid-Day investigations editor who was murdered in broad daylight in 2011. Kanu Behl’s 150-minute drama almost unfolds as a prequel to Scoop, Hansal Mehta’s Netflix series that dramatises the life of Jigna Vora, the ‘rival’ journalist and prime suspect in the killing of J. Dey. It’s the sort of grueling double bill that captures the dying moments of press freedom in a country entering a post-truth age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sikandar Ka Muqaddar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-ka-muqaddar-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:07:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-ka-muqaddar-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For Tarantino, it’s the foot shot. For Rohit Shetty, it’s the drone shot. And for Neeraj Pandey, it’s the walking-talking shot: unbroken over-the-shoulder and full-frontal shots of self-serious men striding in and out of spaces, between rooms and corridors, between people and objects. Cops walk. Robbers walk. Waiters walk. Dogs walk. Thoughts walk. The air walks. No cinematographer finishes a schedule unfit. Basically, walking equals narrative momentum. Pandey is a master at making it look like something is always happening even when nothing is — but not in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All We Imagine as Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:13:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All We Imagine As Light opens like a non-fiction film about a city of grand fictions. We see a dark Mumbai — the factory of dreams — in which its survivors and victims imagine light. Invisible migrant voices play over a montage of traffic, streets, beaches, stations and hope. A pregnant housemaid jokes about being fed well by her employer. A veteran from Gujarat refuses to call it home because he’s afraid he might have to leave any moment. A dockyard worker recalls the fishy smells from his first night; he speaks like the stink has gone, but it’s his nose that adapted. A woman credits the place for making her forget a breakup. They all sound like stories from the “Spirit of Mumbai” handbook — it’s hard to tell their fate from their faith. The film seamlessly transitions from the generic to the specific by the end of this montage. The camera settles on one such story in motion: two Malayali nurses on the train back to their tiny apartment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom at Midnight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:52:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As children, most of us learn to see 1947 as India’s finest moment. The event is simple: India gained freedom from the greedy British Raj and that’s that. As teenagers, we start to sense that perhaps it wasn’t all smooth and happy. With independence came the pressure to move out and grow up. But it doesn’t matter much because, either way, colonialism ended. As we get older, however, a full and bittersweet picture emerges: a nation is free, only to be violently divided into two on the basis of religion. It was never as simple as the British leaving or a newly born country celebrating its revolutionaries. This fuller picture has been molded — and revised — into shapeless stories by a future reeling from its scars. History is what happened, but these days, history is what we choose to believe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanguva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanguva-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:17:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanguva-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime last month, a Timothée Chalamet look-alike contest in New York took the internet by storm. The prize was a modest 50 dollars. Some participants were more convincing than others, but the reason this event went viral is because the real Chalamet made a surprise visit in the end to greet the winners. Ironically, he looked nothing like the men trying to ape him. The point of this anecdote — wait for it — is that the entire Indian fantasy-period-action-epic bubble these days is an expensive look-alike contest. During the interval of Kanguva, I was momentarily disoriented: was the second half of Devara: Part 1 or Kalki 2898 AD going to start playing? Would anyone even notice? These movies resemble each other in strange and amateur ways, but none of them resemble the original star, S.S. Rajamouli’s Baahubali. In fact, like Chalamet himself, Rajamouli showed up in a cameo in one of these films — and that scene alone became more popular than the mega-budget production surrounding it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vijay 69</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vijay-69-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:26:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vijay-69-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are some movies you just want to like before you watch them. Personal biases are an integral part of the cinema experience. For instance, I used to have a soft spot for stories that romanticised a version of myself: slice-of-life introvert tales or dysfunctional family dramas. My focus has now moved to aspirational old-people stories; perhaps it has something to do with my parents aging with all sorts of ailments. The prospect of watching Vijay 69, then, was an inviting one. Not only is it director Akshay Roy’s first film since the criminally underappreciated Meri Pyaari Bindu (2017), it stars Anupam Kher as Vijay Mathew, a 69-year-old widower who attempts to become India’s oldest triathlete. I went into the film expecting to revise my reality — of having a 71-year-old father allergic to physical fitness — for a few hours. A bit of sports thrown in can’t hurt matters. What could possibly go wrong? And what could possibly go wrong when you have to ask what could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel: Honey Bunny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 13:41:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citadel: Honey Bunny is a catchy title. In fact, you can almost hear it. “Honey Bunny” instantly evokes the viral Idea Cellular ad jingle from 2012: you’re my pumpkin pumpkin/hello honey bunny. But there’s more to the earworm than a Pulp Fiction tribute or a term of endearment. The commercial itself showed a traveler infecting different parts of the country with a tune; the cutesy lyrics, too, felt like the collective sound of couples staying connected across regions. It’s not a stretch to suggest that Citadel: Honey Bunny — whose pan-world premise features a pan-Indian adventure of a couple named Honey (Samantha Ruth Prabhu) and Bunny (Varun Dhawan) — is a long-form descendent of the jingle. It’s totally on brand for director duo Raj &amp;amp; DK, who thrive on affectionate pop-cultural nods, cinephilia and retro references.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:24:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some movies are so entertaining that they make you miss the good old days. But others are so vapid that they make you miss good days. Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 is “others”. You see Vidya Balan, and fondly reminisce about Priyadarshan’s Bhool Bhulaiyaa (2007) and Pritam’s hit soundtrack. You see Vidya Balan and Madhuri Dixit playing enigmatic women, and think of how well they were cast in Abhishek Chaubey’s Ishqiya (2010) and Dedh Ishqiya (2014). You see a tragic female ghost haunt a mansion and morph into a human social message in a setting full of foolish men, and it’s hard not to respect how fundamentally sound the Stree movies are. You see crows descend from the dark skies for dramatic effect and think of The Crows Have Eyes III: The Crowening, the Bosnian B-movie starring Moira Rose in Schitt’s Creek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mithya: The Darker Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-dark-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:46:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-dark-chapter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my pet peeves features Hindi cinema’s toxic relationship with technology. You know how, in the middle of a public event, every single cellphone in the hall simultaneously beeps with a headline alert because the famous person it’s about is also present? Everyone turns to dramatically look at this unfortunate person; whispers and gossipy glances hijack the scene. This is how news spreads in such stories. It can be at a press conference, a panel discussion, even at a party. In Mithya: The Darker Chapter, it’s at a business auction that comes to a standstill. My questions are simple. How is it that nobody’s phone is on vibrate mode? Why are the shock and awe so coordinated? Why is it that no other message or app on the phone has a pop-up sound? The closest I’ve experienced as a real-world viewer is when, during a press screening of Super 30 (2019), most journalists in the hall audibly gasped when Dhoni got run out in that World Cup semifinal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mithya: The Darker Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-darker-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:46:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-darker-chapter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my pet peeves features Hindi cinema’s toxic relationship with technology. You know how, in the middle of a public event, every single cellphone in the hall simultaneously beeps with a headline alert because the famous person it’s about is also present? Everyone turns to dramatically look at this unfortunate person; whispers and gossipy glances hijack the scene. This is how news spreads in such stories. It can be at a press conference, a panel discussion, even at a party. In Mithya: The Darker Chapter, it’s at a business auction that comes to a standstill. My questions are simple. How is it that nobody’s phone is on vibrate mode? Why are the shock and awe so coordinated? Why is it that no other message or app on the phone has a pop-up sound? The closest I’ve experienced as a real-world viewer is when, during a press screening of Super 30 (2019), most journalists in the hall audibly gasped when Dhoni got run out in that World Cup semifinal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Remarkable Life of Ibelin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-remarkable-life-of-ibelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 10:59:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-remarkable-life-of-ibelin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Ree’s The Remarkable Life of Ibelin starts off as a documentary about death. We see the tombstone of Mats Steen, a Norwegian boy whose body and soul were at war. A mix of VHS footage and family interviews then reveals that Mats had duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD), a degenerative disease that reduced his 25 years to a hellish survival story. His mind yearned for the momentum his muscles never had. Subsequent clips show his body shrinking on landmarks and vacations, the end inching closer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Miranda Brothers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-miranda-brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 23:55:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-miranda-brothers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sanjay Gupta’s The Miranda Brothers revolves around two hunky brothers named Julio (Harshvardhan Rane) and Regalo Miranda (Meezaan Jafri), rising football stars in a Josh-coded Goa where orphaned babies are picked up from garbage dumps outside churches; arrogant cricketers cackle and say: “Cricket has two C’s: Cash and Chicks”; football scouts exclaim: “if we select both brothers, it’s like an earthquake and typhoon becoming one!”; bronze-bodied dance tracks called “Be My Mehbooba” pop up on a beach; and mourners at a funeral walk together in slow-motion as if they’re teleported to Sanjay Gupta’s Kaante (2002) instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:32:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WILD ROBOT is about an all-purpose robot that turns sentient in the wilderness. After washing up on a forest island, Rozzum “Rozz” 7134 learns to feel and discern once it mothers an orphaned goose and befriends a red fox. I’d say it becomes human, but in the context of where we are today, “it grows a heart” is more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The premise is not earth-shatteringly original; cautionary and cute robot tales are the cornerstone of animated cinema and science fiction. A machine coming alive through motherhood is a familiar allegory. An unlikely ‘interspecies’ family is the core of cross-cultural comedy. Ecological fairy tales and deforestation metaphors featuring animals joining paws, claws and wings to defeat manmade evils — we’ve seen it all before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 18:32:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most directors make you feel like you’re watching their film — their technical prowess, their intent, their voice, their commercial and arthouse ambitions. But directors like Vasan Bala make you feel like you’re watching their dreams come true. His movies aren’t shown, they’re shared. His craft isn’t flaunted, it’s realised. In Jigra, there are no shots, only fulfilled aspirations. There are no scenes and set pieces, only childhood memories. There is no action, only the physicality of emotion. There is no story, only the narrativisation of storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raat Jawaan Hai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raat-jawaan-hai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:55:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raat-jawaan-hai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raat Jawaan Hai unfolds as an uncharacteristically warm and vibrant answer to a question popular Hindi cinema is too streamlined to ask: what happens after the end credits of the quintessential buddy comedy have rolled? Call it “Little Things for young parents” or “Dil Chahta Hai for reluctant adults”, but the fact that Raat Jawaan Hai fuses two seemingly exclusive genres of life — the friendship triangle and the marital drama — is, in itself, a minor triumph.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manvat Murders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:54:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a true-crime drama in the Indian streaming landscape is like being an aspiring batsman in India’s cramped bylanes and crowded fields. Everybody is one — and everybody is advised to be one. Consequently, it’s harder to stand out. The default level has to be high: an engrossing story, a solid cast, a sense of place and time, technical competence. Most shows opt for an atmospheric setting to conceal a convoluted plot; the logic is that a visually striking tone will compensate for pacing and structural issues. In other words, the style can distract from a lack of substance. But Manvat Murders, helmed by Aatmapamphlet (2023) director Ashish Avinash Bende, is a Marathi-language series that does the reverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:31:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Aneesh Chaganty’s Searching put the life in screenlife. It marked the natural progression of ‘screenlife storytelling’ — a visual format where events happen entirely on computer screens, smartphones and cameras — into the real world. Until then, the horrors of technology had been literalised by the found-footage and supernatural genres. But Searching featured a father who looks for his missing daughter by following her digital footprints. His internet sleuthing reveals how little he really knew her; the technology he uses to find her is what had isolated her to begin with. Vikramaditya Motwane’s CTRL goes a step further; it expands the plausibility of the genre by unfolding in an age that puts the screen in screenlife. CTRL marks its progression into the reality of a virtual world — one where being watched is simply a natural consequence of feeling seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
