<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Azaad on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/azaad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azaad on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 09:00:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/azaad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 09:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Betaab, Barsaat, Mirziya&amp;hellip; Bollywood somehow loves to launch its kids on horses. Abhishek Kapoor’s Azaad is the latest addition to the list where Ajay Devgn’s nephew Aaman Devgan, and Raveena Tandon’s daughter Rasha Thadani, get a horse ride because of their pedigree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:17:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;बॉलीवुड में इंसान और जानवरों के प्यार, दोस्ती और वफादारी पर &amp;lsquo;हाथी मेरे साथी&amp;rsquo; और &amp;lsquo;तेरी मेहरबानियां&amp;rsquo; जैसी यादगार फिल्में बनी हैं। हालांकि, वक्त के साथ इन बेजुबानों के साथ इंसानी रिश्तों की कहानियां कम होती गईं, पर अब डायरेक्टर अभिषेक कपूर इस कड़ी को आगे बढ़ाते हुए फिल्म &amp;lsquo;आजाद&amp;rsquo; लेकर आए हैं, जिसका केंद्र एक घोड़ा है। अपनी फिल्मों से फरहान अख्तर, सुशांत सिंह राजपूत और सारा अली खान को बॉलीवुड में लॉन्च करने वाले अभिषेक कपूर इस फिल्म से भी दो नए चेहरों, अजय देवगन के भांजे अमन देवगन और रवीना टंडन की बेटी राशा थडानी को पर्दे पर उतार रहे हैं। फिल्म में इन दोनों नए एक्टर्स, खासकर अमन ने आत्मविश्वास भरी अदाकारी से खुद को लंबी रेस का घोड़ा साबित करने की बढ़िया कोशिश की है।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:03:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Azaad is fit, handsome, muscular and agile. His flowy hair is the talk of the town. He plays hard to get. He looks away and sighs if he isn’t interested. He loves his whisky neat — and straight from the bottle. He sits on a bed when he’s tired. He loses his appetite when he’s sad; he eats only if his food is spiked with alcohol. He has expensive taste. He farts in a closed room. He isn’t afraid to defy outdated perceptions of masculinity: his eyes go glassy when he gets a whiff of his late companion’s scent from a turban. He remembers the day they met and necked. He remembers their adolescent-love song together: “Ab jeene ki koi wajah toh hai” (I now have a reason to live). He isn’t ashamed of weeping. He likes dancing. He loves racing, too. Azaad is an expressive action hero; this film is his big-budget launch vehicle. There’s only one problem though: Azaad is a horse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:37:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K1yzR09FhYk?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:35:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of nearly two-and-a-half hours, you want to ask director Abhishek Kapoor and his writing team that includes Ritesh Shah and Suresh Nair, just one question. What was the story you ventured to tell? Was it about a magnificent, Chetak-like horse that could give its life to his master? If yes, then the most-loved animal film remains Rajesh Khanna and Chinnappa Devar’s Haathi Mere Saathi (1971) where entire families had a jumbo-size crush on Ramu, the hero’s pet elephant. But Abhishek and company treat Azaad like a backdrop, never letting the viewer warm up to the animal who is shown throwing off, neighing noisily and kicking the hero, most of the time. Oh, yes, he also likes liquor and breaks wind loudly (humour alert).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:31:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/eLPze5Jh9Es?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:36:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The deep bonds between a horse and their human have been at the centre of many wonderful films. Azaad, which has two men, senior and junior, vying for the affections of a beautiful beast, should have been double the fun. But this one, which launches Ajay Devgn’s nephew Aaman and Raveena Tandon’s daughter Rasha, turns out to be so dated that it appears to have been made in a time lag. First off, the setting has been lifted from ‘Lagaan’– cruel zamindars helping pompous Englishmen lord over cowed villagers — with the addition of a few floggings, and loud proclamations of banishing the villagers to ‘Africa’ as bonded labour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:16:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;कहानी है मध्य भारत के बीहड़ इलाके की, समय है 1920 का। लोकल ज़मींदार अंग्रेज़ों का पिट्ठू है और अंग्रेज़ अफसर के कहने पर गांव वालों को मज़दूरी के लिए जबरन दक्षिण अफ्रीका भेजता है। वह अपनी बेटी को अंग्रेज़ी रंग-ढंग सिखा रहा है ताकि अंग्रेज़ अफसर के कमअक्ल बेटे से उसे ब्याह सके। उधर उसका बेटा गांव के एक नौजवान विक्रम ठाकुर की प्रेमिका को जबरन ब्याह लाया है और विक्रम बन चुका है डकैत। (ओह सॉरी, बीहड़ में बागी होते हैं, डकैत मिलते हैं पारलामेंट में…!) ज़मींदार के यहां घोड़ों की देखभाल करने वाले का बेटा गोविंद घोड़ों का दीवाना है लेकिन घोड़े उसकी औकात से बाहर हैं और ज़मींदार की बेटी भी। उसे अपनी औकात बदलनी है और जालिमों को भी उनकी औकात दिखानी है। कैसे होगा ये सब? इतनी लंबी कथा सुनाने का मकसद आपको यह बताना है कि हमारी फिल्में हवा में नहीं बनतीं बल्कि उनके लिए बाकायदा एक कहानी सोची जाती है, उसे फैलाया जाता है, समेटा भी जाता है। यह बात अलग है कि इस सोचने-फैलाने-समेटने के चक्कर में कई बार कहानी का गुड़गांव हो जाए तो इसमें लेखकों का क्या कसूर…! भई, साइकिल के टायर जितनी कहानी में ट्रैक्टर के टायर जितनी हवा भरेंगे तो पटाखा तो फूटेगा ही।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
