<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tatsam Mukherjee on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/tatsam-mukherjee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tatsam Mukherjee on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:48:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/tatsam-mukherjee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Diplomat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:48:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a miracle, John Abraham is still acting in films 22 years after his debut in Jism (2003). This isn’t a snarky comment on his limited chops as an actor, as much as his risk appetite in an industry that is too busy holding on to fleeting good times and too happy to repeat its successes. Few actors have visibly lived the ‘one for them, one for me’ maxim (working with as varied a list like Anurag Kashyap, Deepa Mehta, Shoojit Sircar to Rohit Dhawan, Anees Bazmee and Milap Zaveri) with as much gusto as the 53-year-old star. Abraham has seen a few successes, but he’s endured gargantuan failures. In Abraham, there is an insecure star constantly probing the market for his commercial viability (he’s produced most recent films through his production house, JA Entertainment), but there’s also a curious actor constantly trying to prove his mettle. This dichotomy in Abraham also finds itself in his latest film, The Diplomat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Unknown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-complete-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 08:55:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-complete-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time we meet Bob Dylan (Timothee Chalamet) in A Complete Unknown, he’s uncomplainingly laying in the back of a wagon amongst a pile of luggage. He’s just hitched a ride to New York City to see his hero, folk musician Woody Guthrie (Scoot McNairy), who has been hospitalised after being diagnosed with Huntington’s disease. Dylan overhears an impassioned discussion trying to determine if Guthrie is a folk or a country musician. “There’s no need to box him,” one of them says. It’s 1961 and a particularly tense period in America, as the House of Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) is summoning people for their alleged communist ties. The celebrities of Hollywood are understandably first in line, just like the musicians of the time like Pete Seeger (Edward Norton), who was critical of the American government. Social justice is becoming a street-side topic among many, as America is sinking deeper into the Vietnam War, the Civil Rights movement is picking up steam. Two years later, a president will be assassinated during a motorcade, fuelling the paranoia of the public and future governments alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 08:59:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one of my most favourite scenes from Faiza Ahmad Khan’s Supermen of Malegaon (2008), the protagonist Nasir is having a verbal duel with brother Nadeem, who wants to follow his foot-steps and make a career out of making amateur films in Malegaon. After making Malegaon Ke Sholay – a parody of the iconic 1975 film – Nasir became a local celebrity. Nadeem is showing his parody of Tere Naam (2003) to the camera, when Nasir rebukes him for wanting to pursue it as a career. It’s a fascinating divide Khan captures in her documentary, where one brother is seduced by the magic of cinema, while the other seems blinded by its glamour and fame. For someone so close to the dream machine, it’s incredible how Nasir is able to suss out the lies in the oft-romanticised maxims: ‘Follow your passion,’ or ‘Conquer your dreams’. He tells Khan how filmmaking has to be a hobby. There are no returns here, and one can’t run a household on it. “Main khud phaste jaara ismein (I, myself, am getting trapped in this).”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baksho Bondi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baksho-bondi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baksho-bondi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In another life, Maya (Tillotama Shome) would have lived a different, more comfortable life. A college graduate in Barrackpore, she was set for an ordinary middle-class life like the many girls around her. However, all her parents’ dreams crash and burn when Maya tells them about Sundar (Chandan Bisht) – a pahadi man stationed in the nearby army cantonment. By the time Tanushree Das and Saumyananda Sahi’s Baksho Bondi (English title: Shadowbox) begins – it’s been a few years since Sundar has been dishonourably discharged from the army because of what appears to be a serious case of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). The rebellion of young love has made way for the caution and weariness of middle age. Both presumably in their late 30s by now, the onus of providing for Sundar now falls on Maya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 19:02:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arati Kadav’s Mrs. – an official remake of Jeo Baby’s The Great Indian Kitchen (2021) – is a technically sound film. It opens with a montage of delicacies being cooked in an average Indian kitchen. Editor Prerna Saigal cuts the meticulous preparation of each dish with a carefully choreographed piece, drawing our attention to the ‘dance’ most women have to endure inside a household, to keep it on its axis. Scored by Sagar Desai featuring sounds from everyday life (like squeaky, rusted gate offering rhythm to the track), the montage works well. But it can’t quite conjure the rhythm of Baby’s original film, which editor Francis Louis establishes in the never-ending loop of domestic labour thrust upon women. Especially inside a kitchen. Kadav, who broke out with imaginative Sci-Fi films (The Astronaut and His Parrot) using wide-eyed imagination to compensate for oppressive budgets, also constructs her latest venture with a similar amount of distance. The food photography is immaculate, the kitchen and the home look like they were built on a soundstage. Unlike Baby’s film, where both the kitchen as well as the home felt lived-in. When Richa (Sanya Malhotra) has to immerse her hand into a clogged sink to weed out the sediments at its bottom, it doesn’t feel as viscerally icky as Nimisha Vijayan’s character having to hand-pick the chewed-out bones thrown by her father-in-law and the husband, in the original film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabar Bonda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sabar-bonda-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 11:32:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sabar-bonda-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anand (Bhushaan Manoj) has just lost his father, but according to his relatives, it’s not the most pressing absence in his life. Anand is a 30-year-old unmarried man, something which is utterly incomprehensible to the folks in his village in Maharashtra. So even as he gets ready to perform the last rites of his dead father, his relatives don’t forget to remind him about the ‘stigma’ of his marital status. An aunt even wonders out loud, if an unmarried man is fit to light the pyre of his own father. Anand and his mother have to wade through a sea of inquisitions about why he hasn’t settled down – only to come up with stories like – “A girl he was in love with, married someone else. So Anand is heartbroken, and doesn’t wish to get married now.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omaha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/omaha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 08:37:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/omaha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Where are we going?” six-year-old Charlie (Wyatt Solis) asks his father (John Magaro). Charlie, his elder sister Ella (Molly Belle Wright) are seated inside a car with their father within the first five minutes of the film. The kids have no idea where they’re headed. Cole Webley’s directorial debut is the kind of film where exposition comes at a premium. Information trickles down through stray scenes – the sheriff putting an eviction notice on their house right around the time they’re leaving tells us about the family’s dire financial situation. Ella tells Charlie she was taught to fly a kite by their mother before “she got sick” – explaining who the father talks to, grieving his partner, almost praying to her for forgiveness. When they’re at a store, and the father wishes to spoil his kids with a kite and a meal of their choice, the clerk informs him he has only $20 left on his food stamps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:23:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time we meet Benji (Kieran Culkin), he’s aimlessly floating around in an airport. Seated in the waiting area with his ear pods plugged in, one can immediately spot the melancholy in his eyes. He appears to be curious about people – observing them closely. There’s a good chance that if someone around him was in need, Benji would be one of the first persons to help. But he’s also a wildcard, who wouldn’t respond to his cousin David’s (Jesse Eisenberg) voicemails, and that too on the day they’re supposed to travel to Poland together. Has he woken up? Has he left? Is he on time? Where is he? Does he remember they have a flight? No response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paatal Lok S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:16:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the second season of Paatal Lok (Amazon Prime Video), it’s safe to say that nobody else in India has mastered the police procedural like Sudip Sharma. Known for writing acclaimed films like Udta Punjab (2016) and Sonchiriya (2019) – Sharma became a household name after the first season of the show in 2020, much like his lead actor – Jaideep Ahlawat. Since then, Sharma has written Kohhra (2023), using the mould of a police investigation to uncover the oppressive culture of patriarchy typical to Punjab. In the second season of Paatal Lok, Sharma is still grappling with the larger rot in society using a trail of missing persons and murder probes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Warrant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 21:33:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all intents and purposes, Sunil Kumar Gupta (Zahan Kapoor) is not a good fit for Tihar jail. He has a slim build and his oversized uniform hangs loosely on him. He’s grown a moustache to mask his lack of depth in an institution fuelled by testosterone; Gupta is too stuck in his ‘decent’ ways to even inadvertently cuss. He refers to his mother as ‘Mumma’ – a seemingly ordinary-but-revealing detail about his dynamic with her and how he’s been raised. He’s called ‘Baby’ by family members and neighbours – a detail almost trying too hard to sell his obvious displacement in Tihar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squid Game S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/squid-game-s02-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 20:07:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/squid-game-s02-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like it happens with the follow-up for any successful show, I entered the Squid Game 2 with a fair bit of trepidation. What worked in the first season was the shock value of the setting that posits the innocence of childhood games, sophisticated Western classical music with a kind of savagery few would be able to stomach. Where unsuspecting debt-ridden civilians are lured onto an island to play a series of games – for which they stand to win an obscene amount of money, or pay for it with their life. A cruel, but clinical simulation of our lives in a hyper-capitalist society, the appeal of Squid Game lay in how it studied human nature – especially the ones with limited means, who are driven to take desperate measures. How far would you go to survive/get paid? As the first season showed: to any length.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 21:17:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing screams ‘crisis’ in Hindi cinema right now more than Salman Khan showing up in his second ‘star cameo’ of the year – hedging his bets between two cinematic universes; hoping at least one of them works. Something works. This is not a spoiler, given how the film’s PR and fan accounts are enthusiastically ‘leaking’ his entry scene on social media. Khan’s films proudly flaunted their ‘critic-proof’ status for a long time, but have looked increasingly silly in the last five years. Apart from YRF’s spy universe, Khan’s Chulbul Pandey has announced himself in the Rohit Shetty cop universe, and now alongside Varun Dhawan in the Baby John universe – where he’s called (what else, but) Agent Bhai Jaan. It looks like even Bollywood’s loosest canon is looking to diversify his portfolio, fervently praying to make windfall gains from one franchise. The devil-may-care swagger has been replaced with the caution of a star unsure of his place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 22:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help but be left with the feeling that there’s an enjoyable disaster film somewhere within Rahul Dholakia’s Agni, which surely owes a debt to The Burning Train (1980). There is more than one echo of the Ravi Chopra-directorial, where the spectacle is foregrounded by professional rivalry – Danny Denzongpa and Vinod Khanna’s in the 1980 film; emulated by Pratik Gandhi and Divyenndu’s characters in Dholakia’s directorial. The innate Bollywood melodrama after an unexpected death, the high-voltage social commentary and righteous anger fuel both spectacles. Both Chopra and Dholakia’s film balance a strong ensemble, offering everyone their moment, and yet Dholakia’s film fails to stick its landing. It might have to do with what Hindi films have become in 2024 – too self-conscious, cautious, and reverential towards any uniform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All We Imagine as Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:34:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Payal Kapadia’s All We Imagine As Light (AWIAL) establishes its Mumbai DNA early on. A visibly-tired Anu (Divya Prabha), an upstart nurse in a city hospital, is jotting down details of a patient. Age? “24… oh no sorry, it’s 25,” a young woman says, holding on to her child. “Pfft!” reacts Anu, showcasing her mild annoyance for having to strike out what she’d written earlier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Want to Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:31:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Will you dance at my wedding?”, a young Reya (Pearle Dey) asks her visibly-ill father, Arjun (Abhishek Bachchan), sitting in their backyard. Arjun used to be a high-flying, pragmatic, proud ad executive in Los Angeles, till one day he was diagnosed with laryngeal cancer. It’s a loaded question – especially for a still-squeaky voice. The initial prognosis gave Arjun 100 days to live. But he’s somehow lived his way through a few months, maybe even a year. While he awaits future surgeries, many things hang in the balance for Arjun, preventing him from giving Reya an answer. The scene ends with the father-daughter’s heavy silence, staring into a distance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gladiator II</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/gladiator-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:36:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/gladiator-ii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when you take one of the most irreverent filmmakers of our times, and force him to be sombre, sincere and melodramatic? The result is a film like Gladiator II. It’s not to say that the sequel doesn’t have the campy goodness of the original, especially in the turns by Denzel Washington playing Macrinus (a gladiator-turned-influential figure in Rome), Joseph Quinn and Fred Hechinger playing Emperor twins Geta and Caracalla (a more sadistic version of Romulus and Remus), but there’s something amiss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel: Honey Bunny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 12:40:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The choices in Citadel: Honey Bunny sing less frequently compared to other undertakings of the Raj &amp;amp; DK filmmaker duo. An offshoot of Amazon Prime’s gazillion-dollar spy franchise pitted against the silliness of James Bond, Jason Bourne, Ethan Hunt, etc., Raj &amp;amp; DK’s latest carries the baggage of an over-embellished universe tensely fitted into a studio-approved runtime. Like its American counterpart helmed by the Russo brothers, even the Indian version spans six episodes with a duration of 40-50 minutes each.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anora</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/anora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:39:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/anora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of the splendour in Sean Baker’s Anora lies in its treatment – where we might be shown one thing, but deliberately made to feel something else. For example, the film opens with a discomfiting panning shot featuring barely-clothed exotic dancers performing with neon lights around them. However, Baker scores this scene with a loud, winsome techno song taking what is a distressing visual of young women forced to work a job that fetishises them, and drains the self-pity out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:05:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on within twelfth-grader Mira (Preeti Panigrahi). Chosen as the first female head prefect at her seemingly orthodox hill-station boarding school, she’s battling most of the pressures and anxieties of being a teenager, while simmering in the shadow of her vivacious mother Anila (Kani Kusruthi). Mira needs to keep her scores up, balance the shifted power dynamic with friends and bullies because of her duties as a head prefect, and rein in her excessively eager hormones for the mysterious new boy – Srinivas (Kesav Binoy Kiron) – in class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:10:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The clock’s ticking for Satya (Alia Bhatt) in Vasan Bala’s Jigra. Her brother Ankur (Vedang Raina) is on death row in an island nation called Hanshi Dao (a fictitious version of Singapore), and she’s just gotten news that the date of his execution has been expedited for an attempted jailbreak. What was supposed to happen in a few weeks, will now happen in a few days. We see her face computing all possible ploys as fast as she can, and then deciding on a plan of action. It’s not going to be pretty, an accomplice warns, but she’s already made up her mind. The accomplice backs out, telling Satya that she’ll be on her own. “I never said I was a hero. I’ll understand if you don’t wish to join me,” she says, “but don’t get in my way.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s one significant challenge to making ‘screen-life films’ (films that unfold almost entirely on digital screens). Once you commit to its visual grammar, you’re tied to them till there’s a good reason to break out of it. No matter what, all your exposition needs to happen on the small screen, key plot points need to be hashed out during video calls, and the filmmakers need to keep imagining newer screens – ranging from iPad, mobile phones, CCTVs, GoPros, webcams, paparazzi lenses, TV screens etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sthal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sthal-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 07:45:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sthal-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early on in Jayant Digambar Somalkar’s Sthal – four men can be seen discussing a woman’s complexion. “She seems fair, doesn’t she?” one of them asks, only to be shut down by the other: “It is all make-up. Didn’t you notice her elbows? They gave it away.” The woman, actually a young girl named Savita (Nandini Chikte), barely out of her teens, in her final year of college pursuing B.A (Sociology), is being looked at as a prospective bride. Those men could be talking about livestock. Such is the ‘marketplace’ for arranged marriages – especially in India, where such casual indignities are fair game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
