<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Srinivasa Ramanujam on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/srinivasa-ramanujam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Srinivasa Ramanujam on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 14:27:47 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/srinivasa-ramanujam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raghu Thatha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raghu-thatha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 14:27:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raghu-thatha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The opening stretch of Raghu Thathatakes us back to the ‘60s. Even as the opening credits roll, we are shown newspaper clippings of important developments in that period. Anti-Hindi slogans and protests are rampant in Tamil Nadu, a state that is furiously vocal against the imposition of Hindi. Indira Gandhi has taken over as the first woman Prime Minister of the country, something that should ideally given women across the country a lot more confidence and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minmini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/minmini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:30:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/minmini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early in Minmini, inside a school during a chilly evening at Ooty, a candle goes off. A student offers to light it up with his candle. “When one candle lights up another, there’s no loss,” someone remarks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This line, in essence, is symbolic of this 143-minute coming of age drama, one that opens with sequences in a school in Ooty. The most popular student here in Pari (Gaurav Kaalai), a football star who has won so many cups that the school shelves aren’t able to accommodate them. Enter Sabari, a new student who has very different interests; he plays chess, isn’t as outgoing as Pari and is more interested in colouring the sketching.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Test S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-test-s03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:35:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-test-s03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around halfway of the second episode of the latest season of The Test, drama erupts. English batter Jonny Bairstow ducks a bouncer, the ball goes to the keeper and the batter walks out of the crease. Pretty much a normal thing that happens during a Test match, you’d think. But there’s tense music in the background, almost like you know something is going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And then it does. Bairstow walks out of the crease thinking the over was done, and wicketkeeper Carey has thrown at the stumps and is claiming a dismissal. “Sort of within one ball yeah, it happened,” Alex Carey recalls in the docuseries. The crowd at Lord’s Cricket Ground would go on to chant, “Same old Aussies, always cheating,” even as a disappointed Bairstow exits. It’s the equivalent of an action-packed interval block in the movies, the kind that leaves you on a high as you make your way through to the bathroom, probably grinning all the way at how good it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
