<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rohan Naahar on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/rohan-naahar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rohan Naahar on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:41:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/rohan-naahar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Residence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-residence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:41:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-residence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embracing the immaturity of a sitcom and the put-on sophistication of prestige TV, Netflix’s The Residence nestles into a comfy stylistic nook that makes more than eight hours of (surprisingly dense) storytelling go by in a flash. The murder mystery show is produced by the prolific Shonda Rhimes but spearheaded by writer Paul William Davies, who injects it with such an infectious sense of fun that you can’t help but play along. At least until the feature-length finale, which strains to deliver the sort of satisfying climax that you’d expect from a show that name-checks The Murder of the Orient Express and Knives Out with such affection. The genre’s ongoing resurgence didn’t, as many have decided, begin with Rian Johnson’s hit. The movie did admittedly well, leaving Netflix with no option but to hurl a reported $100 million at Daniel Craig to lure him back as the smooth-talking detective Benoit Blanc. But a couple of years before Knives Out, however, director Kenneth Branagh reintroduced Agatha Christie’s enduring detective Hercule Poirot to audiences with his largely reverential The Murder of the Orient Express. Believe it or not, the movie was a bigger hit than Knives Out. Branagh made the correct decision to not tinker with the book’s now-legendary climax, having understood that without it, it’s no different from the scores of other murder mysteries that Christie would churn out on a monthly basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:11:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After breaking out with the horror-thriller Fresh a few years ago — this was the movie in which Daisy Edgar-Jones played a young woman on a blind date with a man who turns out to be a cannibal — director Mimi Cave stays firmly in her comfort zone with her sophomore project, this week’s Holland. The cast is bigger, as is the budget and the scale. Fresh was mostly restricted to one large house, where the predatory male protagonist would lure his female prey and then, literally feast on them. An entire suburban town serves as Cave’s playground this time around; and at least one of its citizens is a killer of women. Nicole Kidman plays Nancy, a seemingly mild-mannered woman who works at the local school and dotes on her husband, Fred, played by Matthew Macfadyen. The one-time heartthrob — he played Mr Darcy in 2005’s Pride &amp;amp; Prejudice adaptation — seems to have been typecast as weaselly villains following his memorable performance as Tom Wambsgans in HBO’s Succession. Fred works as an optometrist; he’s the sort of guy that everybody seems to be friendly with, but crucially, not friends with. Nancy becomes suspicious when he starts going on weekly work trips, often using the flimsiest excuses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sing Sing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sing-sing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:29:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sing-sing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the single greatest scene in any movie released last year was the one where Colman Domingo’s character — a convict named Divine G — pleads his case during a clemency hearing in the startling prison drama Sing Sing. He tells the examining committee about the theatre programme that he has spearheaded at the facility, and how uplifting the experience has been not just for him, but each and every prisoner who has participated in it. The scene purposefully recalls the many similar moments in The Shawshank Redemption, in which a hopeful Red, played by Morgan Freeman, desperately begs for mercy. It isn’t a flashy scene, but one that relies almost entirely on Domingo’s (mostly reactionary) performance — easily the best that he has delivered in his career. The same is true of the film itself. Directed by Greg Kwedar, Sing Sing debuted on Max after a negligible theatrical run abroad. Based on the real-life Rehabilitation Through the Arts programme that is conducted at the Sing Sing Correctional Facility in New York, the movie features a handful of ex-convicts playing semi-fictionalised versions of themselves. This gives it a layer of authenticity that would’ve been difficult to achieve with professional actors. There’s a rawness to the drama that’s mostly missing from mainstream American cinema these days, although Sing Sing — the movie premiered at Sundance in 2023 — doesn’t exactly qualify as mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Studio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:27:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-studio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Studio has two things going against it. Films and shows about the entertainment business often struggle to crawl out of their niche corners, unless, of course, they’re packaged like Argo. Second — and this might be a bigger problem — The Studio is on Apple. Nobody watches stuff on Apple. At most, they watch Ted Lasso and Severance and swiftly cancel their subscriptions. The best that The Studio can hope for is to organically find an audience like those flagship shows did, because it certainly deserves to be mentioned in the same breath as them. Clever, crafty, and caustic when it needs to be, it’s the best new comedy series of 2025 so far. The Studio features Seth Rogen in the lead role of Matt Remick, an executive who lives and breathes cinema, and harbours a long-held dream of becoming a studio head. In the first episode, he’s handed the proverbial keys to the castle on a conditional basis by the head honcho of Continental Studios, played by Bryan Cranston in a performance so boozy that it might require a breathalyser test. Tasked with fast-tracking a movie based on the beverage brand Kool-Aid — you read that right — and turning it into a billion-dollar hit akin to Barbie, Matt finds himself torn between his artistic aspirations and the primal impulses of his lizard brain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/adolescence-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 09:30:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/adolescence-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Netflix should be flexing its UK arm more often. It seems to be doing all the heavy-lifting, especially when it comes to long-form programming. After last year’s One Day and The Gentlemen, Netflix UK has already delivered two stellar new shows this year; incidentally, the same writer is involved with both. Just a few weeks ago, the prolific Jack Thorne spearheaded Toxic Town, a crowd-pleasing drama about social injustice, told from the perspective of the women that were most affected by it. Thorne’s latest is the even better Adolescence, a psychological thriller that he co-created with actor Stephen Graham. It’s only March, but Adolescence, the fascinating examination of masculinity and urban alienation that it reveals itself to be, is already a contender for the best show of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picture This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/picture-this-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:54:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/picture-this-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;College kids of a certain age would be familiar with the practice of filtering assignments through a very rudimentary anti-plagiarism software, mainly to avoid being caught cheating by professors. So worthless were the results of this scam that a kid might even be shamed into putting in the actual effort and writing their assignment themselves. Not only were they submitting something unoriginal, it was also impossible to read. Essentially the same route is now being taken by filmmakers. This week’s new romantic comedy, Picture This, isn’t merely a remake; it’s a remake that is happy to be released in the same week as the Oscars and actively aim for a 2/5.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:52:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Jackie Chan could come to Malegaon,” says a young man who has had the misfortune of being born there. “But his films won’t.” The young man is Nasir, the protagonist of director Reema Kagti’s new film, Superboys of Malegaon. Played by Adarsh Gourav, Nasir is the sort of cinephile who would have been logging at least three movies a day on Letterboxd had he been born a decade later, perhaps in a metropolitan city. And as hyperbolic as his words are, there is an element of truth to them. As we speak, the German auteur Wim Wenders is touring the length and breadth of India, taking selfies with Madhabi Mukherjee and reclining on Satyajit Ray’s favourite armchair. But you could be forgiven for not remembering the last time one of his films received a theatrical release here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:50:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, the global cinephile community — the sort of people who compose their Letterboxd reviews even before a film has ended — was thrown headfirst into a heated debate. As far as these folks were concerned, this was a debate of presidential magnitude — the kind of debate that could make a disagreement about Marvel movies seem like a ‘kavi sammelan’ in Lucknow. The British magazine Sight &amp;amp; Sound, which compiles a list of the greatest films of all time every decade, had published its latest rankings. And for the first time ever, the Belgian film Jeanne Dielman, 23 quai du Commerce, 1080 Bruxelles — previously viewed as a favourite only in niche circles — had claimed the top spot, sneaking past perennial favourites such as Citizen Kane, Tokyo Story, and Vertigo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:46:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inviting Javed Akhtar to the premiere of Nadaaniyan, and making him sit through it — it doesn’t matter that he had a recliner to relax on — is tantamount to elder abuse. Directed by Shauna Gautam, the Netflix romantic drama singlehandedly demolishes any argument that nepotism apologists might have preemptively constructed in the run-up to its release. Ineptly put together, lacking any insight whatsoever into the human experience, Nadaaniyan is a blot on Karan Johar’s career as a film producer, and one of the most questionable originals ever produced by Netflix India — remember, this is the streamer that deemed Shirish Kunder’s Mrs Serial Killer to be worthy of sharing the same server space as Alfonso Cuaron’s Roma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rekhachithram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/rekhachithram-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:27:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/rekhachithram-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Malayalam filmmakers aren’t just pushing the boundaries of genre cinema in India, they’ve evolved to a stage where they can confidently toy with tropes. In Aattam, director Anand Ekarshi created magic within the framework of murder mysteries by unraveling the expectations that they come attached with. Ekarshi performed a deft act of cinematic misdirection, revealing that Aattam wasn’t a mystery at all, but a sharp satire of patriarchy. In Rekhachithram, director Jofin T Chacko observes the doctrines of police procedurals, pays due respect to them, and then sends the movie down an altogether unexpected path in the final 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electric State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-electric-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 17:25:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-electric-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone on social media the other day posted that each of the last 15 Best Picture winners at the Oscars could’ve been funded for the amount that Netflix spent on The Electric State, the astronomically expensive new movie from directors Joe and Anthony Russo. We’re talking about films like Oppenheimer, which itself would’ve taken up $100 million of this cash pool, leaving the remaining $220 million to be spent on landmark films such as Parasite, 12 Years a Slave, and this year’s Anora. Starring Chris Pratt and Millie Bobby Brown, The Electric State is the kind of movie that seems to get longer while you’re watching it. No matter how deep into it you are — it could be the end of the first act or the second — it always feels like there’s an hour still left. On the face of it, The Electric State isn’t a particularly long movie. It taps out at around 120 minutes, which is positively merciful of the Russos, whose first gig after the global success of the three-hour-long Avengers: Endgame was Cherry, a 141-minute drama about a drug addict who robs banks to fund his habit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Broken Rage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/broken-rage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/broken-rage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent interview, actor Rajiv Thakur admitted that audiences that have seen him as a fixture on Kapil Sharma’s comedy shows will have no idea that he played a menacing terrorist in the spectacular streaming series IC 814: The Kandahar Hijack. And those who discovered him through IC 814 wouldn’t know that he has spent years as a part of Sharma’s silly troupe. In the Venn diagram of Indian entertainment, these audiences will never intersect, even though both IC 814 and The Great Indian Kapil Show are available on Netflix. Similarly, it is possible that cinephiles familiar with Takeshi Kitano through his art-house yakuza movies, or his memorable appearance in the hyper-violent Battle Royale, will collapse in shock they are told that he was so central to the game show Takeshi’s Castle that they named it after him. Kitano gets to play with his two creative personalities — the Golden Lion-winning filmmaker and the court jester — in his latest movie, Broken Rage, which was released on Prime Video with less fanfare than what you’d find at funerals in certain cultures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple Cider Vinegar S01</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/apple-cider-vinegar-s01-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 23:30:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/apple-cider-vinegar-s01-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both Mark Zuckerberg and the movie based on his early life, The Social Network, are referenced in the new Netflix mini-series Apple Cider Vinegar. Named after the snake oil that was being peddled online by seemingly every lifestyle influencer a few years ago, the show is inspired by the rather unbelievable story of Belle Gibson, a young Australian woman who scammed millions into subscribing to her personalised diet plans. Belle claimed that she’d beaten brain cancer by consuming clean food instead of conventional chemotherapy. The truth was that Belle was never diagnosed with cancer at all; it was the neglect that she experienced in childhood that compelled her to con the world. She’s played in the six-episode series by the wonderful Kaitlyn Dever, who rose to fame with the coming-of-age film Booksmart, and the even better Netflix series Unbelievable. In Apple Cider Vinegar, she puts on a convincing Australian accent, and finds a balance between Belle’s delusion and ambition. Abandoned by her troubled mother, Belle supposedly ran away from home at the age of 12. She gave birth to her first child when she was still a teenager, and subsequently embarked on a career as a huckster. Fuelled by a desire to be loved and accepted, she turned to social media to scratch this itch. Belle founded The Whole Pantry mobile app, through which she literally influenced terminally ill men and women into shunning traditional forms of treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gorge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-gorge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 23:28:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-gorge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gorge is four movies in one. Some might describe this as a value-for-money proposition. But others might find it a bit all over the place. There is no doubt, however, that the film bites off more than it can chew. And in the age of snackable ‘content’, this could be construed as high praise. Directed by Scott Derrickson, a filmmaker who has routinely shown skill at elevating genre movies, The Gorge coasts by for the majority of its two-hour run-time on star-power alone. There are long stretches of plodding nonsense, yes, but the film’s biggest strength lies in its constant determination to be unpredictable — relatively speaking, at least. Miles Teller and Anya Taylor-Joy play Levi and Drasa, two snipers who are hand-picked to keep guard at watchtowers on opposite ends of a mysterious gorge. We aren’t told where the gorge is located, or what our heroes are even supposed to be guarding. In time, however, we learn that the facility is strategically located somewhere between America and Russia, and that protecting it from being discovered was one of the biggest objectives during the Cold War. Levi and Drasa have been drafted to keep watch for exactly a year, following which they’ll be replaced by two others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juror #2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/juror-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 13:04:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/juror-2-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Director William Friedkin was so old and uninsurable during the making of the courtroom drama The Caine Mutiny Court-Martial that the Oscar-winner Guillermo del Toro sat beside him on set every day, contractually bound to take over in case Friedkin were to — forgive the morbidity — die mid-production. The legendary filmmaker got the job done, but passed away not long afterwards. He was 87 years old. Clint Eastwood is even older; at 94, he just delivered what could be his final film, Juror No 2. Coincidentally another courtroom drama, the movie arrives over three decades after Eastwood entered the self-reflective phase of his career with the contemplative Western Unforgiven. In the last decade or so, he has devoted himself — as one would expect of a dying man — to understanding the idea of decency. Having made a name for himself in a genre famous for viewing the world in black and white, Eastwood has spent the better part of the last couple of decades dabbling in different shades of grey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sugarcane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sugarcane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:35:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sugarcane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the year’s most striking documentary, Sugarcane is billed as an ‘investigation’ into the crimes that were committed by Catholic missionaries against Indigenous peoples of Canada across a century, but it is equally successful as an examination of inherited trauma, and as a study of a community in crisis. At the beginning of the 20th Century, schools were set up specifically for Indigenous children across North America, ostensibly to help them assimilate into Western culture. The children were subjected to unspeakable crimes at these ‘residential’ institutions, operated exclusively by the Catholic church, causing many of them to take their lives as they grew older. The magnitude of the tragedy, which is revealed gradually throughout the film, is immeasurable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wallace and Gromit Vengeance Most Fowl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:33:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trust Wallace to get himself mixed up in a plot that puts all of humanity at peril. The eccentric inventor — he’s the protagonist of Nick Park’s four-time Oscar-winning stop-motion animation series — makes his streaming debut alongside his ‘top dog’ Gromit with the feature-length Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit: Vengeance Most Fowl. Released on Netflix, the film is a pure nostalgia trip for fans who grew up with their charming adventures, replete with quirky household gizmos, absurd villains, and more cheese than you’d find in a Frenchman’s larder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blink</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/blink/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:30:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/blink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Canadian couple takes their children on a tour of the world in the new National Geographic documentary film Blink, but it isn’t just an ordinary vacation. Three of their four kids, aged between 13 and 7, have been diagnosed with retinitis pigmentosa, an incurable eye condition that will eventually render them blind. Overnight, the lives of the Pelletier family changed forever. The movie begins after the parents, Edith and Sebastien, made their peace with the cards they were dealt, although there is a sense that they will never fully wrap their heads around the tragedy. Still in the process of accepting their new reality, they collect their entire life’s savings and plan a trip across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yo Yo Honey Singh: Famous</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yo-yo-honey-singh-famous-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 13:00:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yo-yo-honey-singh-famous-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The standard for Indian documentaries about cultural icons is so low that Yo Yo Honey Singh: Famous, out now on Netflix, comes across as a refreshing change of pace. The streamer is itself guilty of lowering the bar with glorified PR exercises like Nayanthara: Beyond the Fairytale, Modern Masters: SS Rajamouli, and the worst of them all, The Romantics. They functioned more like corporate orientation films than the genuinely engaging journalistic profiles that they’re supposed to be. Not that the Honey Singh doc provides any real insight into his artistic process, barring the hilarious scene in which he is stumped by none other than Salman Khan. It does, however, do a decent enough job of giving audiences a peek inside his troubled mind. And for his fans, that will be enough. Many of them appear on camera, either commenting on his well-publicised fall from grace, or expressing their dismay at the lacklustre music that he has been releasing recently. In one scene, a woman tails him on a bike, and weeps openly as he stops to interact with her. A highly sensitive person himself, Honey recognises the emotions that she is experiencing, and begins serenading her with his biggest hit, “Blue Eyes.” Any cynical suspicion that you might have had about the woman being a plant disappears instantly. In another scene, a couple of flower sellers attempt to sell him a garland at the traffic signal. Honey quips that he needs a woman in his life to gift it to. They recognise him, and comment about his past troubles. “You’re looking smart now,” the young flower seller says to him. Honey is ecstatic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carry On</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/carry-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:41:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/carry-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Dwayne Johnson succeeds, he takes hundreds of others along for the ride with him. But when he fails — and he has, in recent years — he doesn’t go down alone. After establishing himself as something of a B-movie auteur early in his career, director Jaume Collet-Serra, like so many others in his position, accepted Hollywood’s offer to level up to the big leagues. He was appointed by Johnson as his latest lackey, but found himself responsible for directing the star’s two biggest recent bombs. These were movies — Jungle Cruise, and more calamitously, Black Adam — that significantly derailed Johnson’s career. Collet-Serra became collateral damage. But as it turns out, being relegated to the relatively forgiving realm of streaming was exactly the jolt to the system that he needed. His latest film, Carry-On, is his best in years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day of the Jackal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-day-of-the-jackal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:39:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-day-of-the-jackal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oscar-winner Eddie Redmayne is at his slipperiest in The Day of the Jackal, the new mini-series based on the classic beach read by Frederick Forsyth. The book was previously adapted into a lithe (and largely faithful) movie back in 1973, but has been updated for a modern audience by series creator Ronan Bennett. The bones of the story — a cat-and-mouse chase between an assassin on a mission and a secret agent tasked with stopping him — remain the same, but Bennett’s attempts to flesh the narrative out are mostly unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Doves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-doves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:35:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-doves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the almost criminally enjoyable new Netflix series Black Doves, Keira Knightley and Ben Whishaw play a chic housewife and her gay best friend who just happen to be covert operatives. They straddle dual identities, as does the show, which can often juggle tones with the deftness of a circus performer. Black Doves is at once a complex espionage thriller, a cheekily humorous dark comedy, and when it needs to be, a dreary domestic drama. It soars on the strength of its two central performances, and writing that is both self-aware and endearingly sincere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emilia Pérez</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emilia-p%C3%A9rez/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:32:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emilia-p%C3%A9rez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did the French auteur Jacques Audiard watch Chachi 420 and feel inspired to make his latest film, Emilia Pérez? Stranger things have happened this year. Nick Jonas has celebrated Holi in Greater Noida, and Ed Sheeran has fried a batata vada with Sanjyot Keer. Is the idea of Audiard, a Palme d’Or-winning maestro, watching a Kamal Haasan rip-off really that outlandish? The genre-fluid mess that it is, Emilia Pérez certainly has origins in mainstream Indian cinema — it can go from Ekta Kapoor-style drama to Farah Khan-inspired musical in a matter of minutes. And like so many of our country’s films, its gender politics aren’t entirely above reproach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/senna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/senna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If nobody were to speak in the new Netflix show Senna, it would immediately warrant at least two extra stars. But each time any of its wafer-thin characters opens their mouths, you’re likely to be overcome by an intense desire to pump the breaks and make a pit stop, or perhaps rewatch Asif Kapadia’s seminal documentary on the subject. Based on the life and career of the legendary Brazilian Formula One driver Ayrton Senna, the six-part biographical drama is flat, uninteresting, and most criminally, boring. It is perhaps the least effective way in which his extraordinary career, and lasting influence, could’ve been commemorated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman of the Hour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/woman-of-the-hour-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:27:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/woman-of-the-hour-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the wiser thing to do is to scale down. Not every film needs to be a sweeping epic, especially not one that demands a tight telling. Directed by the debutante Anna Kendrick, the darkly humorous thriller Woman of the Hour is based on an intriguing real-life story, but suffers from an under-confident execution. The movie would’ve worked wonderfully as a claustrophobic chamber piece, but feels compelled to jump across timelines and juggle between characters with an haphazardness that only does it harm. Kendrick is like an overeager Indian mum, checking the pressure cooker more often than she needs to, thereby releasing all the steam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:24:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A well-intentioned drama that teeters on the edge of self-parody, Joy is a film that absolutely deserved to be made, but certainly not in this form. Some years ago, the utterly forgotten The Current War had all the messy ingenuity that a film about the creation of literal electricity demanded — the movie’s tone captured the spirit of its themes. Joy, which dramatises the events leading up to the first in vitro fertilisation (IVF) birth, would have you believe that all conception — let alone that of the artificial kind — is a cakewalk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Piano Lesson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-piano-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:22:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-piano-lesson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is easy, one would imagine, for a filmmaker to be overwhelmed by the words of the great August Wilson. Especially if they’ve never made a film before. Musical and marauding, the Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright’s language is a vessel for the ambition and anger of his people. Netflix’s The Piano Lesson — the latest adaptation of Wilson’s celebrated Pittsburgh Cycle of plays — is directed by the debutante Malcolm Washington, whose father, the legendary Denzel Washington, has publicly devoted this stage of his career to shepherding Wilson’s work onto the screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:20:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like its protagonist, director Shuchi Talati’s Girls Will Be Girls is a constantly evolving entity. But behind an outer veneer of control, there is burgeoning angst, a simmering chaos, and a terrible desire to be seen and heard. The psychological drama played to an uncommonly interactive packed crowd at the Dharamshala International Film Festival recently — it was a bizarre screening that exemplified how important it is to watch movies in a community environment. Often, these experiences reveal more about society than the films themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 12:57:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an early scene in Singham Again where Ajay Devgn’s titular super-cop barges into his teenage son’s party along with a couple of cronies, embarrasses him in public, and hauls him back home. He does it, it seems, only to give director Rohit Shetty another opportunity to shoot him in stylised slow-motion. At home, Singham and his wife, Avni (Kareena Kapoor Khan) lecture their son about how out of touch he is with Indian values. It’s a deeply melodramatic moment; you can almost imagine them turning into Amitabh Bachchan and Hema Malini from Baghban in a couple of decades. But one thing is made absolutely clear by this early domestic drama: Shetty and Devgn don’t think too highly of the nation’s youth. This became a recurring theme even in their pre-release press interviews. They would both proudly declare that they barely resonate with the kids these days, and how, back in their day, they were roughing it out in the real world. This is a bizarre stance to take, for multiple reasons. For one, it’s always a good idea to understand younger generations. You might just learn something; just ask Javed Akhtar. But second, Singham Again is aimed at the very demographic that Shetty and Devgn have decided to infantilise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Move</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dont-move-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 13:16:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dont-move-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A young woman grieving the death of her child treks to the cliffside spot where he died. She intends to jump herself. Played by Kelsey Asbille, the woman is approached by a mysterious stranger, played by Finn Wittrock. He recognises immediately that she’s one step away from falling to her death. The stranger doesn’t attempt to talk her down from the ledge, but he makes enough of an impression for her to reconsider. They walk back together to the parking lot, where things take a sudden turn. The man injects her with some kind of paralytic substance, revealing that he isn’t a good samaritan after all. Thus begins Don’t Move, a high-concept thriller that producer Sam Raimi probably thought was going to turn out like his knockout 2016 film Don’t Breathe. It didn’t. These movies have nothing in common beyond Raimi’s involvement, and that gentle nudge of a title. In terms of quality, they couldn’t be further apart from each other. Don’t Move appears to be so pleased with its premise — it’s a survival thriller featuring an immobile protagonist! — that it forgets it needs to sustain this early momentum. The movie succeeds in drawing your sympathies for its heroine, Iris, but struggles to put her in interesting scenarios after this pre-credits sequence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Santosh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/santosh-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 13:07:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/santosh-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, there was an uproar over a scene of sustained violence in director Kathryn Bigelow’s Detroit, a period crime drama about a real-life incident that led to the deaths of three young men. The controversial scene unfolded across several uncomfortable minutes, and showed a group of white police officers beat down a lineup of innocent Black men. Bigelow didn’t avert her eyes from the horror, and instead, caught the audience by the scruff of the neck and made them watch. The film’s examination of ingrained racism, police brutality, and the systemic oppression of minorities drew parallels to modern-day America, but it also divided audiences. Director Sandhya Suri’s Santosh, which was screened at the recent Dharamshala International Film Festival, unpacks similar themes, but in the context of contemporary north India. Like Detroit, it pivots on a scene of unrelenting brutality that transforms it from a standard police procedural into something more haunting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tees/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:10:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In director Dibakar Banerjee’s Tees, three generations of a Kashmiri family grapple with identity, erasure, and a desire to be heard in an ever-evolving and increasingly intolerant India. It is cruelly ironic, therefore, that the movie itself has been throttled like its characters. Originally titled Freedom, the ambitious saga has effectively been caged on a hard disk by the paranoid Netflix. But despite being denied a release by the streamer, Tees was presented in its complete form at the 13th Dharamshala International Film Festival recently, with Banerjee present to soak in the warmth that seemed to be emanating from the hundreds of pilgrims who queued up for it on a winter evening. Tees opens, rather worryingly, with a scene that wouldn’t feel out of place in Banerjee’s latest, Love Sex Aur Dhoka 2, which was more an act of self-immolation than self-expression, if we’re being honest. A computer-generated black cat walks towards us, before it is revealed to be the internet avatar of a human being looking for a connection. The year is 2042, and a young writer named Anhad Draboo (Shashank Arora) appears rattled by the rejection of his rebellious verses by an overbearing government.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apocalypse Z - The Beginning of the End</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/apocalypse-z/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 13:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/apocalypse-z/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Influenced by every zombie thriller ever made, but more specifically, by the video game series The Last of Us, Prime Video’s Apocalypse Z: The Beginning of the End is a competently crafted thriller let down by a lack of ambition. The Spanish-language film unfolds across a year in the life of a grieving man named Manel, who is caught by himself in the middle of a zombie apocalypse. Manel is heartbroken over the death of his wife in a car crash not too long ago — the movie opens with this tragic scene — and is hanging on by a thread when the fast-spreading virus breaks out. Having survived the pandemic, everybody assumes that they can handle this outbreak as well. But they have no idea just how terrifying things are going to get. Initially, Manel decides to stay put at home and ignore the government’s instructions to participate in a military-aided evacuation. But after a couple of months in isolation, he has no choice but to make a move. Manel’s sister left with her family for the Canary Islands just as the outbreak got out of control, and even though he lost all contact with them a while ago, he decides that the smartest thing to do would be to make his way to them. Apocalypse Z is divided into chapters; not literally, like a Quentin Tarantino movie, but more structurally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Substance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-substance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:19:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-substance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A gleefully grotesque satire of success, director Coralie Fargeat’s English-language debut, The Substance, lives up to its title. But it has plenty of style to spare as well. Demi Moore stars as Elizabeth Sparkle, a fading actress who, in a moment of great weakness, decides to sample an underground drug that purportedly reverses the ageing process. But she quickly discovers that she has bitten off more than she can chew. The Substance is to Moore’s career what Birdman was to Michael Keaton’s, or The Wrestler was to Mickey Rourke’s, a movie that sheds its superficial obsession with superficiality and transforms into a whole new beast towards the end. It’s the kind of film that requires courage from everybody involved, including the caterers who were presumably tasked with preparing a menu that wouldn’t end up on the shooting floor everyday. It would be remarkable if nobody threw up while making this movie, because every moment of its incredible final act positively challenges you to keep your lunch in your stomach. But before Fargeat unleashes her final flourish, she sets up an increasingly absurd universe for Elizabeth to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Caddo Lake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/caddo-lake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:13:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/caddo-lake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A slow-burn thriller with a deep emotional core, an intricately plotted genre exercise, and an acting showcase for two talented young performers, Caddo Lake, on paper, sounds like the complete package. It takes a while to get going, and the first act is particularly testing, but it’s also the kind of film that gets better with every passing minute. In fact, Caddo Lake is at its best towards the end, when it ties all — or, at least two — of its narrative threads together, unleashing an emotional wallop that rivals only the sheer thrill of watching its well-executed twist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Is the Zodiac Speaking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/this-is-the-zodiac-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:22:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/this-is-the-zodiac-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often described as ‘the most famous unsolved murder case in American history’, the Zodiac Killer’s brutal spree in the 1960s and ‘70s attracted a flock of amateur investigators before true crime was even a thing. But now it is, and as per the law, Netflix is mandated to make a three-part documentary series about it. Titled This is the Zodiac Speaking, the show confusingly omits the real-life chapter that inspired this title, and presents, instead, a new angle to the case, one that has been flogged to death by documentarians, filmmakers, and podcasters alike. This is the Zodiac Speaking has the same fast-paced narrative that has come to define most of these Netflix true crime content; the tone is perpetually ominous, the violence and mayhem is circled and highlighted, cheap recreations are used to heighten the drama. The ending, invariably, is anti-climactic. But the show attempts to sidestep this inevitability by picking its lane and sticking to it. In minute one, This is the Zodiac Speaking identifies a possible suspect — in fact, the only person who was ever publicly named by the police as a person of interest — and proceeds to move heaven and earth in an effort to corroborate its claims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 11:33:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting an audience to detest a movie villain isn’t difficult. People are cynical; all they want is someone to project their frustrations on. But getting the same viewers to genuinely empathise with the protagonist of your film isn’t as easy as it might seem. It requires them to lower their guards and shed their egos; to allow moments of vulnerability in the presence of absolute strangers. Most of all, it requires them to ignore the objectively lunatic act of developing a connection with a made-up person, as if they are real. But Vasan Bala has cracked the code in Jigra — a film that pulls off this almost impossibly difficult feat by getting you, the viewer, to participate in the grandest act of collective empathy crafted on a Bollywood screen this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:02:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normally, one of the most frustrating things that a movie can do is to abandon its characters and become too consumed by the plot. Our mainstream cinema has always struggled with this, and things have only become worse in the streaming era. It is said that show runners, in particular, can get away with anything on digital platforms as long as there is a murder in the first episode. Well, someone most certainly dies at the end of the first act in CTRL, the new film from Vikramaditya Motwane — his first feature since AK vs AK in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/joker-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 15:59:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/joker-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’d think that the world was a less paranoid place five years ago, when the collective trauma of the pandemic hadn’t clobbered us on the head with a comically large mallet. But remember when governments were put on high alert before the release of a comic book movie about a murderous clown? Prepared for the riots that the supposedly incendiary film might incite, teams of police were stationed outside certain screenings of Todd Phillips’ Joker — a movie that was viewed by alarmists as a sort of dog whistle for basement-dwelling incels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
