<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Waking of a Nation on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-waking-of-a-nation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Waking of a Nation on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:36:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-waking-of-a-nation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Waking of a Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:36:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The unrest surrounding the oppressive Rowlatt Act culminates in the Jallianwala Bagh massacre. London-educated advocate Kantilal Sahni, witnessing the carnage, loses his childhood friends Hari and Allahbaksh amidst the political chaos. Haunted by their deaths, Sahni exposes the systemic injustice of the British Raj that facilitated the massacre, while leading the Hunter Commission inquiry. Taaruk Raina, popular for his lighter roles, makes a welcome departure from his strengths, in a heavy role packed with old-fashioned drama – an arena he’s not fully comfortable with, though he delivers a sincere performance. Sahil Mehta, as the angsty journalist with firm opinions, is at ease with his portrayal and is helped by his strong screen presence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Waking of a Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 09:00:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a blood splattered Baisakhi on April 13, 1919. When a jashan (celebration) turned into a janazaa (funeral) for the hundreds gunned down at Jallianwala Bagh, Amritsar. General Dyer went down in history as the butcher. He was the cruel perpetrator, also the puppet. But mastermind, ringmaster and puppeteer Lieutenant-General Michael O’Dwyer was never formally indicted. (Udham Singh did shoot him dead more than 20 years later.) Is it time for an unwritten chapter to be brought to the fore? Director Ram Madhvani who had shown glimpses of how well he can segue imagination into history when he made the short film That Bloody Line (on how Sir Cyril Radcliffe cut off bits of India on the west and on the east), goes down the same path, same era.This time to recreate the Amritsar of 1919.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Waking of a Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:34:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In cricket, when the fielding team challenges an LBW (Leg Before Wicket) call, the DRS (Decision Review System) comes into play. This DRS process is a lot like reviewing a film or show. Every stage corresponds to real-world parameters. First, the third umpire checks if it’s a legal delivery — the equivalent of checking if the craft and shot-taking and basic staging are fundamentally sound. Then they move onto Snickometer to see if there’s an edge off the bat or glove — the equivalent of checking if the storytelling is engaging. Finally, Ball Tracking is used to project the trajectory of the delivery. Even here, it doesn’t matter if the ball is hitting the stumps, it has to pitch in line — the equivalent of checking if the intent and politics of the narrative add up. If all checks out, the on-field decision can be reversed and the batsman is ruled out — the equivalent of defying an anti-art industry and making a good show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Waking of a Nation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 20:20:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-waking-of-a-nation-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 1919 Jallianwala Bagh massacre remains a pivotal event in India&amp;rsquo;s fight for freedom. The deadly killings of hundreds of Indian civilians during the British Raj have been covered several times in cinema. SonyLIV&amp;rsquo;s new limited series looks at the painful historical event through the eyes of a young lawyer who is part of the Hunter Commission, which aims to find out what happened that day in April 1919. Led by a very able Taaruk Raina as the London return lawyer, The Waking of a Nation is less a historical recreation of what happened but rather an examination of the events that led up the massacre.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
