<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Complete Unknown on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/a-complete-unknown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Complete Unknown on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 08:55:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/a-complete-unknown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Complete Unknown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-complete-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 08:55:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-complete-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time we meet Bob Dylan (Timothee Chalamet) in A Complete Unknown, he’s uncomplainingly laying in the back of a wagon amongst a pile of luggage. He’s just hitched a ride to New York City to see his hero, folk musician Woody Guthrie (Scoot McNairy), who has been hospitalised after being diagnosed with Huntington’s disease. Dylan overhears an impassioned discussion trying to determine if Guthrie is a folk or a country musician. “There’s no need to box him,” one of them says. It’s 1961 and a particularly tense period in America, as the House of Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC) is summoning people for their alleged communist ties. The celebrities of Hollywood are understandably first in line, just like the musicians of the time like Pete Seeger (Edward Norton), who was critical of the American government. Social justice is becoming a street-side topic among many, as America is sinking deeper into the Vietnam War, the Civil Rights movement is picking up steam. Two years later, a president will be assassinated during a motorcade, fuelling the paranoia of the public and future governments alike.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
