<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sky Force on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/sky-force/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sky Force on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 10:19:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/sky-force/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 10:19:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A group of Indian fighter pilots, led by Om Ahuja (Akshay Kumar), is tasked with the destruction of a fleet of modern American F-104 Starfighters at the Sargodha airbase in the 1965 war. Meanwhile, a young pilot T Krishna Vijaya (Veer Pahariya), disobeys orders and ventures into enemy territory to rescue his fellow pilots. Haunted by the disappearance of his protégé, Ahuja embarks on a quest to uncover the truth while facing resistance and bureaucratic hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 17:04:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A film releasing close to Republic Day and starring the new-age Bharat Kumar, the poster boy of patriotism Akshay Kumar, and you enter the cinema halls with a bit of dread. But you are pleasantly surprised both by the storyline and the fact that though the film harks back to the 1965 Indo-Pak war, there is no overt Pakistan-bashing or screechy jingoism. ‘Sky Force’, based on true events — actually the Indian Air Force’s retaliatory attack on Pakistan’s Sargodha airfield — tells the story simply, without too many theatrical excesses. Prior to the release, it has been drawing comparisons with last year’s Republic Day release, ‘Fighter’. However, except for some finely executed aerial action set pieces and dogfights, there isn’t much to compare, both in good and bad ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 08:22:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पहले एक सच्ची कहानी सुन लीजिए। 1965 में हुई भारत-पाकिस्तान की जंग में भारतीय वायु सेना ने पाकिस्तान के भीतर तक घुस कर उनके सरगोधा एयर-बेस को न सिर्फ बुरी तरह तबाह कर दिया था बल्कि अमेरिका से उन्हें तोहफे में मिले बहुत सारे लड़ाकू जहाजों को भी नष्ट कर दिया था जबकि वे जहाज भारत के लड़ाकू जहाजों से कई गुना बेहतर थे। इस अभियान में एक भारतीय लड़ाकू विमान भी नष्ट हो गया था और उसका पायलट लापता। वायु सेना ने उस पायलट ए.बी. देवैया को ’मिसिंग इन एक्शन’ घोषित कर दिया लेकिन उसके करीबी विंग कमांडर तनेजा को हमेशा लगता रहा कि वह पायलट जीवित है। क्या हुआ था उस पायलट के साथ…? क्या वह सचमुच लापता हो गया था…? मर गया था…? या फिर…!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 22:45:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kH1-17Lg3EI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:51:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/c-GPNN8po8M?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:49:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week last year, a film released that seemed to epitomise popular Hindi cinema’s decline over a decade. Fighter might have set out to cash in on the success of Top Gun: Maverick, but it played like an advertisement for the sitting government at the centre. Releasing months before the general elections, the film—like Uri: The Surgical Strike in 2019—showed the prime minister as capable commander in chief while engaging in hysterical Pakistan-baiting. “Unhe dikhaana padega ki baap kaun hai (we’ll show them who daddy is),” the PM in the film says, a statesman-like sentiment befitting a Republic Day release. Sky Force also takes a ‘baap’ jab at Pakistan, but it’s a half-hearted swipe. As a fighter pilot film releasing on the weekend of 26 January, there are certain jingoistic beats directors Sandeep Kewlani and Abhishek Anil Kapur must feel they have to hit. And they do, but their heart isn’t in it. On the face of it, there’s not much to recommend this film—it&amp;rsquo;s underwritten, square and tries to pull off elaborate action on a clearly insufficient budget. But where Fighter tends towards rabid nationalism, Sky Force stumbles awkwardly in search of reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:46:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to be disappointed with Sky Force. One, through the lens of its creators. Up until now, the production company Maddock Films — on a high following the dizzying success of its horror-comedy multiverse — has managed to innovate and stay interesting without conforming to mass trends and jingoistic patterns. It’s worth noting that Sky Force is its first real foray into this zone. But within the contours of the herd-mentality move, it tries something different. It chooses to dramatise a real-life story that’s equal parts war movie and investigative drama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 18:25:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago, almost to the day, when Fighter released and didn’t exactly set the box office on fire, director Siddharth Anand put forth a bizarre claim. He said that the Hrithik Roshan-Deepika Padukone starrer, described by its makers as “India’s first aerial action film”, had not found much favour with the audience because “90 per cent of Indians haven’t flown in planes”. By that logic, one would have to be an Italian mafioso to appreciate The Godfather. The good thing is that you don’t have to sign up for a fighter pilot licence before you walk in for a show of Sky Force. This bi-annual Akshay Kumar deshbhakti dose — ‘a fictional story inspired by real events’ — has the kind of thrill and drama that every viewer, brought up on a steady diet of Bollywood patriotic films, is familiar with. Which is both a good and a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 12:53:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is honour among enemies – sometimes. When the Indian Air Force captures decorated Pakistani officer Wing Commander Hussain Ahmed (Sharad Kelkar) in the 1971 war, Wing Commander Om Ahuja (Akshay Kumar) interrogates him. And learns that Ahmed got his gallantry award for shooting down an Indian aircraft in the Sargodha attack in 1965. But the Pak officer won’t reveal anything more. After the ceasefire, Ahmed is sent back to Pakistan. India has acted honorably with a PoW. The downing of the Indian aircraft in Sargodha opens unhealed old wounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:25:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year Bollywood’s Republic-Day gift was Fighter, which zoomed in, checking several patriotic-movie boxes: brave Indian fighter pilots, going up against favourite enemy Pakistan, displaying valour and camaraderie. This year, it is Sky Force, coasting on the same elements, except this one is a thinly-disguised account of a real life incident during the 1965 Indo-Pak conflict, in which a squadron decimated a fleet of modern American jets housed at Pakistani base Sargodha, in an operation the film calls Sky Force.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 08:29:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sky Force directed by Sandeep Kewlani and Abhishek Anil Kapur is led by Akshay Kumar and introduced a debutante star Veer Pahariya. The film based on real incident follows the story of Air Force officers O.P. Taneja and Ajjamada Boppayya Devayya. The makers have fictionalized the characters for their onscreen portrayal but the almost raw performances are. The film begins in 1971 when a Pakistani pilot attacking on Indian soil is capture. The Group Captain played by Akshay Kumar aka Ahuja meets the pilot to question him about his plans, and Pakistan&amp;rsquo;s plans to attack India. However, during a very civil interrogation, Ahuja finds out that he is the same pilot who may have attacked his former colleague who has been missing in action for over six years. The film then turns to a flash back in 1965 where Veer&amp;rsquo;s character is introduced as Vijya his call name Tabby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
