<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Do Patti on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/do-patti/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Do Patti on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:48:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/do-patti/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 18:48:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are twin sisters—Saumya and Shelly—played by Kriti Sanon in a beautiful Uttarakhand town with paragliders covering the blue sky. What a sense of relief in this confusing weather. Defused lighting and a lot of touch ups to bring out the best facial features of good-looking leads ensure a soothing start of a tale which harps on the childhood animosity of the twins. They both have their eyes set on a baby-faced yet quite violent Dhruv Sood (Shaheer Sheikh), which eventually leads to a cop and criminal chase led by Vidya Jyoti aka VJ (Kajol) to a point where the real purpose of law books and its practical usage would be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:02:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do Patti begins with scattered shots of paragliding gone wrong and a stakeout on a bridge, followed by a woman in a police station telling the cops her husband tried to kill her. Phir Aayi Hasseen Dillruba, released in August, also has a stakeout on a bridge, and its first scene is a woman in a police station telling the cops her husband is going to kill her. Both films are written by Kanika Dhillon, both are Netflix releases. Did no one think it was a problem that the films start the exact same way?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:00:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dressed in the exact same attire as her newly wedded sister at her reception, the lookalike twin poses right next to the bride and groom as if fulfilling Bollywood&amp;rsquo;s bawdy fantasy of saali aadhi gharwali in a tasteless, thunder-stealing move.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a rare tantalising moment in a pile of trite twists and turns where Do Patti, directed by Shashanka Chaturvedi, gives in to its basest impulses but collapses like a house of cards when it aims to be clever, or worse still, a crusader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:57:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time, one believed that a compelling cinematic narrative shows more than it tells, and expresses more than it explains. However, the recent content spurt on OTT platforms seems bent on cerebrating the opposite. Do Patti is yet another addition to the long list of films that skip theatres for a streaming service. It reduces the art of storytelling to a mere artifice for meaningful cinema. These films end up delivering the message but little else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:46:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shailee and Saumya are twin sisters who lose their mom early in life. Ever since, they don’t get on well with one another and Shailee is soon shifted to a boarding school. Many years later, Saumya falls for Dhruv, an adventure sports enthusiast and son of a politician. Shailee, unexpectedly, returns to her home town and tries to be the party pooper in their relationship. Where’s the tale headed?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;do-Kriti Sanon in her maiden production essays a double role with impressive finesse, portraying the contrasting twins Shailee and Saumya effectively. No prizes for guessing that Shailee is the pulpier, interesting role of the two. Kajol is particularly impressive with her comic timing, slipping into the shoes of a street-smart cop-cum-lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:25:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xZI_eV47fUg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:23:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0p_wBOwo6Jo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:22:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TUwK72xv1Bs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:20:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0wGCmNDCgGI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:15:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Twins Saumya and Shailee (Kriti Sanon in a double role, this is not a spoiler) are like chalk and cheese. One gets married to hot-headed Dhruv Sood, (television actor Shaheer Sheikh) the privileged man with a volatile temper and political connect who owns a paragliding business in the hills. All’s well on the surface until an unlikely crime makes police officer VJ (Kajol) question everything about this family.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do Patti is deceptive. In an ideal scenario, this could have worked wonders as a thriller but that’s not the case here. Do Patti is deceptive as a film, not as a mystery. You are led on and lured into believing that there’s more to this long-winding twin sister saga but it’s all a damp squib. For some strange reason, you pin your hopes on the big twist that might redeem the situation but that wish stays unfulfilled as it&amp;rsquo;s predictable and underwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:11:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bu4sjQLbyh0?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 06:33:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;पति-पत्नी के रिश्ते में जब प्यार की जगह हिंसा ले ले, तो चोट पूरे परिवार और खासकर बच्चों को लगती है। घरेलू हिंसा का यह जख्म कभी-कभी इतना गहरा होता है कि पूरा घर बिखर जाता है। विडंबना देखिए, हिंसा के इतने खतरनाक रूप को &amp;lsquo;घरेलू&amp;rsquo; कहा जाता है, जिस कारण घर से बाहर के ज्यादातर लोग पति-पत्नी के इस आपसी मामले में दखल तक नहीं देते। घरेलू हिंसा की इसी कड़वी सच्‍चाई को दो बहनों की राइवलरी के मसालेदार पैकेजिंग में लपेटकर पेश करती है, एक्ट्रेस कृति सेनन और राइटर कनिका ढिल्लों के बैनर की डेब्यू फिल्म &amp;lsquo;दो पत्ती&amp;rsquo;।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 19:46:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Both Kajol and Kriti Sanon embark on a couple of firsts in Shashanka Chaturvedi&amp;rsquo;s directorial debut Do Patti. Written by Kanika Dhillon, the Hindi film sees Kajol as tough-on crime police officer and Kriti takes on a double role as twin sisters. The Netflix suspense drama relies on a couple of red herrings eventually emerging as a wobbly thriller with a message.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The story takes place in a picturesque hill station where our protagonists&amp;rsquo; noses and cheeks are constantly rosy due to the chill factor. Police inspector Vidya Jyothi aka VJ (Kajol) is determined to prove that Saumya (Kriti) is being abused by her husband Dhruv Sood (Shaheer Sheikh). She finally gets her opportunity but realises something is off about the larger picture. The timid Saumya has few people in her corner; even her outgoing twin Shailee (also Kriti) has betrayed her enough times. So how does Saumya finally accept Vidya Jyothi&amp;rsquo;s help?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 23:44:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co produced by Kriti Sanon and Kanika Dhillon the film suffers from lack of consistency possibly from the writing stage. The film aims to spread awareness about women and domestic abuse, it attempts to express the turmoils of abuse trauma, its generational history but fails to do it through out the run time. The film tries hard to be It Suspect X (Jaane Jaan), It Ends With Us, Gone Girl and The Girl In The Train all at once with a crime thriller genre — it ends up being none of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 21:30:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is domestic abuse a hush-hush family matter or a crime against society? Is a judge who goes by the word of law (and evidence) dispensing true justice or is a lawyer who looks at the spirit of the law more inclined towards social good?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the end of a disturbing narration where nothing seems to be what it is, writer Kanika Dhillon (story, screenplay, dialogues) opens up an important but inconvenient debate that brings abuse out of the four walls of the house.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:22:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identical twins of the kind that we encounter in Hindi popular cinema are always temperamentally polar opposites. The pair in Do Patti, a Netflix film directed by Shashanka Chaturvedi, is no exception - they look the same but are dissimilar in disposition and demeanour. The film, however, deviates from the larger narrative template that governs the genre. Mumbai movies may have stumbled upon a degree of freedom thanks to the advent of the streamers, but old habits die hard. Do Patti, scripted by Kanika Dhillon, has an old trope at its core. It, however, eschews the usual confusion-caused-by-mistaken-identity construct.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Do Patti’ comes armed with much promise. It is the first offering of a brand new female-led production house, with producer-actor Kriti and writer Kanika Dhillon having created an interesting ensemble led by Kajol, popular TV actor Shaheer Sheikh, Tanvi Azmi, Brijendra Kala and Vivek Mushran. What’s not to like? Turns out, quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The film begins busily. An adventure in the skies, high up in the mountains, turns into a near-disaster. A shaken wife points a finger at her husband, accusing him of lethal designs. Local cop Vidya Jyoti aka VJ (Kajol) begins investigating. Is Saumya (Kriti Sanon), hiding facial bruises, correct in feeling that Dhruv (Shaheer Sheikh) has placed her life in danger? Why would Dhruv, the scion of a businessman intent upon growing his base, who asked for her hand after a sweet courtship, do such a thing? Is he as nice as he appears to be, or is he a monster? What is Saumya’s highly competitive identical twin Shailee (Kriti Sanon again, in a double role) hiding? Does the elderly woman (Tanvi Azmi) who has been part of the twins’ rocky childhood, know something?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:17:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The growing worry about lack of quality control in the OTT space now has a physical embodiment. Do Patti. A film which may have its heart in the right place but is otherwise all over the place. Do Patti aims to be a sensitive and scathing film on domestic abuse. The other tags it wants to earn for itself are a noir thriller, a police procedural, a film on sibling rivalry, a blistering criticism of privilege and a racy romance laced with sex, lies and videotape (or rather, mobile phone footage). It ends up being neither.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
