<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Girls Will Be Girls on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/girls-will-be-girls/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Girls Will Be Girls on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:10:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/girls-will-be-girls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:10:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an unspecified North Indian hilltown boarding school, a girl comes of age. That overused phrase ‘coming-of-age’ is a misnomer when it comes to mainstream Hindi cinema: the years between thirteen and eighteen are those where contradictory impulses leap between synapses, with mind and body taking off in opposite directions, and explorations of both taking you into spaces where you’ve never been before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are elements Bollywood has never been comfortable with. Even if films do get made around this subject, their teenagers are either carefully sanitized or overtly fetishised. The result: infantilised characters and viewers, who’ve never been given a chance to grow up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:20:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like its protagonist, director Shuchi Talati’s Girls Will Be Girls is a constantly evolving entity. But behind an outer veneer of control, there is burgeoning angst, a simmering chaos, and a terrible desire to be seen and heard. The psychological drama played to an uncommonly interactive packed crowd at the Dharamshala International Film Festival recently — it was a bizarre screening that exemplified how important it is to watch movies in a community environment. Often, these experiences reveal more about society than the films themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:17:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X0YzJud5Mr4?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:14:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I won’t allow anything more than a friendship,” decrees Anila (Kani Kusruti), a very mom thing to say. She is sizing up a tall, sweet boy, Srinivas (Kesav Binoy Kiron), who’s drawn her daughter’s affections at their elite, hillside boarding school. The girl, Mira (Preeti Panigrahi), stands at the door and listens. The camera mimics her watchful gaze. It is a simple domestic intervention, yet it thrums with suspense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a charged, decisive moment in Shuchi Talati’s Girls Will Be Girls, which won two prizes at the Sundance Film Festival. Anila is a fussy, controlling parent, turning up annually from Haridwar to tide Mira through her exams. She is also lonely and emotionally desolate. Her choice of dress to meet Srinivas gives it away: a bright, oversized pink top with puffed shoulders, likely purchased at a younger age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:50:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Girls Will Be Girls is a quietly breathtaking film. It includes several remarkable debuts – starting with writer-director Shuchi Talati. This is her first feature, and she weaves this coming-of-age story of 18-year-old Mira with tenderness, frankness and delicacy. Female teenage sexuality has rarely been captured with this sensitivity and nuance in an Indian film. Second, Preeti Panigrahi who plays Mira. Panigrahi is the find of the year. Without a trace of strain or drama, she captures the myriad emotions coursing through Mira as she discovers passion, sexuality, unbridled rage, a twisted sort of jealousy, resentment, disappointment and eventually, comfort. And third, Richa Chadha and Ali Fazal who debut as producers with their company Pushing Buttons Studios. Girls Will Be Girls does this with skill and uncommon grace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:49:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writer-director Shuchi Talati’s debut feature is a simmering and sexually tense coming of age drama. Set in a boarding school, the story is centred around Mira, a school topper, head prefect and teacher’s pet. She’s driven to excel and considers herself the model student, upholder of school rules and moral gatekeeper. So, it’s confusing for the obedient and righteous Mira to be faced with challenges outside of the curriculum and to realise that book-learned knowledge might be no match against street smarts, life experience and generational patriarchal conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:47:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brilliant and sensitive schoolgirl in love with a classmate is watched, monitored and scrutinised incessantly as she seeks to break free from familial and societal shackles in Girls Will Be Girls, writer-director Shuchi Talati&amp;rsquo;s self-assured, award-winning narrative feature debut now streaming on Amazon Prime Video. The exquisitely crafted and insightful coming-of-age drama, an Indo-French co-production that bagged two awards at the Sundance Film Festival this year, is buoyed by impeccable writing and a couple of consummate performances by debutante Preeti Panigrahi and the seasoned Kani Kusruti.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:05:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot going on within twelfth-grader Mira (Preeti Panigrahi). Chosen as the first female head prefect at her seemingly orthodox hill-station boarding school, she’s battling most of the pressures and anxieties of being a teenager, while simmering in the shadow of her vivacious mother Anila (Kani Kusruthi). Mira needs to keep her scores up, balance the shifted power dynamic with friends and bullies because of her duties as a head prefect, and rein in her excessively eager hormones for the mysterious new boy – Srinivas (Kesav Binoy Kiron) – in class.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 19:50:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every viewing of Shuchi Talati&amp;rsquo;s excellent Girls will be Girls, produced by Richa Chadha, will probably elicit a different response. The coming-of-age film focused on a mother and daughter is tender, moving and nuanced. The period story is set around a boarding school where rules and regulations reign supreme. But through them, these women break free, to live a little.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The film introduces us to Mira Kishore (Preeti Panigrahi) just as she has been named Head Prefect. The 16-year-old is a model student and a stickler for rules, and eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll see how the pressure eventually gets to her. Mira is intrigued by new student Srinivas (Kesav Binoy Kiron), eventually forming a romantic relationship with him, under her mother Anila&amp;rsquo;s (Kani Kusruti) watchful eyes. Over time, both Mira and Anila&amp;rsquo;s relationship with Sri changes, and brings them both to a breaking point.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:16:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Girls Will Be Girls is helmed by first time feature film director Suchi Talati. It follows the story of a high school top student in a coming of age story. But the story isn&amp;rsquo;t just about Mira played by Preeti Panigrahi but also about her mom Anila played by Kani Kusruti. Their complex relationship amid Mira&amp;rsquo;s rebellious romance with NRI boy Sri (Kesav Binoy Kiron), the tense environment in strict school. The film offers a change for millennials to live through some of their most embarrassing and traumatizing memories but also gives a chance to many more in building a better and more nutriting relationship with their mothers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
