<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>What if S03 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/what-if-s03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in What if S03 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:21:18 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/what-if-s03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What If S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/what-if-s03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 01:21:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/what-if-s03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The final season of What If&amp;hellip;? Season 3 highlights Marvel characters, big and small, in unexpected ways. Honouring both the comics and the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU), it allowed the story to be taken further. Once more, Jeffrey Wright returns as the voice of The Watcher as he narrates these eight new stories from the multiverse, where characters from different worlds and times converge. While previous seasons were strong, this last season is a mixed bag. It starts off muddled and ends on a high note, leaving us wishing this season had a bit more substance. Each of the eight episodes of What If&amp;hellip;? looks at an alternative universe where characters who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t ordinarily meet are featured. And of course, the casual fan or newbie will be extremely lost, as the series requires you to do your homework (watch all the stuff) before enjoying this even more. Some of the stories explored here include the Hulk accidentally creating a gamma monster that the Mech Avengers must battle with, Agatha Harkness going Hollywood and meeting up with Bollywood star King, the Watcher disappearing, and the most bizarre of all, Howard the Duck having a baby with Darcy Lewis!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What If S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/what-if-s03-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:44:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/what-if-s03-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What If&amp;hellip;? returned with season 3 sharing a deep dive into the 5th dimension and hinted at what we can expect from the future of the multiverse. The show does show Sam Wilson as the new Captain America on a world saving mission with Bruce Banner and others. Meanwhile, more magical and mystical creatures come to life as the Watcher guides more superheroes to save their universes. With every season of What If&amp;hellip;? Marvel continues to surprise their fans with something unexpected, the same is true for season 3 as the multiverse gets more weird and messy. Each episode shared a piece of a story from a different universe and what canon event may have shaped it. It also reveals how The Watcher sees it, and experiences it, the changes he would have expected and wished for. In the past seasons, The Watcher had gotten himself involved in the multiverse by saving lives and reshaping the world. As he continues to do so, it leaves The Eminence unhappy. That too shapes a path for the mortals to move on to a new dimension and turn their fate over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
