<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Holland on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/holland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Holland on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:31:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/holland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Holland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:31:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mystery thriller is directed by Mimi Cave, who is best known for Flesh, a film focused on body horror. A glimpse of the same can be seen in Holland, but this is more focused on being a mystery thriller for its own characters. The trailer zeros in on the story, and the same narrative is explored during the almost two-hour-long film. Led by Nicole Kidman and Matthew Macfadyen, the film explores the dynamics of a family that looks perfect on the outside but something sinister is going on underneath. The film also stars a young actor Jude Hill and Gael García Bernal as the second love interest for Nicole. It begins with Nicole&amp;rsquo;s narration as Nancy Vandergroot, a teacher at the local high school where he kid also goes. She is respected around the town as the wife of Fred Vandergroot, a good church going man who is a life-saving doctor. Their kid, Harry, follows every word of his father, who ends up mediating their fights. Their life is perfect and good, but something remains off about Nancy as she gets obsessive and paranoid about little things. First, it is a missing earning which leads to her firing a babysitter and later, it is a receipt she finds in Fred&amp;rsquo;s pants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:11:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After breaking out with the horror-thriller Fresh a few years ago — this was the movie in which Daisy Edgar-Jones played a young woman on a blind date with a man who turns out to be a cannibal — director Mimi Cave stays firmly in her comfort zone with her sophomore project, this week’s Holland. The cast is bigger, as is the budget and the scale. Fresh was mostly restricted to one large house, where the predatory male protagonist would lure his female prey and then, literally feast on them. An entire suburban town serves as Cave’s playground this time around; and at least one of its citizens is a killer of women. Nicole Kidman plays Nancy, a seemingly mild-mannered woman who works at the local school and dotes on her husband, Fred, played by Matthew Macfadyen. The one-time heartthrob — he played Mr Darcy in 2005’s Pride &amp;amp; Prejudice adaptation — seems to have been typecast as weaselly villains following his memorable performance as Tom Wambsgans in HBO’s Succession. Fred works as an optometrist; he’s the sort of guy that everybody seems to be friendly with, but crucially, not friends with. Nancy becomes suspicious when he starts going on weekly work trips, often using the flimsiest excuses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
