<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pushpa 2 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/pushpa-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pushpa 2 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:12:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/pushpa-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:12:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why do we like Pushparaj? He doesn’t care to look conventionally attractive. His shoulders are lop-sided, his hair unkempt, his speech brimming with contempt. His work? Smuggling red sanders. His retribution? A fierce defiance of systematic oppression, making him a figure of political utility. And his manner of retribution? Ruthless. As he says, he kills “without mercy.” In this sequel, Pushpa seems almost possessed, his machete slicing through limbs as though they were branches from a tree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:46:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Pushpa naam nahi hain, Pushpa matlab brand hain”, (Pushpa is not just a name; it signifies a brand) states Srivalli, portrayed by Rashmika Mandanna, in this sequel anticipated to shatter all box office records. This statement prompts reflection on whether it is the character speaking or if the filmmakers are conveying their confidence through her words. Following the success of Pushpa (2021), the sequel is grander in every aspect, running an exhausting 200 minutes, though it does not necessarily surpass its predecessor. The filmmakers have amplified every successful element from the first installment, leaving no stone unturned in terms of scale and ambition. However, the narrative, or lack of it, remains unchanged—if the first part emphasised “Pushpa flower nahin, fire hai main”, the second part shifts to portraying him as a wildfire, whatever that may imply.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:09:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gRedhGuzEEw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:07:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RIWmn_YJELo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:06:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oD5IsFYVxS4?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:04:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wpyn77jz8tY?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 21:48:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some narratives tend to grow upon repeated viewing, revealing subtle details. Before the release of Pushpa 2: The Rule, revisiting the 2021 Telugu action drama Pushpa – The Rise, the origin story of Pushparaj (Allu Arjun), a coolie who rises through the ranks of a smuggling syndicate in the Chittoor district of erstwhile Andhra Pradesh, highlights how writer-director Sukumar establishes the protagonist as a potential leader. Pushpa is often framed at a higher position than the others, as he navigates tricky situations. These visual metaphors apart, there was a nuanced portrayal of how Pushpa dealt with members of the syndicate as well as the cops. His Achilles heel? Being born out of wedlock, he is frequently taunted about his surname or ‘inti peru’ (family name).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 21:46:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First things first. I am not a fan of Pushpa: The Rise, the first film in filmmaker Sukumar’s franchise. I found it lagging behind in storytelling, performance of the lead actor and filled with quite a few problematic moments. However, I am pleasantly surprised to find Pushpa 2: The Rule not only better than part one but also a paisa vasool entertainer. The first film ended with Pushpa Raj (Allu Arjun) becoming a large force in the world of red sandalwood smuggling. In the end, he marries his lady love Srivalli (Rashmika Mandanna) while his nemesis in the form of the cop Bhanwar Singh Shekhawat (Fahadh Faasil) vows to destroy Pushpa for his crimes and the insult meted out to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 20:39:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It opens on a Japanese port with a clever twist to the famous song ‘Mera joota hai Japani’, giving a miss to the second line that talks of the country, now an aggressor. But the aggression in the film is a given. What follows is a high-on-adrenaline action sequence almost like a climactic scene. So, where can Pushpa go from such a strong build-up? Well, back to where it began, right to Pushpa’s childhood and the indignities he suffered due to his illegitimate bearings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:19:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pushpa: The Rise (2021). Writer-director Sukumar had thrown a revenge-seeking SP Bhanwar Singh Shekhawat (Fahadh Faasil) on the trail of Pushpa Raj (Allu Arjun) even as the cheeky red sandalwood smuggler was happily taking his wedding vows with the love of his life, Srivalli (Rashmika Mandanna). Five baits have kept the audience agog for the last three years. What will happen to the sizzling chemistry of Pushpa and Srivalli? How will the face-off between strong opponents Pushpa and Bhanwar play out? Will the item number in the sequel match or surpass the saucy raunchiness of Samantha-Allu’s ‘Oo antava’? Will the dances and songs have risque-naughty moves once again?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 09:29:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Q. Why can&amp;rsquo;t Miley Cyrus afford to buy Pushpa?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A. &amp;lsquo;Pushpa flower(s) nahin, fire hain.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This PJ masquerading as a riddle — something which I made up while writing this review — is perhaps as low IQ as it can get. Much like the Pushpa franchise, which thrives on being low IQ, but does one thing pretty much consistently: it serves up, in Silk-speak, what it promises — entertainment, entertainment and more entertainment. Pushpa 2: The Rule, arriving three years after Pushpa: The Rise that became a bona fide pan-India blockbuster and laid the foundation for a big-budget franchise, packs a punch in almost all departments, even going up a notch or two from the first film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:17:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukumar, the writer-director of the Pushpa franchise, is something of a genius when it comes to staging setups and their rewarding payoffs. At certain points in Pushpa 2, you sense how he’s working towards a series of payoffs, some that were set-up in the earlier portions of the first film, which is set 20 years before the events of the sequel. At other points, the payoffs are immediate, giving these scenes an elegant beginning, middle and an end that is so good, they can be developed into standalone short films capable of amassing millions of views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
