<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Captain America Brave New World on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/captain-america-brave-new-world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Captain America Brave New World on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 19:05:27 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/captain-america-brave-new-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Captain America Brave New World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 19:05:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Bruce Banner—The Hulk—is looking for a cure for his unusual rage transformation, he seeks help from maverick scientist Samuel Sterns. Their collaboration faces resistance from General Thaddeus “Thunderbolt” Ross, who is hell-bent on stopping Banner because the giant, angry, green Hulk is dating the general’s daughter, Betty. Ross also wants to harness the gamma tech to his own advantage to create an adequate foil for The Hulk. The resultant creation, dubbed the Abomination, clashes with The Hulk, leading to the destruction of Harlem and a permanent scar on Ross’ reputation. This summary of the 2008 film The Incredible Hulk, which starred Edward Norton as Bruce Banner, Tim Blake Nelson as Samuel Sterns, Liv Tyler as Betty Ross, and William Hurt as General Ross, is crucial to understanding Captain America: Brave New World.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Captain America Brave New World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:34:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Captain America took on a new face back in 2021 with the release of The Falcon And The Winter Solider. Sam Wilson decided not to go through the same treatment as Steve Rogers to become a Super Solider and this is about him and fans doubting his decision. It still feels like a good idea for Wilson to take the serum but he won’t in the coming years to justify the ideology — which the film does on more than one occasion even when the decision feels like a bad idea to our new Cap himself. The film does bring in some familiar faces for cameos which makes the second half worthwhile, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t build up to much. The film’s plot remains wafer thin as the government’s high-level prisoner goes rouge (surprise-surprise) and ends up taking over anyone and everyone he wishes including the President. While the tech may already be a real thing IRL, the film fails to see how a prisoner as big as the one introduced in the film gets away with it without raising any red flags or real alarms. Meanwhile, Sam returns to the MCU as the saviour of USA by going on a mission to retrieve a secret package being sold on the down low. And President Ross is working on trying to get the USA some Adamantium found in the celestial island aka Tiamut&amp;rsquo;s body left behind by the Eternals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
