<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CTRL on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/ctrl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CTRL on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:02:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/ctrl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:02:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Normally, one of the most frustrating things that a movie can do is to abandon its characters and become too consumed by the plot. Our mainstream cinema has always struggled with this, and things have only become worse in the streaming era. It is said that show runners, in particular, can get away with anything on digital platforms as long as there is a murder in the first episode. Well, someone most certainly dies at the end of the first act in CTRL, the new film from Vikramaditya Motwane — his first feature since AK vs AK in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unsettling, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Our most reliable source of information and communication can be programmed to keep tabs on our mind and movement across the multiple devices that have become indispensable crutches of modern living. But then the Internet has always been a seductive, if not secure, space where all its gifts come with its share of dangers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From sharing personal details about oneself on chats with complete strangers, unwittingly downloading software that gives clear passage to malware and bugs, falling prey to sophisticated phishing scams or divulging private data every single time we thoughtlessly tick a Terms and Conditions checkbox, there&amp;rsquo;s a constant element of risk and ruin in romancing the gods of cyberspace. Technology&amp;rsquo;s curse and boon remains the same. It advances but the problem is never in its possibilities as much as the greed of its wielder, which conditions us to believe if you&amp;rsquo;re not in, you&amp;rsquo;re out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:21:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s one significant challenge to making ‘screen-life films’ (films that unfold almost entirely on digital screens). Once you commit to its visual grammar, you’re tied to them till there’s a good reason to break out of it. No matter what, all your exposition needs to happen on the small screen, key plot points need to be hashed out during video calls, and the filmmakers need to keep imagining newer screens – ranging from iPad, mobile phones, CCTVs, GoPros, webcams, paparazzi lenses, TV screens etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:20:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well into CTRL, we know the film&amp;rsquo;s protagonist only as Nella. While it’s certainly an Ananya Panday character name (past ones have been Tia, Tanya, Ahana and Bella), I did wonder if it was given by her Delhi Punjabi parents. But then we hear her father’s voice from offscreen calling: “Nalini”. And a little piece clicked into place: an assumed name, a username, a handle, in a film about unstable online identities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:20:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CZe20LgcQZg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:20:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CTRL lacks control. The new Indian Netflix original movie—directed and co-written by Vikramaditya Motwane—has a lot on its mind. It wishes to tackle the perils of building a business with your partner, the blurred lines between online validation and offline happiness, generational malaise and being severely attached to devices, and the dangers posed by Big Tech, deep fakes and generative AI models. There’s a lot more, some of it frivolous and the rest bordering on spoilers. And that’s exactly the problem—it cannot pick a lane. CTRL tries to pack in so much in its 100-minute runtime that it ends up doing none of it well. Worse, everything it does feels stale. We’ve heard and seen variations of this. Nothing it does shocks or surprises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:20:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मोबाइल, इंटरनेट और सोशल मीडिया आज हमारी जिंदगी का एक बड़ा और अहम हिस्सा बन चुका है। हममें से कई की जिंदगी तो इसी के इर्द-गिर्द घूमती है। उस पर, अब ज्यादा एडवांस तकनीक AI भी दस्तक दे चुका है, जिसके फायदे-नुकसान को लेकर खूब हलचल मची हुई है। लेकिन क्या इन नई और एडवांस तकनीक का इस्तेमाल हम कर रहे हैं या फिर ये तकनीक ही हमारा इस्तेमाल कर रहे हैं? इन्हें हम कंट्रोल कर रहे हैं या हम खुद इनके कंट्रोल में हैं? इसी चिंताजनक सवालों के जवाब ढूंढने की कोशिश करती है, डायरेक्टर विक्रमादित्य मोटवानी की फिल्म CTRL यानी कंट्रोल। सोशल मीडिया या पब्लिक ऐप किस तरह लोगों के प्राइवेट डेटा इकट्ठा करते हैं, उनका गलत इस्तेमाल करते हैं, फिल्म हमें यह बात याद दिलाती है और उसके प्रति सचेत करती है।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:20:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I6B78NkSPNo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:17:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bJ1mtN8OO8I?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:45:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conjuring up a life that plays out in a virtual space - in other words, setting up a gauzy existence that floats in a dimension far removed from the real and the tangible - has its wages. Vikramaditya Motwane&amp;rsquo;s inventive, sparky CTRL examines the nature and extent of the toll that burrowing into a rabbit hole of constructed personas and enhanced engagements can extract.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nella Awasthi (Ananya Panday, suitably sprightly), a Delhi girl who has been in Mumbai for six years, discovers the hard way that there is infinitely more to life than reels, brands, subscribers and likes. Not that the film is looking to preach to a flock. Who does not already know what is at stake in a digital life?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:39:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A cautionary tale on cybercrime and artificial intelligence, CTRL works like a ready reckoning on online behaviour for social media junkies and feels like it has been designed to showcase the budding talent of Ananya Panday. Many of us have yet to recover from the shenanigans of Bae when director Vikramaditya Motwane unleashes the effervescence of Ananya in yet another variant of the coming-of-age template for Gen-Z.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Starting with Kho Gaye Hum Kahan, it seems Ananya has cracked the code of playing airheaded characters judged on Instagram. They demand such low expectations from the audience that when they gather a few more grams of gravity and the screenplay develops a few ounces of nuance, it feels like she has made such a long journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:35:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Ctrl, a cautionary tale about the world’s obsession and our near-total dependence on online apps, Vikramaditya Motwane has moved firmly into the future. Or is it the present? Isn’t this what the geeks have been creating with their gaming universes, where your digital avatars are the better, shinier versions of you? Where they slay all the monsters, and leave you — or rather, your avatar — fully in control?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:31:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Aneesh Chaganty’s Searching put the life in screenlife. It marked the natural progression of ‘screenlife storytelling’ — a visual format where events happen entirely on computer screens, smartphones and cameras — into the real world. Until then, the horrors of technology had been literalised by the found-footage and supernatural genres. But Searching featured a father who looks for his missing daughter by following her digital footprints. His internet sleuthing reveals how little he really knew her; the technology he uses to find her is what had isolated her to begin with. Vikramaditya Motwane’s CTRL goes a step further; it expands the plausibility of the genre by unfolding in an age that puts the screen in screenlife. CTRL marks its progression into the reality of a virtual world — one where being watched is simply a natural consequence of feeling seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
