<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Missing You on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/missing-you/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Missing You on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:01:37 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/missing-you/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Missing You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/missing-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 09:01:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/missing-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Her father died nearly 11 years ago. About the same time, her fiance disappeared from her life and it seems from the face of the earth. And she is no ordinary woman but the dogged Detective Inspector Kat Donovan. Could the plot get thicker? Yes it does, often too thick. Indeed, the story unfolds with much intrigue if not cutting-edge tension. Kat, played by Rosalind Eleazar, is in charge of tracing missing persons. Why she has not cared to find out where her boyfriend vanished is as baffling as his sudden popping up on a dating site. Instead, she seeks the help of her friend, private investigator Stacey Embalo (Jessica Plummer), to track him down, actually do half her jobs, including finding her way into a prison hospital. Stacey’s job otherwise is to nail cheating husbands and wives. Amidst fishing in the woes of failing marriages, she plays agony aunt to Kat and directs her to a dating app.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missing You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/missing-you-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 01:24:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/missing-you-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2018, Netflix has been adapting author Harlan Coben&amp;rsquo;s catalog in the form of limited series. These have been gaining popularity over the years, and last year&amp;rsquo;s Fool Me Once with Michelle Keegan broke several records. The newest release, Missing You, revolves around a missing persons detective, Kat Donovan, and a myriad of secrets around her past. Over five episodes, these secrets emerge one by one. Detective Kat Donovan (Rosalind Eleazar), who is already investigating a series of missing people, connects with her former fiancé Josh (Ashley Walters) on a dating app. Josh ghosted her 11 years ago and is apparently living under a new name. Strangely, there is a connection to the missing woman she is currently investigating. Meanwhile, there is also the matter of Kat&amp;rsquo;s dad, a police officer who is murdered by a hitman. Eventually, Kat has to figure out what in her past and present is real and what is being kept from her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
