<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Woman of the Hour on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/woman-of-the-hour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Woman of the Hour on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:27:43 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/woman-of-the-hour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Woman of the Hour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/woman-of-the-hour-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:27:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/woman-of-the-hour-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the wiser thing to do is to scale down. Not every film needs to be a sweeping epic, especially not one that demands a tight telling. Directed by the debutante Anna Kendrick, the darkly humorous thriller Woman of the Hour is based on an intriguing real-life story, but suffers from an under-confident execution. The movie would’ve worked wonderfully as a claustrophobic chamber piece, but feels compelled to jump across timelines and juggle between characters with an haphazardness that only does it harm. Kendrick is like an overeager Indian mum, checking the pressure cooker more often than she needs to, thereby releasing all the steam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman of the Hour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/woman-of-the-hour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:23:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/woman-of-the-hour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The saying &amp;rsquo;truth is stranger than fiction&amp;rsquo; hits harder in films adapted from true-crime stories. The drama feature, Woman of the Hour, tells the unbelievable story of a serial killer who somehow ended up on a dating show as an eligible bachelor in the late 1970s. The shocking story is told by actress Anna Kendrick in her promising directorial debut that is sure to leave an impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The film is set in 1977-1978, following the serial killer Rodney Alcala (Daniel Zovatto), who stalked and murdered women on the pretext of photographing them all over the US. When he lands on a dating show, Rodney ends up being the only bachelor on the panel of three that aspiring actress Sheryl Bradshaw (Kendrick) unfortunately connects with. Woman of the Hour unnervingly shows how few people picked up on Rodney&amp;rsquo;s creepy vibe and suspected something was amiss. And how it took a while before &amp;lsquo;The Dating Game Killer&amp;rsquo; was eventually brought to justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
