<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shubhra Gupta on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/shubhra-gupta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shubhra Gupta on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:26:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/shubhra-gupta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sikandar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:26:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The challenge is real. In almost every frame and sequence of this Eid release, Salman Khan aka Sanjay, the Raja of Rajkot, aka Sikandar, struggles to be present. You can see him go through the motions of emotion and action, delivering dialogue, dancing, romancing, shedding tears –yes, he’s man enough to cry– but nowhere do you see traces of the one and only Bhai, who has never pretended to be anything other than who he has been in the last thirty years– the star with his very specific style-and-swag– the blue bracelet and the bulked-up arms-and-torso akimbo adorning his favourite avatars of the loveable rascal-cum-the desi Robin Hood with the golden heart.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khakee: The Bengal Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/khakee-the-bengal-chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:57:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/khakee-the-bengal-chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the catchy title song going, ‘ek aur rang bhi dekhiye Bengal ka’, we are hopeful that this new Neeraj Pandey series, Khakee The Bengal Chapter, set in Calcutta/Kolkata, will actually be different. The eight-part show starts with a kidnapping gone wrong, and then the story begins unpacking its wares in right earnest: sloppy goons, sharp cops, a posse of politicians with murky underground connections, nefarious activities involving dead bodies and organ harvesting. A promising start quickly descends into predictability. The beats are familiar, the character types are even more so. Apart from the fact that the faces are mostly Bengali actors — some familiar, some not so — Khakee The Bengal Chapter comes off as same old. And that’s too bad, because the ensemble comprises some of the most popular actors working in Bengali, starting with top stars Prosenjit Chatterjee, Parambrata Chattopadhyay, and Jeet, amongst others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Happy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/be-happy-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 19:35:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/be-happy-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ooty-based schoolgirl Dhara (Inayat Verma) is happiest when dancing. Single parent Shiv (Abhishek Bachchan) loves her to bits, but is not mad about her wanting to go off to Mumbai to focus on her moves, even when well-known dancer-teacher (Nora Fatehi) dangles an inducement to attend her sought-after academy. Things start falling into place, and then one day, trouble strikes. Can sheer will and determination win the day? Can dreams really come true?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Diplomat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 08:56:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on a true story, The Diplomat is about an Indian woman lured into a false marriage with a Pakistani man, and how her life spirals into a nightmare. The backdrop of terrorism-and-espionage is, by now, very much a John Abraham zone, and here he plays JP Singh, the diplomat who moves from suspicion-to-support when the terrified Uzma Ahmed (Sadia Khateeb) seeks refuge within the Indian embassy in Islamabad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dupahiya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dupahiya-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 09:10:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dupahiya-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A stolen motorcycle– ‘dupahiya’– in the fictional village of Dhadakpur becomes the fulcrum around which this new comedy and its characters revolve, delivering a melange of Bihari-via-Mumbai accents, loads of quirk and broad life lessons. This is the mix that gave ‘Panchayat’ its mojo, with Phulera’s Sachivji and Pradhanji and their cohorts becoming a byword in the madly-popular OTT-specific ruralcom genre. Here, Uttar Pradesh is replaced by Bihar, but the mood remains similarly overall sunny, as the occasional clouds created by the busy plot (written by Avinash Dwivedi and Chirag Garg) are dispelled by the show’s determinedly cheerful air: leave the viewer smiling is clearly the mandate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 09:06:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take the Dharma template because, duh, this is a Dharma film, borrow deets from a bunch of romcoms, shake ’em up, and you get Nadaaniyan. There’s the swish high-school from ‘Kuch Kuch Hota Hai’, which lead character Pia Jaisingh (Khushi Kapoor) helpfully describes as having ‘no-uniform, resort-type vibes’, just in case we miss it. Ms Braganza (Archana Puran Singh, reprising her role, older but not wiser) is back. No student ever seems to go to class: that’s not changed, either. And those who’ve been missing that shooting star, so cute, ya, fear not: it gets a look-see, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suzhal: The Vortex S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/suzhal-the-vortex-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 09:22:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/suzhal-the-vortex-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A small town in South India. A religious festival drumming up nightly fervour. A crime most foul. Red herrings. Confused cops. These elements which made the first season of ‘Suzhal: The Vortex’ such a gripping watch are back in Season 2, except the town is different, and the crime, this time around, is revealed from the get-go: a local lawyer is found dead. Was it suicide, or murder? Two of the lead actors are back, too. Kathir as the cop Sakkarai, is under a professional cloud for something he did in the previous season, and Aishwarya Rajesh as Nandhini, the young woman who slayed her demon in its satisfactory climax, is awaiting trial. Sakkarai has strong filial ties with slain lawyer Chellappa (Lal), and as he delves deeper, past secrets rise to the surface, and everyone connected to the victim comes under the scanner.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazxy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crazxy-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 09:19:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crazxy-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crazxy movie review: The stuck-behind-a-steering-wheel/closed-phone-booth character, hellbent on saving a loved one from dire consequences, has been used in a few films. In ‘Crazxy’, Sohum Shah plays a surgeon, on track for a crucial meeting, poleaxed by a phone call which changes everything: he needs to rapidly regroup and think on his feet, to prevent calamity befalling a member of his family. At 93 minutes, the film is fashioned as an edge-of-the-seat thriller, and Shah’s Dr Abhimanyu Sood does his best to put metal-to-pedal, while fielding calls from a bunch of increasingly agitated people: ex-wife (voiced by Nimisha Sajayan), current interest (voiced by Shilpa Shukla), boss of his hospital (voiced by Piyush Mishra), and a senior teacher (voiced by Tinnu Anand) at his daughter Vedika’s (Unnati Surana, on screen briefly) school, who is empathetic to her special needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dabba Cartel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dabba-cartel-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 09:13:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dabba-cartel-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dabba Cartel review: A group of Thane-based women come together to fend off multiple elements that are stopping them from being themselves. Sweet housewife Raji (Shalini Pandey), her dour mother-in-law Sheila (Shabana Azmi), mouthy domestic worker Mala (Nimisha Sajayan), unhappy wife-cum-entrepreneur Varuna (Jyotika), smart real-estate agent Shahida (Anjali Anand), all very different from each other, find common cause through an unlikely enterprise: the modest business of daily dabbas with ‘ghar-ka-khana’ laced with a little kick, turns into a ride whose rising profit comes with thrills and danger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 09:26:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Superboys of Malegaon is inspired by Faiza Ahmad Khan’s terrific 2008 documentary ‘Supermen of Malegaon’, on a subset of residents of Malegaon who had become famous for turning their home-grown spoofs of Bollywood blockbusters into a profitable cottage industry. The filmmakers give credit to the original at the end of their film, which in essence, is a feature film with many elements borrowed from the documentary, which in turn was based on the remarkable enterprise on display in a small Maharashtra town afflicted by communal tensions and poverty, and about the power of dreaming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reacher S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/reacher-s03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:34:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/reacher-s03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reacher is many things. Ex-US Army. Tall. Large. Loner. Drifter. But he’s no grifter: he means what he says, even if sometimes he comes off as pedantic. But when he tells wealthy rug merchant Zachary Beck (Anthony Michael Hall) that wherever he, Reacher, goes, trouble seems to find him, he is just stating facts. In a sedate university town of Maine, trouble once again finds our favourite former military cop, and Season 3 of the eight-part show called, simply, and aptly, ‘Reacher’, is off and away. This one is based on Lee Child’s seventh bestseller ‘Persuader’, developed for TV by Nick Santora, and written by Scott Sullivan. Good cops, bad guys, shoot-outs, car crashes, sudden kills, the staple elements of the best-selling author’s page-turners, all show up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mere Husband Ki Biwi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mere-husband-ki-biwi-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 09:30:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mere-husband-ki-biwi-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The film has a catchy title. You go in with a bit of hope, given that director Mudassar Aziz’s previous ‘Khel Khel Mein’ had a few nice moments, but that one was a remake. Here it has been written by the director, and you encounter, over two-and-a-half hours, tropes, flat scenes, and characters who come and go. Which is a pity because the lead characters appear to have taken their jobs seriously. It is no surprise that the two ladies playing romantic rivals, Bhumi Pednekar as Prabhleen Dhillon, and Rakul Preeti Singh as Antara Khanna, make you look. Plus, and this is a surprise, Arjun Kapoor as Ankur Chaddha isn’t half bad as the hapless guy stuck between the two loves of his life. They just needed a better film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chhaava</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 14:47:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 161 minutes of Chhaava, based on the high-points of the life of Sambhaji Maharaj, the son of Shivaji Maharaj, you are left with two chief thoughts. How do you pull off a film which talks up a historical figure not as well known as his illustrious parent, without us wondering: how much is fact, and how much fiction? And the other, which is the reason you manage to sit through this ultra-loud, ultra-violent re-creation of a slice of the 17th century Hindustan is the total commitment on display by its lead actor to the titular character: Vicky Kaushal becomes Chhaava (‘son of a lion’), whose story the film adapts from the Marathi novel of the same name by Shivaji Sawant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhoom Dhaam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 09:37:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you married ‘Iss Raat Ki Subah Nahin’ with a zillion iterations of the odd-couple and lovers-on-the-run and heist movies, you would get Dhoom Dhaam, a film which borrows from all these elements, while straining every nerve to be novel. The trouble with skimming tropes is that your film, even with a fresh pairing, and despite a few flourishes, ends up more or less trope-y.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loveyapa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/loveyapa-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 21:29:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/loveyapa-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To make a modern rom-com remains the bane of Bollywood: Loveyapa proves all over again just how difficult it is to create a cracking love story which truly captures the essence of today’s swipe-right-and-left generation. The real film kicks in well into the second half, much after the listless toing-and-froing of the pre-interval portion between the two leads who cutely call each other Baani Boo, and Baboo. Ooo. You think you love each other? Ok, exchange your phones for a day, and see where you go with it, declares Baani’s stern shuddh-Hindi spouting daddyji (Ashustosh Rana). Consternation on faces, and dread in hearts, Baani Sharma and Gaurav ‘Gucci’ Sachdeva hand over their phones to each other, and thus begins loveyapa, love plus ‘siyapa’, that untranslatable Punjabi word whose closest meaning is trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:59:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The distance between these two contradictory statements — the smell (khushboo) of the kitchen is sexy, and, you smell (baas) of the kitchen, do you expect me to be turned on — is measured by, who else, a man. The man who has deposited the woman he has married and brought to his home, where he lives with his parents, in the kitchen. Where she is expected to be an uncomplaining slave to everyone’s time and moods: the doctor husband who runs a clinic while constantly complaining of overwork, expecting his wife to serve ‘garam phulkas’ when he sits down to eat, the father-in-law wanting his slippers placed just so for him to slide his feet into, the mother-in-law using the sil-batta to grind the chutney, because the mixer-grinder is not loving enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mehta Boys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-mehta-boys-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:11:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-mehta-boys-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The spiky relationship between a father-and-son, which shapes the narrative in ‘The Mehta Boys’, leads us to predict a resolution in which things will get better. The theme has that familiar predictive tilt built into it, but what lifts ‘The Mehta Boys’ are the little spurts of unpredictability built into the script of Boman Irani’s directorial debut. That, and the performances, which are all pitch perfect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bada Naam Karenge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bada-naam-karenge-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:04:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bada-naam-karenge-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watching this nine-part show, run by Sooraj R Barjatya, the Rajshri scion who got back maryada and sanskriti back into Hindi cinema in the mid-90s, is a conflicting business. It makes you wonder at the time and place we live in: have we moved forward at all from the 1994 Hum Aapke Hain Koun!, in which it was perfectly acceptable to offer a freshly-widowed bhai’s hand to his sister-in-law, and where the big temple-going joint family is kind-but-dismissive to its minority characters?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Storyteller</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-storyteller-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 08:18:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-storyteller-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Satyajit Ray short story becomes the basis of ‘The Storyteller’, an unhurried unspooling of an unlikely relationship between two men, separated by geographies, backgrounds, and, most crucially, intent. The result is a film which takes its time to lay out its wares, demanding your patience, which does get a trifle stretched, but overall rewards you for it. Tarini Bandhopadhyaya (Paresh Rawal) is a 60-something Bengali gent who loves fish and hates capitalism with equal passion. Ratan Garodia (Adil Hussain) is a Gujarati businessman who has everything except the comfort of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 08:14:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bunch of cops in Mumbai track down the killer of a fellow officer, opening up several cans of worms. That, more or less, was the thrust of the Roshhan Andrrews-directed Mumbai Police (2013), headlined by Prithviraj Sukumaran. Another bunch of cops in Mumbai do the same, broadly, in the 2025 ‘Deva’, also by the same director. From what I remember of the original, there seem to be several scenes which are exact replicas, but for some strange reason, the filmmakers have taken great pains to prevent themselves, as well as anyone else, dubbing the Shahid Kapoor starrer a remake.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabar Bonda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sabar-bonda-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 01:32:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sabar-bonda-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Sabar Bonda’ is the story of two young men, finding their way back to each other. It is also a story of grief and acceptance, told with warmth and piercing sensitivity. Anand (Bhushaan Manoj) accompanies his mother to their ancestral Maharashtrian village from Mumbai, for the ten-day mourning period after the death of his father. He is back after a sizable gap, but the reason for his staying away starts up again: ‘potential brides from good homes’ are back on the table, and Anand finds himself struggling, like he did before, for a way to tell his relatives that he’s gay. ‘Sabar Bonda’ has a couple of firsts to its credit. It is self-taught filmmaker Rohan Parashuram Kanawade’s debut feature, and the first Marathi film chosen to screen at the Sundance Film Festival, whose 41st edition is currently underway.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:25:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year Bollywood’s Republic-Day gift was Fighter, which zoomed in, checking several patriotic-movie boxes: brave Indian fighter pilots, going up against favourite enemy Pakistan, displaying valour and camaraderie. This year, it is Sky Force, coasting on the same elements, except this one is a thinly-disguised account of a real life incident during the 1965 Indo-Pak conflict, in which a squadron decimated a fleet of modern American jets housed at Pakistani base Sargodha, in an operation the film calls Sky Force.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hisaab Barabar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/hisaab-barabar-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:20:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/hisaab-barabar-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An honest-to-a-fault, maths-whizz ticket collector gets embroiled, unwittingly, in the doings of a greedy banker: this one-line premise may have sounded exciting on paper, but the execution comes off contrived and clunky. Madhavan plays Radhe Mohan Sharma, who brings his affable self and a razor sharp brain to his job, whose first encounter with a comely cop (Kirti Kulhari) isn’t exactly a meet-cute. She rebuffs his offer of an orange bought from a fruit-seller at the station: ‘main chori kiye santare nahin khati’, she says.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Roshans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-roshans-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:57:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-roshans-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the chief things that emerges from this four-part mini-series on the Roshans, is that, despite being part of so many memorable films via music, direction, production and performance, their contribution to Hindi cinema was not celebrated enough. Part of the pleasure of watching this kind of show is the straight-up access: apart from the Roshans themselves — Rajesh, Rakesh, Hrithik and close family — everyone from Shatrughan Sinha, Shah Rukh Khan, Sanjay Leela Bhansali, Karan Johar, the Akhtars, Javed, Farhan and Zoya, Abhishek Bachchan, singers Asha Bhosle, Suman Kalyanpuri, Sudha Malhotra, Usha Mangeshkar, Kumar Sanu, Sonu Nigam, and several others are all here, speaking about their relationship, professional and personal, with the Roshans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:50:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The much-delayed, riding-on-controversies ‘Emergency’, written and directed by Kangana Ranaut, is finally out. The long disclaimer states that the biographical feature ‘draws information from the life and real life events of one of the most respected politicians and former prime ministers, Smt Indira Gandhi’. And then it follows up the standard caveat of ‘creative liberties’ having been taken in the dramatisation, with a most un-standard sentence: ‘the filmmakers fully acknowledge and respect other perspectives and viewpoints’. This unexpected dissonant note pretty much sets the tone of this film in which Ranaut has played the role of Indira Gandhi, which swings from showing her as a young woman growing into an autocratic leader, to a weak, vacillating mother under the influence of Sanjay, her ‘bigda hua beta’, and back again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paatal Lok S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:21:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Hathi Ram Chaudhary says in his world-weary manner, ‘hum toh paatal lok ke permanent niwasi hain’, he’s not just addressing a character in the series. He’s plunging us into the nether-world again, and we dive right in, willingly. The first season of Paatal Lok (2020), directed by Avinash Arun and created by Sudip Sharma, quickly become a benchmark, in the way it lifted a familiar world — weatherbeaten-but-idealistic cops pulled into cases of murder and corruption in high places — by singular story-telling, and characters that stayed with us. I’ve sorely missed my favourite cop, entire lifetimes imprinted in the craggy lines of his face, in the interim. Welcome back, Chaudhary sir.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azaad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:36:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/azaad-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The deep bonds between a horse and their human have been at the centre of many wonderful films. Azaad, which has two men, senior and junior, vying for the affections of a beautiful beast, should have been double the fun. But this one, which launches Ajay Devgn’s nephew Aaman and Raveena Tandon’s daughter Rasha, turns out to be so dated that it appears to have been made in a time lag. First off, the setting has been lifted from ‘Lagaan’– cruel zamindars helping pompous Englishmen lord over cowed villagers — with the addition of a few floggings, and loud proclamations of banishing the villagers to ‘Africa’ as bonded labour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Warrant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:26:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Black Warrant’ is a seven-part series based on a book of the same name about an insider’s account of his time at what has been dubbed ‘the biggest prison in Asia’, Tihar Jail. The volume is co-authored by Sunil Kumar Gupta, who joined Tihar in the early 80s, and journalist Sunetra Chowdhary; the show, directed by Vikramaditya Motwane, cherry picks some of the most sensational cases that unspooled during Gupta’s watch, as he grew from a wet-behind-the-ears rookie to an experienced jailer, without losing his humanity. Gupta, credited with starting Tihar’s first legal aid cell for poor, illiterate under-trials, is played by Zahan Kapoor. The actor, who debuted in Hansal Mehta’s 2022 terrorist drama ‘Faraz’, is given enough time here to grow into his role. Within a few minutes of the opening, his slight frame and smiling, soft ways — unlike his colleagues, he doesn’t cuss a mile a minute, nor does he use brute force on the inmates — are underlined more than a few times, and it’s quickly apparent why. His character, who doesn’t quite fit the job description — maintaining order in a rough-tough jail — is a familiar device used to impart chunks of information. And it is to Kapoor’s credit that he becomes more than just that device which is pressed into service through the series; he inhabits his character with conviction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fateh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/fateh-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:40:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/fateh-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cyber crime is in the crosshairs of Sonu Sood’s ‘Fateh’, in which he plays an In and As role: the name of the film is his, which means victory. So how much of a win is the 127-minute film, the actor’s debut directorial? Sood has mostly played strong supporting roles up until now; this one has him as hero, front and centre. That’s one thing checked off from any actor’s wish-list: solo hero in an action movie, the guy with the gun, leading from the front.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parama: A Journey With Aparna Sen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/parama-a-journey-with-aparna-sen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 23:35:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/parama-a-journey-with-aparna-sen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parama : A Journey With Aparna Sen is a lively portrait of an artiste, with conversations that the director conducts with his subject, and her subjects. It begins, aptly, with a sequence from Sen’s first directorial, ‘36, Chowringhee Lane’, a 1981 film that brings alive a slice of Calcutta long since vanished. Violet Stoneham, played unforgettably by Jennifer Kendal, is an Anglo-Indian-school teacher-spinster who lives alone. An accidental meeting with a former student and her boyfriend injects warmth and colour into her drab life, but the change is sadly short-lived. Ghosh and his team take Sen to the building — the kind in which the lifts didn’t work, the bare tangle of electricity wires hanging dangerously low over the staircase — in which the film was shot, and we hear her reminisce about how one of her best films, and one whose portrayal of loneliness still aches, came together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/doctors-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:43:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/doctors-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India’s answer to ER/Grey’s Anatomy is here: Doctors, which is as straight-forward a title as you can get, is about just that, a bunch of medics, ranging from eager new residents to rockstar surgeons, as well as other denizens– nurses, interns, administrators– who make up a busy hospital. It takes a couple of episodes for the 10-part show to get into the groove, which gives us an insider’s look at medical practitioners going all out in high-stress emergencies, as well as dealing with those who are struggling with terminal diseases. These are humans who are also doctors. We see them as people, with their strengths and weaknesses, but who do not compromise when it comes to saving the lives of their patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 08:51:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a late stage in the film, Rajpal Yadav’s character, who plays a side-kick to the hero, gets the best line of Baby John: comedy is serious business. It was about the only time I heard a ripple of laughter in the preview theatre. It is the kind of punchline that masala movies use to bring the house down. And it says a great deal about Baby John, which weighs in at a punishing 164 minutes, that a comic’s dialogue gets more taalis than the hero’s ‘taqia kalaam’ line: ‘par main toh pehli baar aaya hoon’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 09:10:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an unspecified North Indian hilltown boarding school, a girl comes of age. That overused phrase ‘coming-of-age’ is a misnomer when it comes to mainstream Hindi cinema: the years between thirteen and eighteen are those where contradictory impulses leap between synapses, with mind and body taking off in opposite directions, and explorations of both taking you into spaces where you’ve never been before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are elements Bollywood has never been comfortable with. Even if films do get made around this subject, their teenagers are either carefully sanitized or overtly fetishised. The result: infantilised characters and viewers, who’ve never been given a chance to grow up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:56:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first season of ‘Yeh Kaali Kaali Aankhein’ became an addictive watch in the way it bent one of the oldest genres in the book: being an obsessive lover is not just a male prerogative; women can do it just as well, if not better. It made up for all its nods to hoary Hindi movie heavies who lived in palaces overrun by armed goons, governed by old-style off-with-their-heads villainy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:53:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hindi movies have played with fire several times before. Those with long memories will remember such films as the 1980 adventure ‘The Burning Train’, which may have picked up inspiration from an earlier Hollywood blockbuster ‘The Towering Inferno’, but those who fight the flames at the risk of their own lives, have never been in the limelight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is something that Rahul Dholakia’s ‘Agni’ seeks to correct. The film loses no time in placing its bets with the chief of a Mumbai fire station, Vithalrao Surve (Gandhi), who leads his band of braves from the front, as they go about dousing fires in congested buildings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandish Bandits S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:51:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The face-off between tradition and modernity, past and present, the strict rules of gharana-and-parampara vs doing-your-own-thing, which were the key notes of the first season of ‘Bandish Bandits’, are back again in the second. As are many of the actors, reprising their roles, along with new faces, as the story takes off from where it left off, back in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four years is quite a gap between the two seasons, but it is reassuring to see that the show, directed by Tiwari, who has a co-writing credit with Atmika Didwania and Karan Singh Tyagi, has kept its focus on music and musicians, even as it has added new strands in the plot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despatch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:48:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crime reporter Joy Bag (Manoj Bajpayee) is not the kind of journalist we see too often in Hindi movies. His favourite accompaniment is his rucksack, as he goes about criss-crossing the city on his bike, in search of the latest story. He’s been doing this for a while, because he talks to his seniors like an equal, but at heart he will always remain a scrappy newshound who likes nothing better than chatting up shadowy contacts over cups of cheap cutting chai, which he prefers to the pizza his wife serves at unwelcome parties at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sikandar Ka Muqaddar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-ka-muqaddar-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:48:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-ka-muqaddar-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A large jewellery exhibition in Mumbai becomes the site of a heist. A hysterical phone call raises alarm, gunfire is heard, the cops on duty herd the panicked gathering into a secluded area, and during the melee, a fistful of precious gems go missing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All We Imagine as Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:15:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A woman leans on a pole in her compartment, for support, for balance, swaying with the rhythm of the train. She looks exhausted, after a long day at work. We take in, like she does, the way the city looks at night, bars of refracted light and darkness dancing across her face. This image, which comes early in Payal Kapadia’s lyrical ode to working-class Mumbai and female friendship, becomes a marker of the themes the film explores, and it stays with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waack Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/waack-girls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 09:14:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/waack-girls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An underdog dance group making something of itself: right from the opening frame of Waack Girls, you know that this will be the trajectory of this rag-tag bunch, based in Kolkata. But this Sooni Taraporevala-created-and-directed nine part series attempts to build in differentials. First off, Kolkata is still not a city you’d think of when it comes to street style dancing and underground meetings where dance-offs occur. A lovely Cal feeling is captured in a crumbling old mansion, in a tony club, in the corner puchka-wala, and in the accents people use. You do see some familiar structures on the skyline, like the Howrah Bridge, but they are just there, no emphasis laid. That is refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Want to Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 08:57:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Going into ‘I Want To Talk’, I had no idea that that the character Abhishek Bachchan plays is based on an actual person called Arjun Sen. That knowledge would have added a certain layer to the story of a man who bests certain death- a diagnosis of laryngeal cancer and the consequent grim prognosis of a limited future—and is still around on planet earth. A valid question arises, after you’re done: anyone surviving 19-20 tough surgeries, and finding the energy to bring up a daughter, and run a marathon, is worthy of respect, but is that enough to engage us for two hours? Director Shoojit Sircar has an affinity for characters dealing with life-and-death situations, set in the innards of hospitals (October), as well as exploring filial connections (Piku). Both themes are here, but the depth and emotion which elevate his plots surface only occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom at Midnight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:20:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The choice of using ‘Freedom At Midnight’, Larry Collins and Dominique Lapierre’s account of the tumultuous build-up to India’s independence in August 1947, as the basis for the seven-part web series of the same name achieves one thing above all else: adapting from source material which has been in existence for several years, especially from the celebrity author duo who couldn’t be accused of being either pro-India, or pro-Pakistan, frees creator and director Nikkhil Advani of being accused similar bias.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sabarmati Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-sabarmati-report-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 09:17:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-sabarmati-report-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 27, 2002, several coaches of the Sabarmati Express at Godhra station caught fire, causing the deaths of 59 people, many of them women and children. The train from Ayodhya, bound for Ahmedabad, was full of ‘karsevaks’ returning after a ceremony held under the aegis of the Vishwa Hindu Parishad (VHP). Flames could be seen in four coaches, according to reports, but the worst hit was Coach 6, where the deaths took place. The horrific incident was followed by three days of rioting in Gujarat: according to several accounts, the number of the dead was well over 2000. The Nanavati-Mehta commission, appointed by the state government, concluded that the fire was the result of a pre-planned arson by a large Muslim mob; the one-member Banerjee commission instituted in 2004 by the government at the Centre declared that it was an accident.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vijay 69</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vijay-69-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:21:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vijay-69-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On paper, ‘Vijay 69’ must have felt like a splendid idea. Old men dodder. They don’t go about being potty-mouthed, or making sad sex jokes. How about getting Vijay Mathew, a ripe 69, to have a vocabulary which is more foul than fair, even if he has reached grandfather status? Next, how about setting him an impossible task? Even the fittest baulk at attempting the triathlon. Why not get our elderly hero to have a dash at it? Vijay lives in a house surrounded by the memories of his dead wife, the only one who used to encourage him in his endeavours, the chief of which seems to be getting ranked in a swimming race. Everyone else, including his dearest friend Fali (Chunky Panday donning a grey wig and the broadest Parsi accent that can be mustered), thinks he’s gone bananas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel: Honey Bunny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 13:43:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First things first: all hail the arrival of Samantha Ruth Prabhu, Indian cinema’s first real female action star who demands our attention from the get-go and never loses it through the six part series, Citadel: Honey Bunny. She’s coiled, ready for action, exploding off the screen whenever the script demands it of her, and the demand stays consistently high. As the family woman-cum-spry spy, who will do anything to protect her daughter, Samantha’s Honey is the best part of this enterprise, directed and written by Raj and DK (Sita Menon also gets writing and directing credit), and executive produced by the Russo Bros.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:20:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All right folks, we are back in the labyrinth. For a third time. Lots of stuff that we remember from the earlier outings. Creaky two-hundred-year-old Bengali havelis. Locked rooms. Vengeful ‘aatmas’. Ghosts who flit about. And characters who spout their lines, and vanish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So. Kartik Aaryan is Rooh Baba, a bogus ghostbuster. Accompanied always by the vertically challenged Tilu (Arun Kushwah). Grabbed by the very modern miss Meera (Tripti Dimri) and her uncle (Rajesh Sharma). Transported to said haveli, in order to bust the ghost of Monjulika. Remember her?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:18:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They say that the fount of all Indian fiction are the two epics, Ramayan and Mahabharat. Rohit Shetty seems to have taken this old saying to heart because Ajay Devgn’s eponymous Bajirao Singham is none other than a latter-day Maryada Purushottam Ram, his wife Avni (Kareena Kapoor Khan) is the faithful Sita, and all the other characters play their parallels in this version of Kalyug-ke-Ram Ki Katha. The result is loud and tedious, and instantly forgettable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mithya: The Darker Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-darker-chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 09:21:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-darker-chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was enough intrigue in the first season of ‘Mithya’, in which a troubled author is left on the edge of a sharp wedge, for us to want to return for another round. However, the new season, which comes from the same production house (Applause Entertainment) but a different director (Kapil Sharma) is everything that the first wasn’t: contrived, unconvincing, and, the worst sin, dull.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Do Patti’ comes armed with much promise. It is the first offering of a brand new female-led production house, with producer-actor Kriti and writer Kanika Dhillon having created an interesting ensemble led by Kajol, popular TV actor Shaheer Sheikh, Tanvi Azmi, Brijendra Kala and Vivek Mushran. What’s not to like? Turns out, quite a lot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The film begins busily. An adventure in the skies, high up in the mountains, turns into a near-disaster. A shaken wife points a finger at her husband, accusing him of lethal designs. Local cop Vidya Jyoti aka VJ (Kajol) begins investigating. Is Saumya (Kriti Sanon), hiding facial bruises, correct in feeling that Dhruv (Shaheer Sheikh) has placed her life in danger? Why would Dhruv, the scion of a businessman intent upon growing his base, who asked for her hand after a sweet courtship, do such a thing? Is he as nice as he appears to be, or is he a monster? What is Saumya’s highly competitive identical twin Shailee (Kriti Sanon again, in a double role) hiding? Does the elderly woman (Tanvi Azmi) who has been part of the twins’ rocky childhood, know something?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandaa Singh Chaudhary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandaa-singh-chaudhary-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 09:25:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandaa-singh-chaudhary-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on a real-life character of the same name, Bandaa Singh Chaudhary tells the tale of a man who stood his ground and fought against tremendous odds during the 1980s in Punjab, when militancy was rising rapidly, propelling a clutch of separatist movements. With Arshad Warsi playing the eponymous Banda, and Meher Vij as his spirited wife Lalli, this film had the potential to deliver a strong character study set during one of the most turbulent periods of recent Indian history. But nothing does the subject any justice, neither the story-telling nor the performances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zindaginama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/zindaginama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:16:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/zindaginama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zindaginama tackles a set of mental health issues through six episodes, targeting a different one each time. What happens when a human begins believing in an alt reality? Purple Duniya’s protagonist, a terrific Tanmay Dhanania, sets out ostensibly to go to work, like regular folks do. But that’s all a sham. His total focus lies in the game he plays obsessively, constantly, forgetting to eat or drink. Or communicate with his sister. Therapy can help, but to what extent? And who wins finally, man or machine? Sahaan Hattangadi writes, and co-directs with Danny Mamik.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vicky Vidya Ka Woh Wala Video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 09:34:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s 1997, an era when home entertainment equalled recording all kinds of stuff– beach vacays, birthdays, and ahem, X-rated activities– on handheld video cameras, and playing them back on personal VHS machines. On their ‘shaadi ki first-night’, nudge-wink, Vicky (Rao) and Vidya (Dimri) record their ‘voh wala video’, the loss of which propels the film into motion. Given the director’s track record with his Ayushmann Khurrana-led ‘Dream Girl’ films, in which he mixed soft-core raunch with family drama with a degree of success, it would have been foolish to expect anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 09:28:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early on in the 1 hour 55 minutes film, a character asks Satya, ‘Toh kya Bachchan bananna hai?’ The question is meant as both set-up and punch-line. Her reply, ‘Ab toh Bachchan hi bananna hai’, sets us up for the entire premise-cum-gist-raison d’etre of ‘Jigra’, in which Alia Bhatt’s Satya attempts to become a Bachchanesque hero, kicking and punching, hurt and hurting, falling down and getting up. And staying up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:35:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Ctrl, a cautionary tale about the world’s obsession and our near-total dependence on online apps, Vikramaditya Motwane has moved firmly into the future. Or is it the present? Isn’t this what the geeks have been creating with their gaming universes, where your digital avatars are the better, shinier versions of you? Where they slay all the monsters, and leave you — or rather, your avatar — fully in control?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
