<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:24:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:24:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WSzC3qNVoJ0?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 14:32:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this horror comedy movie, Kartik Aaryan returns as Ruhaan or Rooh Baba, a self-proclaimed ghostbuster. We find him swindling people out of their money by claiming to get rid of evil spirits possessing their family members or haunting their houses. However, his pretty profitable career brings him to a new case in which he comes face to face with something he is not prepared to deal with an actual, honest-to-goodness ghost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:04:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2007 की ‘भूल भुलैया’ तो ज़रूर याद होगी आपको। तर्क की कसौटी पर कसी हुई प्रियदर्शन निर्देशित वह फिल्म एक सायक्लोजिकल सस्पैंस-थ्रिलर थी जिसे आज हम हिन्दी की क्लासिक फिल्मों में गिनते हैं। उसके 15 साल बाद आई ‘भूल भुलैया 2’ को उस फिल्म के कंधे पर सवार होकर सिर्फ और सिर्फ इसलिए बनाया गया था ताकि नोट बटोरे जा सकें। वह फिल्म पिछली वाली का सीक्वेल नहीं बल्कि उसी कड़ी की एक फ्रेंचाइज़ी फिल्म थी जिसमें मंजुलिका को भूतनी दिखा कर लोगों को डराया और कुछ मसखरे जोड़ कर लोगों को हंसाया गया था। अनीस बज़्मी के निर्देशन में आई उस फिल्म को आज हम भले ही एक सफल फिल्म कहें लेकिन थी वह एक औसत दर्जे की मसाला फिल्म ही। अब अनीस के ही निर्देशन में आई यह ‘भूल भुलैया 3’ (Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3) भी ऐसी ही है-हॉरर और कॉमेडी का मसाला लपेट कर आई एक औसत फिल्म जो कुछ पल को हंसाएगी, डराएगी, नोट बटोरेगी मगर इज़्ज़त नहीं कमा पाएगी।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:01:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the festive season, director Anees Bazmee tells cinegoers to bring in the popcorn and he would deliver the comic twists. This Deepavali, the director lights up a green cracker that leaves a purple patch in the air but in a bid to be progressive, he fails to keep his traditional comedic pot on the boil and underutilises powerhouse performers like Madhuri Dixit and Vidya Balan to light up the screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:51:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1I-ohOnCkTI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:28:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a good time to a make a ‘horror-comedy’ in Hindi cinema, in this case, rehash a film with a sequel of an established franchise. In this genre, you don’t really have to focus on the horror part (the audience laughs at it anyway, in many cases, it is nervous laughter) and for the comedy part, you just have to put a few characters in a ‘horror’ situation and voila, the comedy element is sorted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:23:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2007, Priyadarshan directed Vidya Balan as the ghostly apparition Manjulika in Bhool Bhulaiyaa, with Aneez Bazmee taking over the reins of this comedy-horror franchise in 2022. Akshay Kumar was replaced by Kartik Aaryan, who played Ruhaan—a charlatan masquerading as a psychic, who communicates with and channels spirits. Tabu stepped into the dual roles of the trapped spirit, Manjulika, and her twin sister, Anjulika.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In part three, Bazmee reinvents the wheel, casting Vidya Balan and Madhuri Dixit as the (maybe) Manjulikas. However, the presence of these two seasoned actresses in one film does not amount to much. In fact, it’s a wasted opportunity. While you have two times the Manjulikas, Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 is half the fun. Even Kartik Aaryan comes across as fatigued, with his character Rooh Baba’s fake ghostbusting antics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:03:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/W294OEfFuCM?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:30:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping with the theme of the franchise, Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 also pits an unassuming cheeky protagonist against a spooky haveli with a buried past. The century-old mansion needs to be restored to its former glory and sold, but Manjulika’s terrorising presence in it forbids the owners from doing so. The royal family in dire need of resources, seeks Rooh baba’s intervention. The fraudster takes up the lucrative offer only to find himself tangled in a mess as he discovers two dark forces who claim to be Manjulika.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:29:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fFhfuctqQJo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:24:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some movies are so entertaining that they make you miss the good old days. But others are so vapid that they make you miss good days. Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 is “others”. You see Vidya Balan, and fondly reminisce about Priyadarshan’s Bhool Bhulaiyaa (2007) and Pritam’s hit soundtrack. You see Vidya Balan and Madhuri Dixit playing enigmatic women, and think of how well they were cast in Abhishek Chaubey’s Ishqiya (2010) and Dedh Ishqiya (2014). You see a tragic female ghost haunt a mansion and morph into a human social message in a setting full of foolish men, and it’s hard not to respect how fundamentally sound the Stree movies are. You see crows descend from the dark skies for dramatic effect and think of The Crows Have Eyes III: The Crowening, the Bosnian B-movie starring Moira Rose in Schitt’s Creek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:20:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All right folks, we are back in the labyrinth. For a third time. Lots of stuff that we remember from the earlier outings. Creaky two-hundred-year-old Bengali havelis. Locked rooms. Vengeful ‘aatmas’. Ghosts who flit about. And characters who spout their lines, and vanish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So. Kartik Aaryan is Rooh Baba, a bogus ghostbuster. Accompanied always by the vertically challenged Tilu (Arun Kushwah). Grabbed by the very modern miss Meera (Tripti Dimri) and her uncle (Rajesh Sharma). Transported to said haveli, in order to bust the ghost of Monjulika. Remember her?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 22:14:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like the earlier two Bhool Bhulaiyaa movies, kickstarted by Priyadarshan in 2007, the third of the horror comedy series by Director Anees Bazmee revolves around a phony psychic caught in the family drama of a haunted haveli. Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 opens like one of those The Mummy preludes unfolding a dark history from 200 years ago only to cut to the present, signalling at the wicked all the wrongdoing has unleashed, which Ruhaan aka Rooh Baba&amp;rsquo;s (Kartik Aaryan) goofball ghostbuster must put an end to by hook or crook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:41:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a film takes off with an unpredictably thoughtful ending. The beginning and the middle get written to lead up to it. Director Anees Bazmee and writer Aakash Kaushik seem to have had an unexpected climax in mind before they sat down to take the audience through a maze, keeping alive the question, “Who’s Manjulika?” With the return of Vidya Balan (Mallika) to the franchise, the entry of Madhuri Dixit (Mandira) and the tussle between them, the guessing game goes on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
