<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carry On on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/carry-on/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Carry On on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:47:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/carry-on/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carry On</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/carry-on-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 15:47:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/carry-on-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are one of those die-hard cinephiles who believe Die Hard is a Christmas film (along with the first two Home Alone flicks), then Netflix’s latest offering may very well make it to that coveted list of yours. Jaume Collet-Serra, the mastermind behind some simple yet efficient nail-biting action thrillers is back and while he’s not teaming up with Liam Neeson this time, he’s got an efficient Taron Egerton and a cast-against-the-grain Jason Bateman facing it off in Carry-On.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carry On</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/carry-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:41:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/carry-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Dwayne Johnson succeeds, he takes hundreds of others along for the ride with him. But when he fails — and he has, in recent years — he doesn’t go down alone. After establishing himself as something of a B-movie auteur early in his career, director Jaume Collet-Serra, like so many others in his position, accepted Hollywood’s offer to level up to the big leagues. He was appointed by Johnson as his latest lackey, but found himself responsible for directing the star’s two biggest recent bombs. These were movies — Jungle Cruise, and more calamitously, Black Adam — that significantly derailed Johnson’s career. Collet-Serra became collateral damage. But as it turns out, being relegated to the relatively forgiving realm of streaming was exactly the jolt to the system that he needed. His latest film, Carry-On, is his best in years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
