<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shamayita Chakraborty on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/shamayita-chakraborty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shamayita Chakraborty on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 08:56:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/shamayita-chakraborty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chaalchitro: The Frame Fatale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chaalchitro-the-frame-fatale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 08:56:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chaalchitro-the-frame-fatale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A gruesome murder shakes Kolkata. Seasoned cops Kanishka Chatterjee (Tota Roy Chowdhury) and Naseer (Anirban Chakrabarti) of the Kolkata Police Detective Department see an uncanny similarity in the execution from an old case. Along with these two, Ritesh Kumar (Shantanu Maheshwari) &amp;ndash; a young enthusiastic IPS, and Bishwa (Indrajeet Bose) get together in action. Soon there are more bodies. Nothing beats a chilling thriller on a winter night, and Pratim D Gupta serves it with a delectable plot garnished with a handful of red herrings. The film, which occasionally runs into predictability, is far too engaging to find flaws. It is fast, lethal, and entertaining, keeping the guessing game on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaalratri</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kaalratri/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:21:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kaalratri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Devi (Soumitrisha), who only remembers the past six years of her life, gets married to Rudra Roy Burman (Indrasish Roy) — a drunkard and lecherous son of Samaresh Roy Burman (Debesh Chattopadhyay). Devi’s mysterious friend Maya (Koushani Mukherjee) — known for her ominous presence – predicts that Rudra will die the next day after their marriage. Her prediction becomes real.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talmar Romeo Juliet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/talmar-romeo-juliet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 01:19:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/talmar-romeo-juliet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Badal Majumder (Kamaleswar Mukhopadhyay) and Liyaqat’s (Joydeep Mukherjee) families harbour animosity for each other for years. Badal’s eldest son Somnath (Anujoy Chattopadhyay) and Liyaqat’s nephew pugnacious Mostaq (Anirban Bhattacharya) do not see eye to eye. However, Rana – Badal&amp;rsquo;s younger son, and Jahanara – Liyaqat&amp;rsquo;s daughter and the apple of his eye, love each other. All this drama takes place in a small town, Talma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikosh Chhaya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nikosh-chhaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:16:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nikosh-chhaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of corpses disappear from a morgue. Police officer Amiya (Gaurab Chakrabarty) and his team start investigating. They learn about a little stinky monster, Genu, who reminds him of an old story. Amiya and Titas (Anindita Bose) remember that their old friend Sanjay (Anujoy Chatterjee) told them a story of a similar monster 10 years ago and both the descriptions match. That’s when Amiya seeks help from Bhaduri Moshai (Chiranjeet Chakraborty).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tekka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tekka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 08:29:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tekka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The film’s story is pretty much what you have seen in the trailer. For those who are uninitiated, here is the plot in brief. Iqlakh (Dev) loses his job, randomly kidnaps a young girl Avantika (Aameya) from her school, and takes her hostage. He demands to get his job back. Maya (Rukmini Maitra) from Kolkata Police comes to negotiate. Even after his company&amp;rsquo;s maintenance manager (Anirban Bhattacharya) verbally promises to give his job back to him, he demands the owner of the firm Anubrata Adhikari (Paran Bandyopadhyay) to come personally. Meanwhile, in a turn of events, little Aratrika’s mother Ira (Swastika Mukherjee) hunts down Iqlakh’s house and takes hostage of his little boy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bohurupi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bohurupi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 18:32:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bohurupi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shiboprosad Mukherjee and Nandita Roy’s Bohurupi delivers what it promises: unadulterated entertainment. It is fun watching this mad cat-and-mouse game. The film is lavishly shot, and most importantly, made with care. It excels in almost every department with Shiboprosad’s skillful acting hogging the lion’s share of the limelight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To begin with, Bohurupi is based on a well-written script and made almost like a biopic of Bikram’s character. The comedy timing, the chemistry between the two lead pairs, the action sequences – everything seems to have worked suitably along with its script. There is no glaring social commentary and that has allowed the film to emerge as a champion masala entertainer. The second half gets into a bit of melodrama but recovers from it quickly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kaantaye Kaantaye</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kaantaye-kaantaye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 13:17:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kaantaye-kaantaye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After their daughter died in a car crash, advocate PK Basu (Saswata Chatterjee) and his wife Rani (Ananya Chatterjee) go to North Bengal to recover from their grief. They visit their family friends Sujata (Ayoshi Talukdar) and Kaushik (Somraj Maity) who open a homestay there. A series of murders take place in Kolkata and North Bengal. As a number of characters get stranded in the homestay, PK Basu catches the culprit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parineeta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/parineeta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 13:19:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/parineeta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Neighbour duo Lolita (Debchandrima Singha Roy) and Shekhar (Gourav Chakrabarty) have unending claim on each other. Despite a marriage in haste, they parted ways because of Shekhar’s prejudices and Lolita’s pride. In Parineeta, Saratchandra Chattopadhyay&amp;rsquo;s classic takes a makeover in Aditi Roy’s series on Hoichoi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saratchandra Chattopadhyay’s Parineeta, as a plot, is clearly dated. And yet its unsullied charm of old-school romance makes it fascinating even today. The original story was adapted on the big screen a number of times. Soumitra Chatterjee and Mousumi Chatterjee’s Parineeta was directed by Ajar Kar. Meena Kumari and Ashok Kumar played the lead in Bimal Roy’s film. Most recently, Vidya Balan and Saif Ali Khan’s Parineeta – directed by Pradeep Sarkar – was released in 2005 and was one of the highest-grossing films of that year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manikbabur Megh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manikbabur-megh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 13:22:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manikbabur-megh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manikbabu (Chandan Sen) lives a lonely life. He is first chased and then romanced by a whiff of cloud that only he can see. What do we see when we look at the sky? Manikbabu sees a whiff of cloud that refuses to leave him. He decides to embrace that celestial piece of cloud in his life. This lonely man and his quirky environment – his noisy ceiling fan, his rooftop greenhouse, the hanging lizard in the bathroom, the pile of files on his office table, and so on – tell a lot of hitherto bottled-up stories. The film is a collage of those chronicles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
