<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Barroz on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/barroz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Barroz on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:56:56 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/barroz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Barroz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/barroz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 20:56:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/barroz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dream projects often come with their share of self-indulgence and doses of obsession. Yet, somewhere one gets to feel things expressed right from the heart of the maker, who has immersed his soul in this idea for so long. What one misses amid all the plasticity of Barroz, Mohanlal’s dream project and his debut directorial, is such an expression which hits us right where it matters. It is no wonder then that one is largely left untouched by the fantasy drama that plays out over 150 minutes. Part of the reason for how Barroz turned out in the end could be the abrupt exit of Jijo Punnoose, the brilliant brain behind India’s first 3D film My Dear Kuttichathan, in the early stages of the project. One of his major grouses was the drastic tinkering with his original screenplay. His stand appears to be justified since one of the weakest elements of Barroz is its unimaginative screenplay filled with overdramatic dialogues that spoil every other scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barroz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/barroz-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:39:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/barroz-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Debutant director Mohanlal has been hung up on the 3D element of Barroz: Guardian of Treasures. So much so that every other aspect of the film has gotten little to no attention. Even Mohanlal, the incredible performer, is absent as everything about Barroz comes across as a stage play captured on camera. The only focus of the team has been to come up with various ways to gloat the 3D elements of the film on the face of the viewer. A flower bouquet will get an unnecessary slow-motion shot as Barroz extends it to Isabell (Maya Rao). The idea is to impress the audience as the flowers extend outside the screen, but even children (who seem to be the target audience of the film) lose interest as such gimmicks become redundant. Beyond the brilliant execution of the 3D technology and the superlative production design, Barroz has little to offer concerning an engaging story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
