<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Her on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/her/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Her on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 14:22:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/her/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Her</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/her-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 14:22:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/her-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lijin Jose’s film Her is an anthology, but it is not strictly one. No clear demarcations exist between the five films in the collection, with one segment segueing smoothly into the next, although the characters and narratives are different. However, only two of the films are directly connected, while the rest have characters from other films popping in at some point to connect it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Her</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/her/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:40:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/her/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s not fair to call Lijin Jose’s Her, written by Archana Vasudev, an anthology. On the surface, these are the stories of five women taking place across five households in and around Thiruvananthapuram. The timelines are jumbled and these stories are set across different genres with at least one comedy, one satire and parts you can broadly call drama, each with its own mood and theme. Yet you feel conflicted by the thought of calling it an anthology because it never stops feeling like a unified whole, with the narrative smoothness of a well-written feature film (it’s edited by Kiran Das).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
