<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Severance S02 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/severance-s02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Severance S02 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 13:13:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/severance-s02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Severance S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/severance-s02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 13:13:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/severance-s02-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a fan of the 2004-2010 sci-fi island drama Lost, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d never find a show that would be weirder or more out there. I was wrong. The Apple TV+ series Severance is a fascinating thriller set in the corporate world that might just be one of the most intriguing streaming series right now. Exploring the premise of having an &amp;lsquo;inner&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;outer&amp;rsquo; self at work and home, the show created by Dan Erickson returns for a second season that continues to examine what it means to be human in a world that is out to exploit you constantly. The second season picks up after the uprising from the innies at the Macrodata Refinement team at Lumon Industries, where Mark (Adam Scott), Helly R (Britt Lower), and Irving (John Turturro) are able to explore the outside world. Management is not happy as the gang is put through their paces initially and pushed even further as they come to terms with the added knowledge of their outie selves. Audiences get to explore more of the Lumon offices with new expanded departments and co-workers like Miss Huang (Sarah Bock), the new deputy manager who is just a child.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
