<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tumko Meri Kasam on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/tumko-meri-kasam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tumko Meri Kasam on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:45:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/tumko-meri-kasam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tumko Meri Kasam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tumko-meri-kasam-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:45:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tumko-meri-kasam-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Second time within months there is an Aurangzeb reference in a Hindi film. If the Mughal ruler was vilified in Laxman Utekar’s Chhaava then he is freshly referenced in Vikram Bhatt’s Tumko Meri Kasam. A character wickedly says he can do anything to sit in the seat of power, like Aurangzeb. But neither the man saying it is particularly odious nor is the outcome of the mention a disaster. One can argue about the overall ineffectiveness of Bhatt’s new work, but, in reality, Tumko Meri Kasam harks back to the good old time in Hindi cinema when films were made without agenda and motives, and scenes were allowed to breathe and not spliced together by furtive video-game editing. Well, one part of this is more true than the other. Scenes go on unendingly in Tumko Meri Kasam (endearing at first and grating soon after) as the narrative veers towards propaganda. Except, Bhatt’s film props up a man and not a nation. But given that it props at least something up, Anupam Kher features in a central role and does everything. He stands in court as the accused; he argues as his own lawyer and doubles up as a detective to find loopholes in the case even as police officers remain conspicuously absent like what we are watching is a figment of someone’s imagination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumko Meri Kasam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tumko-meri-kasam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 09:35:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tumko-meri-kasam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written and directed by Vikram Bhatt, the film is a fictionalised version of the story of Ajay Murdia aka the founder of a chain of fertility clinics, Indira IVF. According to reports the film has incorporated some real facts about his life and career in the screenplay. The film explores a legal case, where he is accused of an attempt to murder one of his younger board members, while the memory of his dead wife gives him hope to not give up. With a run time of over two and a half hours, the film feels longer than necessary between, flashbacks, songs and more. Led by Anupam Kher as Ajay Murdia, the film begins with a news montage of how he is accused of attempting to murder, while a court proceeding grants him bail in the matter. His lawyer played by Eesha Deol is seen flying with him to Udaipur, so the family can decide how to move forward with the case. While Ajay wants to brave the storm along, he isn&amp;rsquo;t left behind by his kids who also decide to stick by him till the end. Soon it is evident, that the young board member is trying to frame Ajay Murdia in the case and his life was never in danger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
