<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>This Is the Zodiac Speaking on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/this-is-the-zodiac-speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in This Is the Zodiac Speaking on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:22:10 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/this-is-the-zodiac-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Is the Zodiac Speaking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/this-is-the-zodiac-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:22:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/this-is-the-zodiac-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Often described as ‘the most famous unsolved murder case in American history’, the Zodiac Killer’s brutal spree in the 1960s and ‘70s attracted a flock of amateur investigators before true crime was even a thing. But now it is, and as per the law, Netflix is mandated to make a three-part documentary series about it. Titled This is the Zodiac Speaking, the show confusingly omits the real-life chapter that inspired this title, and presents, instead, a new angle to the case, one that has been flogged to death by documentarians, filmmakers, and podcasters alike. This is the Zodiac Speaking has the same fast-paced narrative that has come to define most of these Netflix true crime content; the tone is perpetually ominous, the violence and mayhem is circled and highlighted, cheap recreations are used to heighten the drama. The ending, invariably, is anti-climactic. But the show attempts to sidestep this inevitability by picking its lane and sticking to it. In minute one, This is the Zodiac Speaking identifies a possible suspect — in fact, the only person who was ever publicly named by the police as a person of interest — and proceeds to move heaven and earth in an effort to corroborate its claims.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
