<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>You&#39;re Cordially Invited on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/youre-cordially-invited/</link>
    <description>Recent content in You&#39;re Cordially Invited on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:24:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/youre-cordially-invited/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Cordially Invited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/youre-cordially-invited-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:24:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/youre-cordially-invited-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest Prime Video release is the romantic comedy titled You&amp;rsquo;re Cordially Invited led by Reese Witherspoon and Will Ferrell. Directed and written by Nicholas Stoller, the film focuses on the story of two supporting characters at two different weddings aka the bride&amp;rsquo;s sister and another bride&amp;rsquo;s widowed father. They cross paths at the accidently double-booked wedding venue and the fight for the venue ensues. While the plot seems easy to explore in the comedy genre, the makers did present a new take on the situation. Instead of the fight going on before the wedding proceeds, the arguments go on throughout the wedding and after, taking away the urgency of the incident. The film begins with Will Ferrell&amp;rsquo;s character finding out that his young daughter is getting married to her boyfriend. While he isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly happy about it, he agrees because it would mean his daughter moves closer to home. On the other hand, Reese finds out her sister is getting married to her erotic dancer boyfriend. Supportive of the decision and wary of how the family would react, she agrees to look after the wedding planning. Both weddings are accidentally booked at the same resort on a small island for the same weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Cordially Invited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/youre-cordially-invited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 23:02:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/youre-cordially-invited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By now, big stars teaming up for a streaming original film — mostly comedy, and made on a budget that makes you wonder about the recovery without a theatrical run — has become a mainstay. What’s been difficult is to shake off the tag that these films offer little entertainment compares to their big-screen counterparts. Films like Prime Video’sYou’re Cordially Invited tell you why this trend is, unfortunately, not a fad. Director Nicholas Stoller, the maker behind comedies like Forgetting Sarah Marshall, Get Him to the Greek, The Five-Year Engagement and Bros, is back for another comedy headlined by powerhouses Will Ferrell and Reese Witherspoon. In You’re Cordially Invited, a single father, Jim (Will Ferrell), to get his daughter Jenni (Geraldine Viswanathan) married off, books a small inn on Palmetto Island where he got married years ago. Concurrently, television producer Margot (Reese Witherspoon) finds out that her sister Neve (Meredith Hagner) is planning on marrying and she volunteers to plan the wedding. She books the same Palmetto Island, where she and Neve visited their grandmother as children. Thanks to what can be only called a clerical error, both parties reach the island on the same day to learn about the double booking. While Jim and Margot initially decide to work it out by sharing the premises, their egos, insecurities, miscommunication, and many other mistakes play havoc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
