<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bougainvillea on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bougainvillea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bougainvillea on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:52:40 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bougainvillea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:52:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amal Neerad&amp;rsquo;s Bougainvillea features an impressive cast, including Kunchacko Boban, Jyothirmay, and Fahadh Faasil; however, the film ultimately flatters to deceive. Faasil is relegated to a tertiary role, likely either to help out his friends or for a fat paycheck – probably the former. Pitched as a psychological thriller, the film becomes exasperating due to its screenplay and overall execution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a film of this nature, a concise narrative is essential, along with an assumption that the audience possesses a degree of intelligence—an area where Bougainvillea falters. Neerad&amp;rsquo;s method involves showing then explaining, and then repeating the &amp;lsquo;show part again for those who may still not have grasped it. For example, the film repeatedly informs viewers about the kidnapping of three girls. Once the perpetrator is revealed – something that becomes evident well before the actual disclosure – there is little value in depicting all three kidnappings in flashback, as the method remains consistent and ultimately becomes irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 08:04:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amal Neerad and his co-writer Lajo Jose (whose story this film is based on) know how far to push the unreliable narrator trope. Not only is their protagonist Reethu (Jyothirmayi in her return) suffering from both retrograde and anterograde amnesia, but we’re seeing the film through her perspective for the most part. What makes this film even more complex is how quickly we get the feeling that we cannot rely on the people Reethu relies on to make sense of her chilling universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 08:02:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_eQDsBPZvzI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:36:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among all the flaws a writer can imagine for their protagonist, an unreliable memory throws up quite a few fascinating possibilities. In Bougainvillea, Reethu (Jyothirmayi) is almost always unsure of anything that happens right in front of her eyes. For a fairly good period, we are also caught in a similar dilemma — as to whether what we are seeing through her eyes is for real; whether she has painted a Sunflower or yet another Bougainvillea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:10:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Director Amal Neerad&amp;rsquo;s latest movie Bougainvillea is a slow-burning thriller that offers more strengths than weaknesses in its entertainment value. Set against the backdrop of an unreliable memory, the film borrows elements from classics like Memento and The Usual Suspects, while crafting a uniquely Malayalam narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What sets Bougainvillea apart is Neerad’s ability to command attention, even with minimal marketing. Filling half a theatre on a Thursday morning in Bengaluru for a Malayalam film speaks volumes about the anticipation surrounding Neerad’s projects, a testament to his loyal fanbase and established reputation. The film itself lives up to expectations, offering fans signature Amal Neerad moments: slow-motion sequences, intense visuals, and an atmospheric score by Sushin Shyam that keeps the tension simmering throughout.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 10:28:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How does one lead a life when you forget your routine and even the mere existence of your loved ones? Bougainvillea, directed by Amal Neerad, is a film that revolves around a couple, Royce (Kunchacko Boban) and Reethu (Jyothirmayi), that gives you an insight into a pair that is trying to overcome this kind of an unusual situation. In the initial few seconds, we see Royce and Reethu meet with a nasty accident. The after-effect of the accident: Reethu suffers from Anterograde and Retrograde amnesia. Reethu&amp;rsquo;s life is defined by Royce&amp;rsquo;s ideas. Her day-to-day routine and details about her family are written in a diary. And house help Rema (Srinda) oversees her at home when Royce, a doctor, is at the hospital. One day, David Koshy (Fahadh Faasil) turns up at Reethu&amp;rsquo;s home and asks her about the whereabouts of a missing girl. His interrogation hits a roadblock because of Reethu&amp;rsquo;s memory. But, there&amp;rsquo;s more than what meets the eye.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
