<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:24:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:24:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Anbe Sivam, Madhavan’s Anbarasu, who coerces his friend Sivam, to become his brother figure of sorts, says, “Idhenna kaadhala, asingama sollitte irukkardhukku… (This isn’t love. Why should we keep on announcing it to the world?)” It was a poignant scene about the importance of understanding love without putting it in words. But it was also a reminder that love for one another has to be expressed repeatedly. Why? It is not to just create a sense of acknowledgement about the relationship. It is also to create an example for many others who might think their love isn’t right, or they are not destined for love, or they are not deserving of love. That is why all kinds of love need to be showcased for all to see. And that is why Jayaprakash Radhakrishnan’s Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai is an important film in Tamil cinema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:03:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kadhal Enbathu Podhuvudamai is a film about the upper limit of a modern family’s progressiveness. For Sam (Lijomol Jose), it comes as a shocker that her parents aren’t the rational beings they seem to take pride in. Their facade of being a modern couple crumbles down when she reveals that her lover is a woman. Director Jayaprakash Radhakrishnan manages to pack in a lot of questions and answers about acceptance in a matter of 102 minutes, with a gripping tale that doesn’t let you meander much. The success of this character-driven film is due to its focus on the conflict and not pretending to be anything other than what it is. The film follows the events of a day at Lakshmi’s (Rohini) household. Lakshmi is excited as her daughter’s lover is expected for lunch. She is also annoyed by the absence of her maid Mary (Deepa), who we are shown to be dealing with an abusive son-in-law at a police station. Lakshmi’s excitement knows no bounds as she is ready with gifts for her to-be son-in-law. However, Sam is petrified as her lover is Nandini (Anusha Prabhu), a woman. We are kept on the edge for almost all of the first half of the film as the ice doesn’t break. Nandini comes with a male friend and Lakshmi takes him for the lover of her daughter. When the cat finally gets out of the bag, Lakshmi flips, revealing her ugly side. What ensues is an interesting conversational drama that makes a case for queer love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 14:52:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first 30 minutes of Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai (Love Is Common Property) is not an easy film to sit through. It’s frothy and hollow and you’d be surprised that you’re watching the work of writer-director Jayaprakash Radhakrishnan, known for intense psychological dramas such as Lens (2016) and Thalaikoothal (2023). It begins with Sam (Lijomol Jose) confessing to her mother (Rohini) that she’s in love and wants her to meet this person. With the flowery set-up you’d find in silly rom-coms, we get scene after painful scene of the mother, preparing to welcome her future son-in-law. We learn that they hail from the upper middle class, and we also learn that Sam&amp;rsquo;s parents separated years ago. The film uses this time to introduce us to a handful of characters, including Sam’s father (Vineeth), Sam’s bestie Ravi (Kalesh) and Deepa (Deepa Shankar), the cook who is more than family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 23:42:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Indian films about same-sex love are far and few. The ones with the right portrayal of homosexuals are even fewer. Director Jayaprakash Radhakrishnan&amp;rsquo;s recent release, Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai, is the latest entrant to the list of films on queer love. Starring Lijomol, Anusha Prabhu, Vineeth and Rohini, the film is a deeply moving and heartwarming film about love that goes beyond boundaries, societal acceptance, prejudice and personal traumas. Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai begins with Sam (Lijomol Jose) having a heartfelt chat with her mother Lakshmi (Rohini Molleti). She confesses that she is in love and Lakshmi suggests she take the &amp;lsquo;man&amp;rsquo; home for lunch on a Sunday. Lakshmi conveys the news to her estranged husband Devararaj (Vineeth) and asks him to join them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
