<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wallace and Gromit Vengeance Most Fowl on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wallace and Gromit Vengeance Most Fowl on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:33:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wallace and Gromit Vengeance Most Fowl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 01:33:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trust Wallace to get himself mixed up in a plot that puts all of humanity at peril. The eccentric inventor — he’s the protagonist of Nick Park’s four-time Oscar-winning stop-motion animation series — makes his streaming debut alongside his ‘top dog’ Gromit with the feature-length Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit: Vengeance Most Fowl. Released on Netflix, the film is a pure nostalgia trip for fans who grew up with their charming adventures, replete with quirky household gizmos, absurd villains, and more cheese than you’d find in a Frenchman’s larder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wallace and Gromit Vengeance Most Fowl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 01:27:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wallace-and-gromit-vengeance-most-fowl-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been 20 years since the last Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit feature film, The Curse of the Were-Rabbit. And this follow-up does not disappoint, largely due to the reappearance of the greatest villain in the franchise, Feather McGraw. Yes, that dastardly silent penguin is back, and he wants revenge on the duo that sent him to jail all those years ago. Will he succeed? Not if Gromit has his way. With Nick Park back as co-director, Wallace &amp;amp; Gromit: Vengeance Most Fowl is a funny, delightful romp in the neighbourhood. Wallace&amp;rsquo;s newest invention in the film is a Norbot, a smart gnome robot ready to help poor Gromit around the house. Even when he doesn&amp;rsquo;t need any help. What the pair don&amp;rsquo;t realise that someone&amp;rsquo;s got their eye on them, all the way from jail, as the quick-witted penguin has been biding his time, waiting to get back at Wallace for turning him into the authorities in the 1993 short film The Wrong Trousers for attempting to steal the Blue Diamond. Soon, Wallace and his trusty dog Gromit are evading the police, who believe he might be the recent spate of neighbourhood robberies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
