<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manvat Murders on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/manvat-murders/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manvat Murders on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:51:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/manvat-murders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manvat Murders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 10:51:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early 1970s, a series of murders left the residents of Manvat terrorized, and people of Maharashtra in shock. A small town in Parbhani district, Manvat saw people, mostly women, being killed over a span of about two years with a black magic ritualistic motive, as the cops would later find out. Ashish Bende’s series attempts to take a deep dive into the case through the eyes of late cop Ramakant Kulkarni’s lens. Manvat Murders is based on Kulkarni’s book Footprints on the Sand of Time, which documented his high-profile cases, including the Manvat case which he was assigned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manvat Murders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:54:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a true-crime drama in the Indian streaming landscape is like being an aspiring batsman in India’s cramped bylanes and crowded fields. Everybody is one — and everybody is advised to be one. Consequently, it’s harder to stand out. The default level has to be high: an engrossing story, a solid cast, a sense of place and time, technical competence. Most shows opt for an atmospheric setting to conceal a convoluted plot; the logic is that a visually striking tone will compensate for pacing and structural issues. In other words, the style can distract from a lack of substance. But Manvat Murders, helmed by Aatmapamphlet (2023) director Ashish Avinash Bende, is a Marathi-language series that does the reverse.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manvat Murders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 11:22:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/manvat-murders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ritualistic Manwat Murders which brutally claimed the lives of innocent children and women and shook Maharashtra in the 70s, does it again. Amol Palekar had already put it effectively on screen in Akriet (1981).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But relive the grisly times as creator-writer Girish Joshi and director Ashish Avinash Bende take off from Ramakant S Kulkarni’s book ‘Footprints On The Sands Of Time’ to go back to the village (spelt Manwat in actuality and Manvat in the series) where tantriks presided over human sacrifice and blood offerings from private parts in the unquenchable quest for a hidden treasure and to fill the womb of a barren second wife.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
