<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priyanka Roy on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/priyanka-roy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Priyanka Roy on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:37:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/priyanka-roy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adolescence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/adolescence-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:37:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/adolescence-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adolescence confronts the debilitating fear(s) of every parent — where are our children going? Who are they meeting? What kind of conversations are they having? Who or what is influencing them? And the biggest question of them all — what are our children watching? Ever since it dropped exactly a week ago, this Netflix miniseries has taken the world by storm. ‘A perfect piece of television’ is not a descriptor that comes by easily, but Adolescence has earned that in more than a few reviews. On social media, it is being discussed, debated and dissected. Besides the overall impact of this four-episode series, almost every scene, dialogue, body language and more, is being put under the microscope, even as the viewer peels off layers and semi-layers of this crushing yet cathartic watch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Khakee: The Bengal Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/khakee-the-bengal-chapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:35:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/khakee-the-bengal-chapter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Calcutta is a living, breathing entity in Khakee: The Bengal Chapter, but not in the way we have come to know of it on screen. The city — familiar to the world as the hub of culture and creativity, as the land of Tagore and Ray — is imbued with a sinister edge in this new Netflix series, functioning as a hotbed of gang wars, organ trafficking, kidnapping, murder and of the consistently tenuous equation between cops and criminals. So, a machher bajar, where the act of buying fish has almost been romanticised into a form of art by the Bengali gastronome (honestly, is there any other kind?) sees a policeman being hacked in broad daylight by a bnoti; At the parar cha-er dokan, adda is definitely a mainstay but so is the brokering of hit jobs. A significant character’s body is stacked against the gate of the Victoria Memorial, forming a dichotomous (I refrain from saying ‘striking’) bloody red foreground against the pristine white facade of the city’s iconic landmark. Guns are traded at New Market. The streets are seedy, the changing positions of the players often finds the underbelly indistinguishable from the rest of the city. Calcutta carries the burden of many bodies, its streets tinged with blood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:15:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had never thought that there would come a film — at least in my lifetime — that could challenge the combined vacuous pointlessness of the Student of the Year franchise. That distinction belongs to Nadaaniyan, a film which, even though we are just in March, stands a good chance of being within the Top 5 section of the worst films list of 2025. Nadaaniyan, streaming on Netflix, comes from the same folks who, of course, made the Student of the Year franchise. Dharma Productions may have packaged its ‘younger’ productions as the more sleek-sounding Dharmatic, but Nadaaniyan is clearly not the kind of film that is going to take them far. Nor is it the kind of debut that actors Saif Ali Khan and Amrita Singh should have approved for their son Ibrahim Ali Khan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:21:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Shaukh paal ke kya karega, Malegaon mein tu marega.&amp;rsquo; This innocuous line sung rambunctiously by two childhood friends on a bike ride is both about ambition and the realisation of the futility of it, destined as they are to live within the borders of Malegaon, the small town they were born in and will probably die in. And yet, it is these two boys — along with a few pals, all of who share a common love for cinema — that have gone on to put Malegaon on the map. Superboys of Malegaon revolves around this motley crew. A charming, slice-of-life film about ordinary men doing extraordinary things, this Reema Kagti directorial written by Varun Grover is a potent, layered example of storytelling, one which strikes a chord immediately, even if you know very little of the world the film is set in. Malegaon, an unassuming town close to Nashik in Maharashtra, has made it to the news for a variety of reasons. There were the Malegaon blasts close to two decades ago that claimed many lives. Five years ago, Malegaon incubated itself in such a way that very few lives were lost in the Covid-19 pandemic, prompting other administrations to attempt and replicate its model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhoom Dhaam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:14:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An extroverted heroine with an inclination to cuss with abandon and the ability to talk nineteen (hundred) to the dozen. A docile hero, the exact opposite of her. And the pair caught up in chaos during the course of one night. This could well be the first hour of Jab We Met. But the dark and quiet galiyaan of Ratlam have given way to the cacophonic roads of Mumbai. The pair here — unlike Geet and Aditya in Imtiaz Ali&amp;rsquo;s romantic comedy for the ages — are married. This is Dhoom Dhaam. The title is a smart play on the festivities associated with a wedding. After all, &amp;lsquo;dhoom dhoom se shaadi karenge&amp;rsquo; is as old as Bollywood itself. But in Dhoom Dhoom, now playing on Netflix, &amp;lsquo;dhoom dhaam&amp;rsquo; alludes to the fireworks that follow. What can be more deadly than marriage? Well, a bride and groom on the run on their wedding night, pursued by a gang of goons who are convinced that the newly-married couple are in possession of a key piece of incriminating evidence. Except that they aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chhaava</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:12:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The law of averages — that a brilliant father rarely gives way to an equally illustrious son — was turned on its head as early as the 17th century when Sambhaji took over the reigns of the Maratha empire from his father, Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj. Chhatrapati Sambhaji Maharaj&amp;rsquo;s depiction in history — despite tales of his unwavering valour — are unfortunately sketchy. Even the name by which he was referred to — &amp;lsquo;Chhaava&amp;rsquo; aka &amp;rsquo;lion&amp;rsquo;s cub&amp;rsquo; — is more of a nod to Shivaji&amp;rsquo;s larger-than-life courage and persona. To cite an almost as-good-as-it-gets allusion, it refers more to Mufasa than it does to Simba. Hence, the unsung story of Sambhaji, and his relentless fight against the Mughals, led by the tyrannical Aurangzeb, needed to be documented. Chhaava does that, with its source material being the eponymously named historical novel by Shivaji Sawant. Which brings us to the tricky question of how much of Chhaava — the book, and by logical extension, the film — is fact and how much of it is exaggerated fact? We will, perhaps, never know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 20:01:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those not in favour of remakes — I am one of them, considering most turn out to be a lazy copy-paste job — the decision to let go of Mrs because the memories of watching The Great Indian Kitchen are too sacrosanct, will not be unfounded. But Mrs is not just any other remake. It is a thriving, breathing, nuanced film in its own right. It is the kind of film that takes the best out of its source material and enhances it, setting itself in a socio-cultural context that is relevant and relatable. Mrs hits hard — just as hard as The Great Indian Kitchen did when it released at the tail-end of the first wave of the pandemic. The Malayalam film with a seemingly simple story of a newly-married woman struggling to fit into a conservative and patriarchal household, ignited conversations around gender roles, casual sexism, toxic relationships, male entitlement and a woman&amp;rsquo;s role in a world she is constantly stereotyped in. It became a mirror of the suffering that most Indian women, at some time or maybe all of the time, have been subjected to. In that film, what remained subtle and innocuous at first finally boiled over into rage that resulted in a moment of gut-wrenching catharsis. Like the woman at the centre of it, we felt elated, but we also cried.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 13:22:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are flawed protagonists. And then there are problematic men masquerading as heroes. Dev Ambre aka Deva belongs to the latter category. Deva is a trigger-happy Mumbai cop whose designation is disproportionate to the body count he has notched up. Deva has severe anger issues, conveniently notched down to him being a rebel. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t think twice before sticking the barrel of a gun into the mouth of a woman who is not a criminal by any measure. Dev is a huge proponent of police brutality, but gets away with it every time. No one can say &amp;rsquo;no&amp;rsquo; to him. For that would mean that person&amp;rsquo;s body parts could be in real danger of being distanced from his body. When Dev asks his girlfriend Diya (Pooja Hegde) what she likes about him, she replies with: &amp;lsquo;Besides your arrogance, your grumpy face and your huge anger issues, I like the fact that you have a child in you&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 18:25:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year ago, almost to the day, when Fighter released and didn’t exactly set the box office on fire, director Siddharth Anand put forth a bizarre claim. He said that the Hrithik Roshan-Deepika Padukone starrer, described by its makers as “India’s first aerial action film”, had not found much favour with the audience because “90 per cent of Indians haven’t flown in planes”. By that logic, one would have to be an Italian mafioso to appreciate The Godfather. The good thing is that you don’t have to sign up for a fighter pilot licence before you walk in for a show of Sky Force. This bi-annual Akshay Kumar deshbhakti dose — ‘a fictional story inspired by real events’ — has the kind of thrill and drama that every viewer, brought up on a steady diet of Bollywood patriotic films, is familiar with. Which is both a good and a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mother&#39;s Instinct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mothers-instinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 20:54:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mothers-instinct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mother&amp;rsquo;s Instinct could have been named &amp;lsquo;Mom gone bonkers&amp;rsquo;. Turning the concept/ idea/ theme of a mother&amp;rsquo;s selfless love for her child on its head, this 2024 thriller, now streaming on Prime Video, is a pulpy watch, with maternal instinct going into a zone dark enough to result in murder. A couple of them, in fact. Set in the 1960s and headlined by Hollywood A-listers Anne Hathaway and Jessica Chastain, the directorial debut of acclaimed French cinematographer Benoit Delhomme has a Hitchcockian feel of unease and foreshadowing, but never really lives up to its ultimately pulpy potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paatal Lok S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:06:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we first met Hathiram Chaudhary in the summer of 2020, humanity was in the grip of a severe pandemic, and &amp;lsquo;paatal lok&amp;rsquo; — to now put it lightly — didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be too much of an alien word (or world) at that moment. The show provided a much-needed distraction, and was a rare watch that gave us food for thought, metamorphosing from a police procedural to a tightly-knit thriller that compelled us to examine the fault lines of caste, social prejudice, marginalisation, vote-bank politics, fake news and religious divide. Five years later, Hathiram — played like second skin by the irrepressible Jaideep Ahlawat — is back. In Season 2, the stakes may be higher, the socio-political environment more tense and the cocktail of betrayal, deceit, double-cross and revenge more tricky and tenuous&amp;hellip; but Hathiram has remained the same. A man still world-weary and honest to a fault. But if angst defined Chaudhary in the first season — a sincere if bullheaded cop thirsting for one challenging case in his predominantly unremarkable career — it is acceptance that forms his core this time. Hathiram hasn&amp;rsquo;t made any significant strides in his career, but as a man he seems content. &amp;lsquo;Seems&amp;rsquo; is the operative word here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:34:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a film in which the leading man&amp;rsquo;s signature line is &amp;lsquo;I am unpredictable&amp;rsquo;, Game Changer feels as old as cinema itself. In fact, the plot of this film — stretching over an abominably long 165 minutes — is so stale that every second of it will remind you of some terrible movie you may have had the misfortune of sitting through in the past. Game Changer is vintage Shankar, which is more of a bad than a good thing these days. The man who once gave us films like Gentleman and Anniyan, Enthiran and Indian, has been stuck in a creative rut, recently illustrated by the torture fest called Indian 2. Game Changer is a definite improvement over Indian 2 but that isn&amp;rsquo;t saying much about a film that relies on every overused trope in the masala movie book — physical (over) acting, grating background score, expensively-shot but totally unnecessary songs and a story that goes here, there, everywhere&amp;hellip; and ultimately, nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Warrant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:32:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Vikramaditya Motwane film (or series) will always have one standout moment that stays on with the audience long after curtain call. In his debut film Udaan, it is the final moment of brothers Rohan and Arjun triumphantly walking hand-in-hand to their long-deserved freedom. In Trapped, it is Shaurya’s almost gleeful taandav-like dance when he burns down his mattress in a bid to attract attention in the apartment he finds himself locked in. In Lootera, it is the painfully poignant penultimate scene of Varun hanging an artificial leaf in the blinding blizzard so that Paakhi has reason to live, for at least a day more. In Jubilee, among many memorable moments, it is the unbridled sense of joy, reminiscent of Awaara, where Jay and Niloufer lose their umbrella in the pouring rain, but discover each other in the process. Each of these scenes represents freedom — or the journey towards it — in many ways. Each moment, as is the norm in a Motwane directorial, is simple on the surface but is loaded with meat and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squid Game S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/squid-game-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:46:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/squid-game-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Squid Game in 2021 was met with overwhelming resonance and relevance. In a world ravaged by the pandemic which had shifted power structures, altered priorities for both individuals and institutions and given birth to an existential crisis which compelled many of us to question purpose and privilege, the South Korean series — that Netflix dropped with very little fanfare — may have spoken, much like the Oscar biggie Parasite, about the class chasm in that country as well as fast-growing debt and the perils of the rise of capitalism in the South Korean economy, but it found itself touching a chord with audiences across the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 17:44:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Logic, chronology, geography, sensitivity, ear drums and brain cells all take a hike in Baby John. The big-budget production that attempts to launch Varun Dhawan as an all-out action star is an all-round assault on the senses, partially redeemed by only a few clap-worthy moments mostly credited to ‘VD’, which is what the baby-faced actor is introduced as at the beginning of Baby John. I haven’t watched Theri, the 2016 Tamil blockbuster which was purely a fan-service exercise for diehard followers of Thalapathy Vijay. I am not sure if Varun has the kind of fans — I mean by demographic and not volume — that would queue up feverishly to watch him defy the laws of physics to make easy work of 10 men at one go or swing his sunglasses in one swift movement as some sort of a signature style, a mid-level tribute to everyone from the iconic Rajinikanth to the magnetic Chulbul Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juror #2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/juror-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 14:51:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/juror-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes truth isn’t justice, and justice isn’t truth’. Delivered with both pain and profundity in the penultimate moments of Juror#2, this incandescent line not only sums up the film, but the justice system as a whole, anywhere in the world. Exposing the fault lines in our rules of crime and punishment, but in the kind of quiet yet forceful manner which has been a signature of his brand of filmmaking ever since Clint Eastwood first put on the director’s hat a staggering 53 years ago, Juror#2 is the type of film that makes your mind go back to it time and again even days and weeks after watching it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:50:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If the 2019 reboot of The Lion King, that came out 25 years after the original, also called The Lion King, taught us anything, it is that one should never tamper with anything that has made a place for itself not only in the hearts of the audience but also in cinema history. Mufasa: The Lion King, though not a reboot or remake, can be added to that list. Serving as a prequel to the 2019 film, it takes us back in time to when Mufasa and Taka — as Scar was once known — were young cubs roaming the plains together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despatch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:57:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A watch of Despatch, especially in its penultimate moments, sent me straight to Google in search of some facts and figures. That, in turn, led me down a rabbit hole where I was bombarded with one astounding (‘uncomfortable’ would be more apt) revelation after another. According to the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organisation’s UNESCO Observatory of Killed Journalists, more than 1,600 journalists have been killed since 1993. Earlier this year, UNESCO director-general Audrey Azoulay broke it down bluntly, stating that in 85 per cent of such killings, the perpetrator has gone unpunished.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 09:29:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Q. Why can&amp;rsquo;t Miley Cyrus afford to buy Pushpa?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A. &amp;lsquo;Pushpa flower(s) nahin, fire hain.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This PJ masquerading as a riddle — something which I made up while writing this review — is perhaps as low IQ as it can get. Much like the Pushpa franchise, which thrives on being low IQ, but does one thing pretty much consistently: it serves up, in Silk-speak, what it promises — entertainment, entertainment and more entertainment. Pushpa 2: The Rule, arriving three years after Pushpa: The Rise that became a bona fide pan-India blockbuster and laid the foundation for a big-budget franchise, packs a punch in almost all departments, even going up a notch or two from the first film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom at Midnight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:25:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At the stroke of the midnight hour, when the world sleeps, India will awake to life and freedom”. This momentous line from Jawaharlal Nehru’s Tryst with Destiny speech, delivered on the eve of India’s Independence on August 15, 1947, remains etched in the annals of history. What also remains an indelible part of our country’s birth into freedom after 200 years of colonial rule is the bloodied, agonising, gut-wrenching division of one nation into two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vijay 69</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vijay-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 16:20:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vijay-69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The never-say-die mantra of its 69-year-old protagonist is what forms the crux of Vijay 69. This is a story of spirit, spunk and resilience which is birthed within Vijay Mathew when he, ironically, is given up for dead. Played by Anupam Kher with the kind of chameleonic ease that has seen the actor make 500-plus films in 40-odd years, Vijay Mathew’s moment of epiphany arrives in the film’s initial moments when he lands up at his own ‘funeral’. When former swimming coach Vijay is spotted ‘diving’ into the sea in the middle of the night and not turning up till the morning, his friends and family assume the worst. The truth is that Vijay was spending the night at a drunken sesh and when he stumbles on to his coffin the next morning, it is a wake-up call for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel: Honey Bunny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 11:27:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A man, holding a gun, chases a woman through the nooks and crannies of Belgrade. Finding himself in a cul-de-sac of sorts, he sees her pointing a gun back at him. “Put your gun down,” she barks at him. He, a seasoned special agent, lets go of his gun and promptly gets shot. The law of probability points to the fact that if he had held on to the gun, there would be a 50 per cent chance of him being shot and a 50 per cent chance of him being able to shoot the woman in front of him. When he drops the gun, for no explainable reason, he makes that probability convert to a 100 per cent chance against him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Bobby: My Catfish Nightmare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sweet-bobby-my-catfish-nightmare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 14:33:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sweet-bobby-my-catfish-nightmare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even seasoned true-crime documentary aficionados will be left perplexed and very, very uncomfortable by what unfolds in this recently released watch on Netflix. A large part of that has to do with the fact that Sweet Bobby: My Catfish Nightmare feels both relatable and ridiculous at the same time and brings to the fore the dark abyss that is the Internet as well as exposes the shocking depths that human apathy can plunge to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Longlegs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/longlegs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 13:10:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/longlegs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As is the norm in promoting any product these days, in the run-up to its theatrical release, Longlegs fell back on social media influencers to market it as the ‘scariest film of the year’. A far more interesting promotional campaign, which quickly went viral, included cryptic ads in newspapers, billboards across Los Angeles comprising nothing but a phone number which, when called, had actor Nicolas Cage, who plays the titular character, whisper ‘threats’ to listeners. A true-crime website was specially designed to detail the antecedents of Longlegs’ long list of victims. A modestly budgeted horror film was turned into an event, which made everyone ask: is Longlegs the most terrifying film in recent times?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:38:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is not a single subtle bone in Singham Again&amp;rsquo;s action-packed, slo-mo loving body. While over-the-top has always been the signature of not only the Singham films but also of director Rohit Shetty&amp;rsquo;s cinema as a whole, Singham Again takes it to level next. Which really isn&amp;rsquo;t a good thing from the point of view of the art and craft of cinema but perhaps works in giving fans of this kind of filmmaking ample bang for their buck.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 15:17:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The growing worry about lack of quality control in the OTT space now has a physical embodiment. Do Patti. A film which may have its heart in the right place but is otherwise all over the place. Do Patti aims to be a sensitive and scathing film on domestic abuse. The other tags it wants to earn for itself are a noir thriller, a police procedural, a film on sibling rivalry, a blistering criticism of privilege and a racy romance laced with sex, lies and videotape (or rather, mobile phone footage). It ends up being neither.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raat Jawaan Hai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raat-jawaan-hai-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 22:43:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raat-jawaan-hai-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The millennial attempting to retain individuality and identity, while holding on to old friendships and coping with being a new parent, is a demographic that has hardly, if ever, been represented on the Indian screen. Even if it has been, it has been reduced to a strand or a subplot in a coming-of-age story. The fact that it even goes down this route immediately sets Raat Jawaan Hai apart. That it does it well, making its eight episodes a breezy watch which you want to hold on to and hope it doesn’t end, is a huge feather in its cap. This is a definite clutter-breaker in the Indian streaming space. One which has been long overdue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:56:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agneepath plays on the aircraft entertainment system, that telling scene of a young Vijay Dinanath Chauhan burning down a petrol pump being a visual allegory of a similar incident perpetrated by the protagonist in Jigra a few moments ago. This is just one instance. Throughout the runtime of Jigra, Amitabh Bachchan pops up as idea and inspiration, set-up and syntax. When Satya (Alia Bhatt), caught in a situation which may end in violence, is gently warned: &amp;ldquo;Abhi Bachchan nahin bann na hain&amp;hellip; sirf bachke nikalna hain&amp;rdquo;, she rolls up her sleeves and says matter-of-factly: &amp;ldquo;Ab toh Bachchan hi bann na hain&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/joker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 20:48:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/joker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let’s give the people what they want,” Lady Gaga’s Harleen “Lee” Quinzel (aka Harley Quinn) declares at a key moment in Joker: Folie a Deux. That seems odd coming from a film that is committed to giving audiences quite the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a haul of $1 billion at the box office, the Golden Lion at the Venice International Film Festival, 11 Academy Award nominations and the first-ever Oscar for Joaquin Phoenix, director Todd Phillips knew it would be carte blanche for him when it came to the inevitable sequel to 2019’s intriguing if ultimately superficial Joker. Five years later, Phillips, armed with a follow-up with ample promise and potential but little in terms of premise and plot, has, unfortunately, squandered that opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
