<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daaku Maharaaj on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/daaku-maharaaj/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daaku Maharaaj on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:10:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/daaku-maharaaj/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daaku Maharaaj</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daaku-maharaaj-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:10:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daaku-maharaaj-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No one in Telugu cinema loves playing the saviour as much as Nandamuri Balakrishna. The more grave the injustice, the more weapons he can wield, the more henchmen he can kill, and the more noise his dialogues can make. Probably why he feels most at home in a Boyapati Srinu film which allows him to be all this and much more. In Bobby Kolli’s latest, Daaku Maharaaj, Balakrishna is a do-gooder with a strong emotional core. He is a doting guardian of a young girl who seems to effortlessly put a smile on his face. And yes, he is also a saviour who saves an entire district from brutal oppression, wields fascinating weapons, kills hundreds of henchmen in innovatively gory ways, and says lines like, “If you shout, it is barking… if I shout…” and Thaman inserts a lion’s roar in the background score. Daaku Maharaaj is the quintessential Balakrishna film, but it is burdened by the hangover of a number of films including Rajinikanth’s Jailer, Kamal Haasan’s Vikram, and the ‘God of Masses’ own filmography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daaku Maharaaj</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daaku-maharaaj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daaku-maharaaj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Balakrishna’s resurgence in recent films such as Akhanda and Bhagawant Kesari can be attributed to filmmakers Boyapati Sreenu and Anil Ravipudi making the star more relatable to the masses beyond his larger-than-life quirks. While the ethos of a typical Balakrishna film has not changed drastically, the fresh narrative styles have breathed a new lease of life into time-tested templates. In Daaku Maharaaj, it is evident that director Bobby Kolli was keen on a new visual aesthetic to a star-led vehicle. The action is stylised and slick; there is a genuine effort at charismatic world-building and the ‘punch lines’ are minimal (going by the standards of popular Telugu masala potboilers). Hero worship is woven into the narrative rather than appearing forced. Despite these merits the film falls short, owing to its lack of conviction in the execution. It neither plays to the galleries nor embraces the new dictum wholeheartedly. A handful of sequences draw attention and can be termed paisa vasool, but the film on the whole is not satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daaku Maharaaj</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daaku-maharaaj-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:09:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daaku-maharaaj-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nandamuri Balakrishna struck a hat-trick with Akhanda, Veera Simha Reddy and Bhagavanth Kesari. Now, he is back with his next outing, Daaku Maharaaj, with director Bobby Kolli, aiming to make it four in a row. Balakrishna, fondly called Balayya by fans, is known for his over-the-top faction entertainers. Will he strike gold with Daaku Maharaaj? Govind Gujjar (Makarand Deshpande) sends a message to Nanaji (Nandamuri Balakrishna) that Baby Vaishnavi is in danger. Vaishnavi and her family face threats from local MLA, Thirumurthulu Naidu and his brother (Sandeep Raj) after they are caught cultivating cocaine on the pretext of tea production. Nanaji arrives as a driver and protects Baby Vaishnavi and her family from grave dangers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
