<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mufasa: The Lion King on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/mufasa-the-lion-king/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mufasa: The Lion King on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:09:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/mufasa-the-lion-king/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 22:09:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While watching Mufasa: The Lion King, all I could think about was this: 4 precious years of Barry Jenkins’ career were spent in front of Disney green screens and sound stages to not even create something madly original? Don’t get me wrong, I’m not against effects-driven or photo-realistically animated movies; visionaries like Peter Jackson and James Cameron have redefined the relationship between technology and storytelling over the years. But Disney? Another Lion King film? My viewing experience was laced with the frustration of realising that yet another Hollywood studio franchise was doing wasteful Hollywood things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:02:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mufasa is the prequel to the Disney&amp;rsquo;s iconic film The Lion King. However, the film takes a different route than a typical prequel, we also get to see a follow-up plotline for Simba, Nala and their kids along with what&amp;rsquo;s going on at Pride Rock aka Milele. The Hindi Dub remains as close to the original names and essence of the characters while also adding a bit of a twist. While Simba and his family remain the prideful ruling family of Pride&amp;rsquo;s land, Timon, Pumbaa and some supporting characters get a twist with the Hindi Dub adding more comedy to the screenplay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 12:50:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If the 2019 reboot of The Lion King, that came out 25 years after the original, also called The Lion King, taught us anything, it is that one should never tamper with anything that has made a place for itself not only in the hearts of the audience but also in cinema history. Mufasa: The Lion King, though not a reboot or remake, can be added to that list. Serving as a prequel to the 2019 film, it takes us back in time to when Mufasa and Taka — as Scar was once known — were young cubs roaming the plains together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:11:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were charmed in 1994. By the story of Simba the lion cub, son of Mufasa, King of the Pride Lands. Scar, the evil force, had provided dramatic confrontation. The freshness of the animated number Circle of Life and the energetic camaraderie of Hakuna Matata have remained on the charts since then. Director Barry Jenkins’ prequel therefore comes with high expectations of a heartwarming, musical entertainer. The screenplay by Jeff Nathanson gives a backstory to Mufasa who died early in the 1994 blockbuster. Who was Simba’s dad?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
