<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sookshmadarshini on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/sookshmadarshini/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sookshmadarshini on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 14:20:15 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/sookshmadarshini/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sookshmadarshini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sookshmadarshini-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 14:20:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sookshmadarshini-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For prying eyes, the most innocuous action might seem suspicious. Priyadarshini (Nazriya Nazim) is the one with a bit of nosy behaviour in the neighbourhood in which Sookshmadarshini is set. At times, she almost behaves like the kind of neighbour that no one would ever wish to have. We get an interesting character detail that she is a microbiology graduate, for whom a Sookshmadarshini (microscope) is a part of her trade. Just that her lens is trained more on her neighbour, rather than microbes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sookshmadarshini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sookshmadarshini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:43:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sookshmadarshini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first 20 minutes of Sookshmadarshini may be used as a textbook to learn the art of writing a setup. Writers Athul Ramachandran and Libin TB are preparing their viewer for a film that falls into an unusual genre but instead of rushing towards the plot, they take their time to focus on establishing their protagonist: Priyadarshini (Nazriya), a 20-something mother who admits to feeling bored of domesticity. She lives in a regular middle-class neighbourhood, filled with regulars who know everything about each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
