<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:51:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:51:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author Helen Fielding’s first novel about a single, thirty-something woman living in London was released in 1996. The novel was adapted into a movie in 2001, with the heroine of Bridget Jones’s Diary returning in a movie sequel titled Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason in 2004. American actress Renée Zellweger has starred as Bridget Jones in all four films based on Fielding’s writing, which, in part, is the writer’s homage to Jane Austen’s Pride and Prejudice. It’s no coincidence that Bridget’s love interest is called Mark Darcy, played by Colin Firth, who famously portrayed Mr. Fitzwilliam Darcy in the 1995 TV adaptation of Austen’s novel. The latest, Bridget Jones: Mad About The Boy, is the fourth film (the last was Bridget Jones’s Baby, from 2016) about the life and loves of Bridget Jones. Michael Morris directs a screenplay by Fielding, Dan Mazer, and Abi Morgan. The film explores themes of loss, resilience, and self-discovery while still delivering the trademark awkwardness and comedic situations that have defined Bridget’s character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:31:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bridget Jones Mad About The Boy explores a new chapter in the life of Bridget Jones after the death of Mark Dary. The film doesn&amp;rsquo;t do well for Renee Zellweger&amp;rsquo;s character as it continues to progressively not age throughout the series. However, the second half of the film focuses on a typical rom-com setting which works well for the film. It also brings more closure to all subplots and concerns that Bridget and her kids have. The film is as goofy and silly as earlier films in the series were and it is the nostalgia and emotional closure for the audience that keeps the film engaging. The film begins with Bridget going to visit Mark&amp;rsquo;s friends on his death anniversary. When he thinks about bailing her son reminds her, that it is the one day she leaves the house. At the party, it becomes obvious that even four years after his death she has not been able to move on, nor does she plan to do it. However, her friends demand that she return to work to be able to live a normal, healthy life. After recalling her father&amp;rsquo;s last wish that &amp;lsquo;she lives and not just survives after the death of her husband&amp;rsquo;, Bridget begins to take an interest in returning to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
