<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 21:12:25 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/guild/members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aditya Shrikrishna</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/aditya-shrikrishna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/aditya-shrikrishna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aditya Shrikrishna is a Independent Film Critic from Chennai. Aditya’s writings on cinema have appeared in The Hindu, Senses of Cinema, Frontline, OTTPlay, Mint Lounge, FiftyTwoDotIn, The New Indian Express, The Quint, The Federal, Vogue and Film Companion among others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ajay Brahmatmaj</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/ajay-brahmatmaj/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/ajay-brahmatmaj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ajay Brahmatmaj is a veteran film critic and author who reviews films in Hindi. He has previously been the film editor of Dainik Jagran and has also written for different newspapers and web portals. He now runs a YouTube channel called CineMahaul.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He has a keen interest in the history of Hindi cinema and has written books like Irrfan&amp;hellip; Aur Kuchh Panne Kore Rah Gaye, Irrfan: Echoes of Presence, Cinema Bas Cinema, Cinema Ki Soch, Cinema Samkaleen Cinema etc. He edits and publishes a monthly emagzine, CineMahaul, frequently participates in webinars, seminars, and discussions on Hindi cinema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Akhil Arora</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/akhil-arora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/akhil-arora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Akhil Arora covers entertainment &amp;amp; video games for Gadgets 360, covering series premieres, product &amp;amp; service launches and looking at movies from a global socio-political and feminist perspective. He also co-hosts the movie podcast The Long Take.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anmol Jamwal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/anmol-jamwal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/anmol-jamwal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anmol Jamwal is a content creator who shares his love for Indian films across languages on his YouTube channel, Having garnered an audience in the span of 5 years, with over 1 million subscribers, the channel has grown to form a community that discusses Indian films week in and week out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aswathy Gopalakrishnan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/aswathy-gopalakrishnan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/aswathy-gopalakrishnan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aswathy Gopalakrishnan is a film critic who writes for Silverscreen.in. She also worked as a film programmer with MAMI Mumbai Film Festival in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subha J. Rao</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/subha-j-rao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/subha-j-rao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Subha J Rao has loved the movies since she sat in a darkened makeshift auditorium as a child and watched a K Balachander classic come alive on a white cloth that doubled up as a screen. A journalist with over 27 years of experience, she has worked in The Indian Express and United News of India, New Delhi, from 1997 to 2002. She then joined The Hindu and had two stints there, from November 2002 to February 2015 and from January 2016 to May 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avinash Ramachandran</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/avinash-ramachandran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/avinash-ramachandran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Avinash Ramachandran has been an entertainment journalist for over seven years now, specializing in the review of films, series, shorts, and documentaries. His primary focus is on South Indian cinema, although he also regularly engages with Hindi and English films, as well as occasionally exploring foreign films. He has written for The New Indian Express, South First, and is currently writing for The Indian Express.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avinash Singh Pal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/avinash-singhpal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/avinash-singhpal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Avinash Singh Pal has been in the media world for almost a decade. He is presently working as Senior Correspondent at Bollywood Bubble. Previously he has worked for Amar Ujala, Dainik Bhaskar and Hindustan and also been a news anchor and radio jockey in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhawana Somaaya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/bhawana-somaaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/bhawana-somaaya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bhawana Somaaya is a film critic, columnist and author. She has been writing on cinema for&#xA;almost 50 years. She is the former editor of Screen and written biographies of superstars like&#xA;Hema Malini and Amitabh Bachchan. Her books are a point of reference for students studying cinema at Whistling Woods, Mumbai,&#xA;Manipal University, Mangalore and JNU, Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She is a classical dancer, a broadcaster, a podcaster and author of 19 books.&#xA;She has translated our honourable Prime Minister, Shri Narendra Modi’s Gujarati books Saakshi&#xA;Bhaav and Aankh Aa Dhanya Chhe into English as Letters to Mother and Letters to Self in 2020&#xA;and 2022 respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deepak Dua</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/deepak-dua/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/deepak-dua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deepak Dua is a Hindi Film Critic honored with the National Award for Best Film Critic. An independent Film Journalist since 1993, who was associated with Hindi Film Monthly Chitralekha and Filmi Kaliyan for a long time. The review of the film Dangal written by him is being taught in the Hindi textbooks of class 8 and review of the film Poorna in class 7 as a chapter in many schools of the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gopinath Rajendran</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/gopinath-rajendran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/gopinath-rajendran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gopinath Rajendran is an entertainment journalist and film critic from Chennai with nearly a decade of expertise in reviewing Tamil and English films and television shows. Currently contributing to The Hindu, he previously worked with The New Indian Express.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ishita Sengupta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/ishita-sengupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/ishita-sengupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ishita Sengupta is an independent film critic and culture writer with a keen focus on nonfiction work. Her writing is informed with gender, pop culture and politics and it has appeared in publications like The Indian Express, The Hindu Frontline, OTTplay among others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Janani K</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/janani-k/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 21:12:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/janani-k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Janani K has been an entertainment journalist for the past 10 years. Her primary focus is on South Indian cinema. However, she manages to catch up on popular movies in other languages as well. She started her career with Galatta magazine, while simultaneously pursuing M.Sc Electonic Media at Anna University. She joined Silverscreen as a full-time journalist after her post-graduation and has climbed the ladder slowly and steadily. Her tenure as a Kollywood correspondent at Deccan Chronicle helped her gain contacts. Not just film news, she also dabbled across different beats contributing to Culture and City pages in Chennai Chronicle. In 2017, she joined India Today as a Writer. Having spent seven years in the media company, she is now a Senior Assistant Editor managing the desk (including Bollywood), while managing the Regional Cinema section. Training new joiners and overseeing the day-to-day activities of the Desk is her everyday routine. Apart from reviewing, she also interviews film talents and writes opinion pieces on movies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keyur Seta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/keyur-seta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/keyur-seta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keyur Seta is a film journalist with close to 15 years of experience. He has been covering Hindi cinema extensively for the last 12 years and Marathi cinema since seven years. In the past, he has worked with brands like Zee Entertainment, Cinestaan.com and The Times Of India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kirubhakar Purushothaman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kirubhakar-purushothaman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kirubhakar-purushothaman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kirubhakar Purushothaman is a Principal Correspondent with News 18 and is based out of Chennai. He has been writing about Tamil cinema and OTT content for the past eight years across top media houses like India Today, Indian Express and Deccan Chronicle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kriti Tulsiani</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kriti-tulsiani/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kriti-tulsiani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kriti Tulsiani is an entertainment journalist and film critic for WION. She has previously worked with Times Now, ZoomTV and CNN News18 Digital. Apart from writing about cinema, she also covers lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kshitij Rawat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kshitij-rawat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kshitij-rawat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kshitij Rawat did not unleash himself to the world as a film critic, but such are the vagaries of destiny. He has been reviewing films and TV shows since 2017. Growing up in different parts of the country, he has been exposed to a variety of cultures, something that informs his criticism. He currently works at Lifestyle Asia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kunal Guha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kunal-guha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/kunal-guha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kunal Guha is a film critic and features writer with Mumbai Mirror.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manoj Kumar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/manoj-kumar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/manoj-kumar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Manoj Kumar R, a seasoned film writer, began in digital journalism in 2010. He honed his skills at Deccan Herald, The Week, and The Indian Express, and HT Media Group focusing on the South Indian film industry. Proficient in four South Indian languages, Manoj delves deep into regional cinema with insightful coverage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meena Iyer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/meena-iyer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/meena-iyer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meena Iyer has been the Editor of Bombay Times and a film critic with the TOI group for two decades. Currently she is a freelance writer for Hindustan Times. She has also co-written two books with Rishi Kapoor titled Khullam Khulla (Harper Collins) and Sonu Sood titled I&amp;rsquo;m No Messiah (Penguin Random House).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mihir Bhanage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/mihir-bhanage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/mihir-bhanage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mihir Bhanage is a film critic and has been reviewing films, majorly Marathi, for Times of India since 2014. Besides reviews, he is also an entertainment correspondent for Pune Times. As a viewer, he loves to watch films across genres and languages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monika Rawal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/monika-rawal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/monika-rawal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monika Rawal is a seasoned Entertainment Editor and Film Critic with over 19 years of experience in digital and print media. Having worked for organisations such as NFDC, Hindustan Times, Times of India, Dainik Bhaskar and Mid-Day, she has extensively written on Hindi cinema, besides also leading several marquee events involving celebrities from the world of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonika Singh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/nonika-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 13:16:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/nonika-singh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nonika Singh is a journalist, art, and film critic of considerable repute. She has been at the forefront of covering art, culture, and entertainment extensively, with a deep passion and profound knowledge of her domain. In particular, she excels in reviewing movies and profiling well-known personalities connected to the entertainment, visual, and performing arts. She writes for leading dailies in the country, including The Tribune and The Hollywood Reporter India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poulomi Das</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/poulomi-das/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/poulomi-das/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Poulomi Das is an independent film journalist, critic, editor, and programmer. Her writing on film has appeared in national and international publications including NY Mag, MUBI Notebook, Film Comment, India Today, Firstpost, The Swaddle, The Wire, Film Companion, The Federal, Mint Lounge, and GQ among others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priyanka Roy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/priyanka-roy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:28:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/priyanka-roy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Priyanka Roy heads the screen beat at The Telegraph t2. Based in Kolkata, she has 18 years of experience in film writing, which includes reviews, interviews, trend stories and opinion pieces. She writes on Hindi, English, regional Indian films and world cinema. When she isn&amp;rsquo;t watching something to review, she relaxes by watching true-crime documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renuka Vyavahare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/renuka-vyavahare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/renuka-vyavahare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Renuka Vyavahare is a film critic with one of India&amp;rsquo;s leading dailies, The Times of India and also a senior entertainment journalist with Bombay Times. She has been reviewing films for the Times Group for over a decade now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rohit Khilnani</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/rohit-khilnani/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/rohit-khilnani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rohit Khilnani is an entertainment journalist with more than two decades of experience. He currently does film interviews for Bollywood Hungama and reviews movies in a personal capacity. In the past he was Entertainment Editor for the NDTV Group, India Today Group, Times Internet and CNN-IBN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rohit Vats</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/rohit-vats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/rohit-vats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rohit Vats is a journalist, film critic, translator and a digital strategist with more than 14 years of experience. Currently, he is serving as the Editorial Head of DNA India (Zee Digital).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S. R. Praveen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/s.r.praveen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/s.r.praveen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working as a journalist with The Hindu since 2012. Writing reviews of Malayalam films weekly, longer pieces on Malayalam cinema and the industry as a whole, covering international film festivals including IFFK and IFFI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saibal Chatterjee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/saibal-chatterjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/saibal-chatterjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saibal Chatterjee is an independent film critic based in Delhi. His weekly reviews appear on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ndtv.com&#34;&gt;www.ndtv.com&lt;/a&gt;. He also writes on cinema for The Tribune and The Gulf Today newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sangeetha Devi Dundoo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sangeetha-devi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sangeetha-devi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sangeetha Devi Dundoo is a journalist and film critic with The Hindu, Hyderabad, with a focus on Telugu cinema. She has been reviewing films for nearly 13 years in her 25-year journalism career. She was part of the founding team of The Times of India, Hyderabad, and worked in the features section for nearly six years before moving to The Hindu. Growing up in Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, she now considers Hyderabad her home. She writes on cinema, fine arts, textiles and handlooms, fashion, environmental issues, city trends and occasionally, books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sanyukta Thakare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sanyukta-thakare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sanyukta-thakare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sanyukta Thakare is a film journalist &amp;amp; critic turned content creator who discusses the cultural and social impacts of cinema. Currently, she works at Mashable India, and also covers anime, Korean drama and other Western content. Previously, she has worked for The Free Press Journal and DNA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shamayita Chakraborty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/shamayita-chakraborty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 14:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/shamayita-chakraborty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shamayita is a journalist and film critic with over 15 years of experience. She has previously worked with Times Of India, OTTplay, Bangalore Mirror and Zee 24 Ghanta. She reviews and writes on Bengali, Hindi and English films and web series.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shilajit Mitra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/shilajit-mitra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/shilajit-mitra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shilajit Mitra is a film critic and journalist with The Hindu. Based in Mumbai, he has been writing on cinema for over seven years. He started out contributing reviews to the Times Now and Zoom websites; later, for five years, he worked as a critic for The New Indian Express. Currently, he reviews Hindi films and beyond for The Hindu. He also writes features and opinion pieces for the publication, and curates a fortnightly recommendations column called Screen Share. He loves talking films, on end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shubhra Gupta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/shubhra-gupta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/shubhra-gupta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shubhra Gupta, a senior columnist and acclaimed film critic at The Indian Express, boasts over 30 years of experience with her widely-read weekly review column. A prominent figure in India&amp;rsquo;s film criticism scene, she frequently attends global film festivals and has served on national and international juries. She curates and conducts the hugely popular platform, The Indian Express Film Club, in Delhi and Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;She has been a member of the Central Board Of Film Certification ( CBFC). She is the recipient of the prestigious 2012 Ramnath Goenka award that celebrates the finest in Indian journalism. Shubhra has authored two books&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;50 Films That Changed Bollywood 1995-2015&amp;rsquo; ( HarperCollins) and &amp;lsquo;Irrfan: A Life In Movies&amp;rsquo; ( PanMacMillan), a comprehensive tribute to the late actor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sonal Pandya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sonal-pandya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sonal-pandya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sonal Pandya is the Associate Producer for Times Now and Zoom, and earlier worked at Hindustan Times, and Cinestaan.com as deputy editor. Prior to becoming a film journalist, she worked as a CG artist and digital compositor in the animation industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Srinivasa Ramanujam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/srinivasa-ramanujam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/srinivasa-ramanujam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srinivasa Ramanujam is a Senior Assistant Editor with The Hindu, Chennai, and a primary film critic for Tamil cinema. His 15+ years of work experience includes being associated extensively The Hindu, The Times of India (Chennai), The Week, ET MadrasPlus and ChennaiOnline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Srivathsan Nadadhur</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/srivathsan-nadadhur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/srivathsan-nadadhur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Srivathsan Nadadhur is a senior entertainment journalist with over 11 years of media experience who writes about movies, literature, culture, and lifestyle and has contributed to The Hindu, Times of India, Deccan Herald, The News Minute and Film Companion in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sudhir Srinivasan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sudhir-srinivasan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sudhir-srinivasan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sudhir Srinivasan is the Entertainment Editor of the New Indian Express. He has previously written for The Hindu and The Times of India. He is known for his writing on South cinema, especially Tamil Films.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suhani Singh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/suhani-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/suhani-singh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suhani Singh is a journalist with over two decades of experience. Currently, she’s the Deputy Editor with India Today magazine, India’s leading news weekly, where she has been covering the entertainment industry as well reporting on culture and sports beats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sukanya Verma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sukanya-verma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sukanya-verma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mumbai-born and based Sukanya Verma is a senior film critic, music critic, columnist, features writer, quiz maker and columnist with rediff.com since 1999. She has contributed cinema columns to The Hindu as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sukhpreet Kahlon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sukhpreet-kahlon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/sukhpreet-kahlon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukhpreet Kahlon is the Artistic Director of South Asian Film Festival of Montreal and an Independent Film Critic. Her writing concentrates on film history, independent films and Punjabi cinema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suparna Sharma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/suparna-sharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/suparna-sharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suparna Sharma is a senior Independent Film Critic. She currently writes for The Week and Al Jazeera. Previously she was writing on films for Rolling Stone magazine and was the Resident Editor of The Asian Age, New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tanul Thakur</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/tanul-thakur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/tanul-thakur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tanul Thakur is a National Award-winning film critic and an independent journalist. A film critic for The Wire, he&amp;rsquo;s written features and opinion pieces for The Caravan, Open, Fountain Ink, GQ, and Yahoo! India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tatsam Mukherjee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/tatsam-mukherjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/tatsam-mukherjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tatsam Mukherjee has been working as a film journalist since 2016. Having contributed to the Indian Express, Mint Lounge, India Today, Open magazine, his byline has also appeared in foreign publications like Slate, Al Jazeera and Juggernaut. He is currently based in Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uday Bhatia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/uday-bhatia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/uday-bhatia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uday Bhatia is Film Editor with Mint Lounge in Mumbai. He was previously with Time Out Delhi and The Sunday Guardian. His work has appeared in GQ, The Caravan, Indian Quarterly and other publications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upma Singh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/upma-singh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/upma-singh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Upma Singh is a journalist with 17 years of experience in the field of entertainment and feature journalism. She has worked with Amar Ujala and Dainik Bhaskar , leading national hindi newspapers before joining Navbharat Times. She is an assistant editor at Navbharat Times, Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vishal Menon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/vishal-menon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/members/vishal-menon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vishal Menon is the Assoiciate Editor at The Hollywood Reporter, India. He was previously with Film Companion and The Hindu. He writes about Malayalam and Tamil Cinema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
