<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Viduthalai Part 2 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/viduthalai-part-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Viduthalai Part 2 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:38:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/viduthalai-part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Viduthalai Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:38:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Viduthalai Part 2, a film that leans more on thought than emotion, more on words than feelings, my favourite portion is a brief, tender exchange between Perumal (Vijay Sethupathi) and Mahalakshmi (Manju Warrier). They are united by their disillusionment with life and society. Mahalakshmi has almost adopted the appearance of a man (and we later learn why), while Perumal, when tentatively reaching out to her about the prospect of a relationship, stammers and stutters, unsure of himself. Vetrimaaran beautifully allows Mahalakshmi time to respond to Perumal&amp;rsquo;s proposal, time to think, time in which to give us a beautiful Ilaiyaraaja song. And when you hear his melody, love, expectedly, blooms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viduthalai Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 23:36:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vetri Maaran’s Viduthalai Part 1, told from the perspective of a new police constable Kumaresan (Soori), posted in a rural hillside Tamil Nadu village, explored the story of an extremist organisation named Makkal Padai and its head Perumal Vaathiyar (Vijay Sethupathi). Makkal Padai has a history, but when we entered the world in the first part, the conflict was immediate as the terrorist organisation had just bombed a passenger train killing and injuring several lives. The premise answered both ‘why and why now’ of the film’s existence. It ended with the arrest of Vaathiyar, aided by Kumaresan, who is on the brink of getting disillusioned with the government’s propaganda against the organisation. The effective first part left us with many questions about Vaathiyar and how it will affect Kumaresan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viduthalai Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:35:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first part of Viduthalai, you’d remember the long trek Kumaresan (Soori) undertakes to reach the camp where he is posted as a police constable for the first time. Even for a story that takes more than five hours to unfold, you’d remember the slow pace with which he treks across terrains, water bodies and hills to finally get to the top. Until today, I felt the pacing was intentional because we needed to understand how remote and challenging it was going to be for Kumaresan to work there. Narratively too, it was important for us to register the hostile terrain everyone in this movie was fighting over, right from the locals to the police and the mining corporation that wants to set up shop there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
