<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game Changer on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/game-changer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game Changer on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:34:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/game-changer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:34:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a film in which the leading man&amp;rsquo;s signature line is &amp;lsquo;I am unpredictable&amp;rsquo;, Game Changer feels as old as cinema itself. In fact, the plot of this film — stretching over an abominably long 165 minutes — is so stale that every second of it will remind you of some terrible movie you may have had the misfortune of sitting through in the past. Game Changer is vintage Shankar, which is more of a bad than a good thing these days. The man who once gave us films like Gentleman and Anniyan, Enthiran and Indian, has been stuck in a creative rut, recently illustrated by the torture fest called Indian 2. Game Changer is a definite improvement over Indian 2 but that isn&amp;rsquo;t saying much about a film that relies on every overused trope in the masala movie book — physical (over) acting, grating background score, expensively-shot but totally unnecessary songs and a story that goes here, there, everywhere&amp;hellip; and ultimately, nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:41:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it’s the repetition of certain ideas, or perhaps it’s the undeniable power of Shankar’s hit cinema, but it’s impossible not to think of his earlier works—his heyday, shall we dare call it—while watching Game Changer. A road grinding to a halt due to governmental apathy reminds you of Mudhalvan. A government authority dismantling corruption? That’s from the same film. There’s even a self-aware reference to Kadhalan as Ram Charan’s shoes perform a little jig during a song. A love-meter reminds you of Anniyan. When the hero lands out of a helicopter, it’s impossible not to think of Sivaji, especially with Jayaram’s character doing the signature tap on the villain’s shaved head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:29:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the monumental success of SS Rajamouli’s RRR, Game Changer marks Ram Charan’s return to a big solo release. Directed by Shankar, Game Changer is his first solo release and features him in dual roles, guaranteeing double dhamaka for the audience. After the debacle of Indian 2, Shankar is back with Game Changer, which marks his Telugu debut. Is it a &amp;lsquo;Game-Changing Day&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Game Over&amp;rsquo; for Shankar-Ram Charan duo? Let’s find out! Ram Nandan (Ram Charan) is an IAS officer battling anger issues. He is an honest, upright officer who doesn’t bend to corruption. As a high-ranking official, he wants to make Visakhapatnam corruption-free. Meanwhile, Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister Bobbili Satyamurthy (Srikanth), who so far has corrupted the government, undergoes a transformation and instructs his sons, Mopidevi (SJ Suryah) and Maavera Munimanikam (Jayaram), and his ministers to stop favouring anyone and run a corruption-free government for the next year while they remain in power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:51:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZT6Y4bHkjqY?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:25:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shankar has an unrelenting confidence in his socio-political conscience, and he seems to be constantly bothered about the ills around him. Nothing else explains his grip on the anti-corruption ideas, which fuels most of his films. After the disastrous Indian 2, Shankar’s Game Changer, starring Ram Charan, is another addition to his list of political films. The filmmaker not only holds onto his politics in Game Changer but also strongly believes in the old-school commercial entertainer where the film breaks to a song every twenty minutes. In a sense, this familiar screenplay formula works in the favour of Game Changer as you know what to expect from the film at any given point. It doesn’t pretend to be anything more than what it is. Hence, there is no room for disappointment with Game Changer. That said, Game Changer, at the end of the day, is a dated film that would have probably been fresh a decade back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:23:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When one looks at Shankar’s filmography, it is interesting how his mind doesn’t gravitate towards the easiest way to elevate the hero. Almost all of his leading men could have been typical straightforward police officers who take on the system. But instead, he makes them a small-time entrepreneur moonlighting as a Robin Hood, a young lover fighting for his love, an old revolutionary who wants to eradicate corruption, a journalist who becomes the chief minister, an NRI who returns to his homeland to weed out societal ills, and even a robot. But never a cop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Changer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:21:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/game-changer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At a pre-release promotional event, director Shankar mentioned how his new film, Game Changer, considers the audience’s diminishing attention spans, shaped by Instagram Reels, and delivers engaging sequences in quick succession. This is perhaps why two-hour 45-minute film feels like a patchwork of segments opting for hurried transitions rather than seamless segways. Is Shankar’s first Telugu film (his older Tamil films were massive hits in Telugu) fun? Yes, quite a bit. Do the face-offs between Ram Charan and SJ Suryah live up to the hype? Sure, there are clapworthy lines and segments. The bigger question is, beyond the instant gratification, will these segments, or the film, stand the test of time?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
