<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dragon on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/dragon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dragon on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 22:38:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/dragon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dragon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 22:38:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jCVN7093oso?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 23:49:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when a mistake you commit uproots the life of an already struggling person? How do you overcome this? Does it make you realise your mistake or does it push you into the depths of depression? Director Ashwath Marimuthu&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Dragon&amp;rsquo; is a film that provides definite answers to these questions. D Ragavan (Pradeep Ranganathan), a archetypal &amp;lsquo;good boy&amp;rsquo;, is a gold medallist in school. He confesses his love to a girl after he gets awarded the gold medal. However, she rejects him, stating that she sometimes prefers &amp;lsquo;bad boys&amp;rsquo;, who are unruly and roam around the school with gethu (swag). Cut to his college days, D Ragavan becomes Dragon because of the rejection and has 48 standing arrears. What he earned in college was the love of Keerthi (Anupama Parameswaran).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 23:21:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dragon has a protagonist who is insufferable for most of its runtime, which, more often than not, doesn’t work in the favour of movies. Pradeep Ranganathan as D Raghavan aka Dragon is one of those bullies in the engineering colleges, who believes being macho makes him a hero. He is an instantly off-putting personality. His college attendance is 2 per cent. He is notorious for his on-campus violence. He has several ‘cases’ against him in college. You get the drift. On top of it all, he has 48 backlogs, nearly all of the subjects in the course. He was not always like this. In school, he was the naive D Raghavan with a glorious progress report. He becomes Dragon when his school crush tells him that bad boys are the thing. Once Dragon gets out of his den, which is his college, he ends up becoming a nuisance to his friends, a failure to his girlfriend, and a fraud to his parents. When the girl breaks up with him, he takes a shortcut to become a successful person, but his mistake comes back biting when everything looks up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:57:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dragon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If one is good only because of the fear of repercussions, are they really good people? If one is disillusioned with the idea of being perfect, wants to live life on the fly, make mistakes and amends along the way, are they really bad people? Now, with most questions regarding the existential crisis of being a good person in a seemingly bad world, these also don’t have concrete answers. Director Ashwath Marimuthu attempts to tell a story of a guy who descends into the depths of depravity only to find the shortest of ropes to hold on and crawl back to redemption. A guy named D Ragavan aka Dragon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
