<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agni on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/agni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agni on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:35:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/agni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:35:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Indian tradition, fire alludes to love and conflict, devotion and anger, eternality and death. The ever-youthful element that demands sacrifice plays the central character in director Rahul Dholakia’s ode to the unstinting spirit of the firefighters. Capturing a daze’s multiple faces and colours, Dholakia removes the smokescreen that covers the firefighters’ work and opens a window into the lives of those who keep us out of its fury but whose services are not duly acknowledged by the system and society. The action takes us into the heart of the evacuation process, the drama unravels the sacrifices firefighters make and the thriller elements seek to find the answer to the source of the firestorm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:53:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hindi movies have played with fire several times before. Those with long memories will remember such films as the 1980 adventure ‘The Burning Train’, which may have picked up inspiration from an earlier Hollywood blockbuster ‘The Towering Inferno’, but those who fight the flames at the risk of their own lives, have never been in the limelight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is something that Rahul Dholakia’s ‘Agni’ seeks to correct. The film loses no time in placing its bets with the chief of a Mumbai fire station, Vithalrao Surve (Gandhi), who leads his band of braves from the front, as they go about dousing fires in congested buildings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 22:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help but be left with the feeling that there’s an enjoyable disaster film somewhere within Rahul Dholakia’s Agni, which surely owes a debt to The Burning Train (1980). There is more than one echo of the Ravi Chopra-directorial, where the spectacle is foregrounded by professional rivalry – Danny Denzongpa and Vinod Khanna’s in the 1980 film; emulated by Pratik Gandhi and Divyenndu’s characters in Dholakia’s directorial. The innate Bollywood melodrama after an unexpected death, the high-voltage social commentary and righteous anger fuel both spectacles. Both Chopra and Dholakia’s film balance a strong ensemble, offering everyone their moment, and yet Dholakia’s film fails to stick its landing. It might have to do with what Hindi films have become in 2024 – too self-conscious, cautious, and reverential towards any uniform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:22:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;इस फिल्म में एक फायरमैन जब यह कहता है तो उसकी यह बात कानों को चीरती हुई निकल जाती है। सच ही तो है। हम में से कितने होंगे जो किसी फायरमैन को पर्सनली जानते हैं? कितने होंगे जिन्हें उनकी निजी और वर्किंग ज़िंदगी के बारे में करीब से पता है? सच यही है कि ज्वाला से खेलने वाले जांबाज़ों के बारे में हम में से ज़्यादातर लोग नहीं जानते और इस सच का एक स्याह पहलू यह भी है कि हिन्दी सिनेमा में आज तक इन लोगों को केंद्र में रख कर एक भी फिल्म नहीं बनी। अमेज़न प्राइम पर आई राहुल ढोलकिया की यह फिल्म ‘अग्नि’ उसी कमी को दूर करती है और हमें दिखाती है कि ये ‘अग्नि-वीर’ भी हमारी-आपकी तरह इंसान हैं, लेकिन कुछ अलग जीवट वाले।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agni</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:17:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How refreshingly different. Writer-director Rahul Dholakia takes his camera into the life-saving heroism of firefighters, so far an unexplored subject in Hindi cinema. Cut through black smoke and scorching flames for a warm story on how Fire Chief Vittalrao Surve (Pratik Gandhi) and his colleagues respond with alacrity and put their lives on the line to save lives day in and day out. Vittal, Avni Purohit (Saiyami Kher), Jazz (Udit Arora) and Mahadev (Jitendra Joshi) are a team that fearlessly go in to bring out those trapped in a fire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
