<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vettaiyan on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/vettaiyan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vettaiyan on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:32:39 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/vettaiyan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 10:32:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Journalist-turned-director TJ Gnanavel proved his mettle with a hard-hitting second film, Jai Bhim, starring Suriya, Manikandan and Lijomol Jose. In Jai Bhim, despite having Suriya onboard, he played more of a supporting role to brilliant Manikandan and Lijomol Jose. His third film, Vettaiyan, features Rajinikanth, but the director promises to have a solid story that champions Thalaivar. Will Gnanavel be able to strike a balance? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out! Athiyan (Rajinikanth), Superintendent of Police, is all about successfully carrying out encounters against criminals. He believes that killing a person is justice for those who were wronged and is not willing to wait for the law to take its course. Sathyadev (Amitabh Bachchan), a retired judge, bats against extrajudicial killings. A police case and a major misjudgement by Athiyan bring him face-to-face with Sathyadev.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 08:28:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/f4Y9uP4v_ww?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:12:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Journalist-turned-director T. J. Gnanavel doesn’t seem to care much for any sort of filmmaking subtleties. It’s as though he enjoys dialling up the volume knob to underline his already-dramatic writing, and doesn’t let you rest until you feel the full weight of a scene’s emotions. This was obvious in the way he didn’t stop by just showing you a police officer dragging a beaten-up Manikandan K. into the back of a police jeep in Jai Bhim (2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:08:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All Rajinikanth films have some default settings. It doesn’t matter who directs him, they have to play by these rules or around it. Experimentations by the director are allowed but within the frame of the boilerplate. The success then comes down to how the proverbial ‘director’s touch’ syncs with the template of a superstar film.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With Vettaiyan, TJ Gnanavel has tried his best to weave a realistic social commentary around the quintessential superstar, and the result is a conspicuous mismatch of tone. While Gnanavel gets a lot of moments right, the excess of Superstar isn’t his strong zone. Thus, Rajinikanth’s heroic moments become perfunctory, like most of the things in the film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:05:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vettaiyan brings together two cinematic legends—Rajinikanth as Athiyan, a top cop delivering swift justice, and Amitabh Bachchan as Justice Sathyadev Bramhadutt Pande, who questions the very foundation of that justice. Director TJ Gnanavel sets up a thought-provoking premise that wrestles with themes of morality, justice, and redemption, but unfortunately, the film struggles to deliver a compelling narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the heart of Vettaiyan is Athiyan, a law enforcer who is celebrated by the media and the public for his efficiency in &amp;ldquo;solving&amp;rdquo; cases. When he&amp;rsquo;s tasked with eliminating a fugitive, he executes his mission within 48 hours, and society hails him as a hero. But the entry of Justice Sathyadev turns the narrative on its head. The justice&amp;rsquo;s presence forces Athiyan to confront an unsettling truth: Did he really kill the right man?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:02:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are always visual and grammatical cues to determine the origin of any kind of cinema. In India, it differs with language and region but there is one kind of image that is not exactly the pride of Tamil cinema. Simplistic and overused in the last thirty years, its progenitor is probably director Shankar though the image draws power from the long history of Tamil Nadu in post-independent India.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is the sight of protesting people, the sight of people pouring their emotions out to the TV media, news footage spilling over as a character on screen and people surrounding a terrible event or crime. They mean to add to the gravity of the situation. The severity of it all. It has appeared in many films and evolved to feature on the internet and social media. An indelible image from Tamil cinema, one that looks to quickfire solutions to sociopolitical issues, in which one man fights for the angry citizens populating these scenes. TJ Gnanavel uses these images in Vettaiyan, his third film, this one increasing the stakes by featuring Rajinikanth taking the law in his hands while also being responsible for its preservation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 07:58:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In among the best stretches of Vettaiyan, the friend of an accused—both hailing from the slums—is being interrogated for his assistance in facilitating the latter’s escape, and the police eagerly slap their biases on them. Director TJ Gnanavel quietly, and subtly captures the indignation of these two young men at various times, as they square up to the police forces. It takes a great line about friendship from Athiyan (Rajinikanth) to restore a bit of faith in the young man’s eyes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
