<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keyur Seta on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/keyur-seta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keyur Seta on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:54:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/keyur-seta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Follower</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/follower/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 18:54:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/follower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes Follower more interesting and intriguing is that it organically weaves a story of close friendship between three friends and perfectly joins the same with the political conflict. It also makes fine use of flashback. The story could have been narrated in a linear form and it still would have been likeable. But the back and forth narrative converts the film also into a mystery drama. The events that lead Raghu into becoming a staunch supporter of the star political leader is the biggest triumph of the film. The production value makes the film look more like a telefilm. The lack of proper resources is clearly visible. This, however, doesn’t turn out to be a major issue because of the strong content at hand. The film is also shot in a creative manner by cinematographer Saket Gyani. It is laced with a number of impressive long one-take shots. The one that takes the cake is between Raghu and Parveen when both are riding their respective two-wheelers while conversing. The background score is minimally used, which goes with the nature of the film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Diplomat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 10:09:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Shivam Nair’s The Diplomat tells the real story of an Indian lady Uzma Ahmed (Sadia Khateeb), a single mother. She falls in love with a Pakistani national Tahir (Jagjeet Sandhu) while working in Malaysia in 2017. He promises to marry her and help treat her daughter, who suffers from Thalassemia. However, after she lands in Pakistan, she sees the real face of Tahir. He takes Uzma to the deserted land of Khyber Pakhtunkhwa where she realizes that he is already married and also has a few kids. But that’s not all. Tahir repeatedly physically and sexually abuses Uzma before forcing her to marry him. Once by chance, Uzma gets to know that the only way to escape from there is by somehow reaching the Indian embassy in Islamabad and ask for help. She makes Tahir take her to the Indian embassy through some pretext and, when he and his friends are away, barges inside the embassy and begs for help. But JP (John Abraham), the Deputy High Commissioner at the embassy, doubts her intentions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sthal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sthal-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 08:43:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sthal-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;India is obsessed with marriages. Weddings take place all over the country in different regions and among different communities and they are celebrated like anything. However, even in today’s times in rural India, the idea of a girl’s forced arranged marriage still exists. Filmmaker Jayant Digambar Somalkar’s Sthal (A Match) boldly highlights this social evil. The movie takes place in a village in Maharashtra named Dongargaon and it revolves around Savita Daulatrao Wandhare (Nandini Chikte). She is in her Final year of Bachelor of Arts course and her specialization subject is Sociology. Her father (Taranath Khiratkar) and mother (Sangita Sonekar) wish to get her married off soon but she wants to study further.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 13:57:37 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Malegaon, a small little town in Maharashtra, has its own little film industry. It all began after the mid-1990s when local artistes over there started making parodies of iconic Hindi films. These films were made in minimal costs and with whatever resources available. Some examples of these include Malegaon Ke Sholay, Malegaon Ki Shaan, etc. Filmmaker Reema Kagti’s Superboys Of Malegaon is a fictionalized tale of Nasir Sheikh and his friends who started the crazy film industry in Malegaon. Starting off in 1997, the film tells the story of Nasir (Adarsh Gourav), who runs a video parlour in Malegaon. He struggles to attract audiences as he screens international films. The parlour opposite to theirs is doing well as it screens mainstream Hindi films. Nasir, one fine day, learns the trick of editing and starts compiling action sequences from different films and releases them as a single film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sangeet Manapmaan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sangeet-manapmaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 09:33:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sangeet-manapmaan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Actor Subodh Bhave’s directorial debut Katyar Kaljyat Ghusli (2015) turned out to be a spectacular affair. There were much expectations for his second film as a director Sangeet Manapmaan, not just because he is in the director’s chair. This film is also adapted from an old classic musical play, just like the 2015 movie. But this time, the end result turns out to be just a one-time watch. Sangeet Manapmaan is adapted from Krushnaji Prabhakar Khadilkar’s musical play of the same name, which was first staged way back in 1911. The story takes place in a kingdom in Maharashtra called Sangrampur in an unspecified era. The chief of army Kakasaheb (Shailesh Datar) expresses his wish to the queen of Sangrampur (Nivedita Saraf) to retire from his services because of his advanced age. Although the queen believes he is irreplaceable, she suggests Kakasaheb’s deputy Chandravilas (Sumeet Raghvan) as the next chief. Kakasaheb subtly disagrees with the queen as he believes, despite being a brave warrior, Chandravilas doesn’t possess the exact qualities to be the next chief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mukkam Post Bombilwadi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:11:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Paresh Mokashi’s Mukkam Post Bombilwadi is based on his own Marathi play of the same name. The story takes place in 1942 when World War II is in full swing. Adolf Hitler (Prashant Damle) is under pressure for not having won the war despite fighting it for years, especially from his wife Eva (Deepti Lele). Winston Churchill (Anand Ingle), the Prime Minister of Great Britain, is making things more difficult for him. Meanwhile, in Bombilwadi village in Maharashtra’s Konkan, Varvante (Vaibhav Mangle) heads a theatre group. He is struggling hard to rehearse for a play with the members of his troupe (Devendra Pem, Geetanjali Kulkarni and Ritika Shrotri). Vaidya Buwa (Sunil Abhyankar) and Bhaskar (Pranav Raorane), who are also a part of the theatre group, have made a bomb to blow up Britishers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maharaj</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/maharaj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:42:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/maharaj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The name of Karsandas Mulji isn’t heard often when one speaks of Indian social reformers that were active during the British Era. Filmmaker Siddharth P Malhotra’s Maharaj will perhaps make him a talking point to some extent as the film is based on his heroics in a bygone era. Produced by Yash Raj Films, Maharaj, which is streaming on Netflix, is based on the book of the same name written by Saurabh Shah in 2013. It narrates the story of Karsandas’ fight against an evil priest. The story starts off in a village in Gujarat in the 1820s where Karsandas, as a kid, questions everything, especially religious practices. He is sent to Bombay to his uncle’s place after he grows up (Junaid Khan). Karsan’s critical and revolutionary mind makes him a fearless journalist and a social reformer. He regularly writes about the evil social practices in Dadabhai Naoroji’s (Sunil Gupta) newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushtaini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushtaini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:39:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushtaini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of indie films are based on unexpected journeys that bring about a change in the film’s character(s) and provide a heartwarming message in the end. Director, actor and producer Vinod Rawat’s Pushtaini is also one such film but it succeeds in standing apart due to quite a few reasons. The story revolves around Bhupinder Rawat aka Bhuppi (Vinod Rawat). He is a struggling actor in Mumbai, who has just landed a role in a film starring the famous actor Ankur Bhatia (Rajkummar Rao) for a small sum. If this wasn’t enough, his friend (?) Sumit (Nitin Goel) shows him a video of his sex scandal that happened while he was drunk recently. Bhuppi has no idea of him indulging in such an act. But now Sumit asks for Rs 8 lakhs from him, else he threatens to make the video viral.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paradise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:37:03 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paradise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Prasanna Vithanage’s Paradise is a Sri Lankan-Indian joint venture produced by Newton Cinema and presented by Mani Ratnam’s Madras Talkies. The movie is a tri-lingual in English, Sinhala and Malayalam. Paradise tells the story of a couple from Kerala, Kesav (Roshan Mathew) and Amritha (Darshana Rajendran), who visit a hill station in Sri Lanka to celebrate their fifth wedding anniversary. Their trip coincides with the mass protests in April 2022 after the country declares bankruptcy. Hence, there are agitations at various places for basic necessities of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:35:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Nikhil Nagesh Bhat’s ambitious action saga Kill is a first not just because of the violence and gore it projects in Hindi cinema but also in terms of cinematic finesse. After going through this ‘ride’, one can vouch that the makers succeeded in their ‘mission’. Kill revolves around the love story between the commando Amrit Rathod (Lakshya) and Tulika (Tanya Maniktala). The former returns from an army camp after days and gets to know that Tulika’s father Baldeo Singh Thakur (Harsh Chhaya) has planned her engagement with someone else and that too the very next day in Ranchi. Amrit takes his colleague and close friend Viresh (Abhishek Chauhan) to Ranchi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stree 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/stree-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:33:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/stree-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Amar Kaushik’s Stree was about the villagers of Chanderi fighting against a female evil spirit called Stree, who attacks and takes away the men residing in the village. After a lot of twists and turns, the men are freed in the end and Stree vanishes after her long braid is cut. But in the end, the viewers are given a hint that the mysterious girl with no name (Shraddha Kapoor) is a witch after she leaves the village. The story of Stree 2 continues a few years later when Chanderi is a peaceful place. Vicky (Rajkummar Rao) and his best friend Bittu (Aparshakti Khurana) are leading a happy-go-lucky life, except that the former is still waiting for the girl with no name (Shraddha) as he loves her. Their buddy Jana (Abhishek Banerjee) is in Delhi studying to become an IAS officer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dharmaveer 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dharmaveer-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:30:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dharmaveer-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Pravin Vitthal Tarde’s Dharmaveer: Mukkam Post Thane (2022), the first film in the series, spoke about the rise and the greatness of the late Shiv Sena leader Anand Dighe, who was from Thane. The film was a good biopic that also worked as a commercial entertainer with a fine act from Prasad Oak as Dighe. As the protagonist passes away at the end of the first film, one wondered what the film’s sequel, Dharmaveer: Mukkam Post Thane 2, would have in store. As it turns out, the movie is nothing but a 157-minute long campaign for the upcoming assembly polls in Mahahrashtra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navra Maza Navsacha 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/navra-maza-navsacha-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 21:28:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/navra-maza-navsacha-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is quite common for movies to not live up to its exciting trailer. It is extremely rare for the opposite to happen. Sachin Pilgaonkar’s Navra Maza Navsacha 2 is that rare film that turns out to be many times better than its trailer. In other words, the film’s promo was misleading, but in a good way. Navra Maza Navsacha 2 is the sequel to the iconic and successful Navra Maza Navsacha (2004), which starred Sachin Pilgaonkar and Supriya Pilgaonkar in lead roles. The film ended with Vakratund aka Vacky (Sachin) somehow managing to fulfill his late father’s vow of visiting the Ganesh temple in Ganpatipule naked. He was pushed for the same by his wife Bhakti (Supriya). The couple also earns Rs. 8 crores as they help the police nab the criminal Babu Kalia (Pradeep Patwardhan).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 21:46:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First things first. I am not a fan of Pushpa: The Rise, the first film in filmmaker Sukumar’s franchise. I found it lagging behind in storytelling, performance of the lead actor and filled with quite a few problematic moments. However, I am pleasantly surprised to find Pushpa 2: The Rule not only better than part one but also a paisa vasool entertainer. The first film ended with Pushpa Raj (Allu Arjun) becoming a large force in the world of red sandalwood smuggling. In the end, he marries his lady love Srivalli (Rashmika Mandanna) while his nemesis in the form of the cop Bhanwar Singh Shekhawat (Fahadh Faasil) vows to destroy Pushpa for his crimes and the insult meted out to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All We Imagine as Light</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:04:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/all-we-imagine-as-light-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mumbai has not only been one of the most featured cities in Indian films but it is also explored as a subject over the decades. Many a times, the dark underbelly of the city is brought to light. Filmmaker Payal Kapadia’s worldwide acclaimed feature film debut All We Imagine As Light (Malayalam along with some usage of Hindi and Marathi) also shows the bitter side of Mumbai. But it, for a change, doesn’t feature the criminal side of the city in any way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:31:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rohit Shetty’s cop sagas started with the brilliant Singham (2011). It was obvious for him to bring out a sequel to it. But Singham Returns (2014) turned out to be just an average fare. His latest and third outing in the series, Singham Again, is better than the 2014 film. Hence, it keeps alive his Cop Universe, which also contains the enjoyable Simmba (2018) and Sooryavanshi (2021).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the pre-climax scene in Sooryvanshi, Bajirao Singham (Ajay Devgn) vows to finish off the terrorist Omar Hafiz (Jackie Shroff), who is hiding in Kashmir. As fate would have it, Singham soon gets posted in Kashmir and during the start of Singham Again, he captures Omar in an operation. Omar warns Singham that he will have to deal with a new evil force.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boong</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/boong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:39:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/boong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aijaz Khan’s Hamid and Danish Renzu’s Half Widow are the names that easily come to my mind when it comes to movies about husbands going missing. But both the aforementioned films have the backdrop of the political crisis in Kashmir. This is where filmmaker Lakshmipriya Devi’s Manipuri movie Boong stands apart. It is more of a personal story of a boy whose father goes missing not due to any political tensions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yek Number</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yek-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 22:59:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yek-number/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago, we saw the release of Dharmaveer 2, in which a deceased political hero, Anand Dighe, was used to glorify and popularize Maharashtra’s current Chief Minister Eknath Shinde. Now, the same kind of propaganda has become the core of another Marathi movie. Titled Yek Number, the film aims to glorify Raj Thackeray, the chief of Maharashtra Navnirman Sena (MNS).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As one finally leaves the cinema hall after this 160-minute saga, one just wonders whether, after Hindi cinema, Marathi too will regularly churn out political propaganda films.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
