<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manoj Kumar on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/manoj-kumar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Manoj Kumar on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 08:46:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/manoj-kumar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mithya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 08:46:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mithya is an intimate story of a young boy struggling to make sense of his life, which has been shattered into countless pieces after his parents pass away. It marks director Sumanth Bhat&amp;rsquo;s feature film debut. Previously, he helmed the Kannada web series &lt;em&gt;Ekam&lt;/em&gt;, also co-produced by Rakshit Shetty. Mithya sheds light on the internal turmoil of an 11-year-old boy, Mithun. Taken in by his aunt’s family after his mother dies by suicide — leaving him and his younger sister orphaned — he is uprooted from Mumbai, where he was born and raised, and placed in the slow, quiet countryside of Udupi. He prefers to be called Mithya, but adjusting to his new reality is far from easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brutalist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-brutalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 13:46:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-brutalist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you saw the poster for The Brutalist, featuring Adrien Brody squinting his eyes, staring straight at you in a low-angle shot, cigarette in mouth, with streaks of fire flying across, you might take him for an Italian-American gangster. Especially since The Brutalist sounds like the perfect title for a gangster flick, set in late 1950s America, adding to its vibe as the ultimate land of freedom and wild wealth. But The Brutalist isn’t that. It’s about architecture — big, heavy, concrete-and-steel stuff. These imposing structures mirror the post-World War II psyche. For those untouched by the war’s direct traumas, these brutalist buildings might feel cold and uninviting, even ugly. But for those who have endured the dehumanising horrors of war, they represent something deeply intimate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nayanthara: Beyond the Fairy Tale</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nayanthara-beyond-the-fairy-tale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 17:12:39 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nayanthara-beyond-the-fairy-tale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Nayanthara&amp;rsquo;s 40th birthday, Netflix unveiled a documentary series, Nayanthara: Beyond the Fairy Tale, chronicling her journey in the film industry. The series opens with her disappointment over not securing permission to hold her dream wedding at the Tirupati temple and transitions to her eventual wedding at a picturesque beachside glasshouse, attended by the who’s who of Indian cinema.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, just before the documentary’s release, Nayanthara made headlines by issuing a strongly worded letter addressing Tamil star Dhanush . She accused him of holding a grudge against her and her husband, Vignesh Shivan, and alleged that he denied permission to use footage and songs from the movie Naanum Rowdy Dhaan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhairathi Ranagal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhairathi-ranagal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 19:37:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhairathi-ranagal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shivarajkumar&amp;rsquo;s portrayal of Bhairathi Ranagal in the 2017 movie Mufti was a monumental success. His iconic look—featuring coloured khadi vestis and shirts—became a trendsetter, even inspiring Nandamuri Balakrishna&amp;rsquo;s style in Veera Simha Reddy. It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that the filmmakers were tempted to delve deeper into the character and cater to the audience&amp;rsquo;s appetite for more. After all, the market rarely gets it wrong, right? Fast forward seven years and director Narthan brings us Bhairathi Ranagal, the origin story of this beloved character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanguva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanguva/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 11:59:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanguva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A characteristic in all of director Siva&amp;rsquo;s movies that I strongly dislike is the lack of subtlety in emotions and reactions. Everything is loud—and sometimes even louder than Boyapati Srinu&amp;rsquo;s films. But if you can look past this trait, Kanguva might just be one of the most cinematic spectacles you’ve experienced in theatres in a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For audiences to connect with a character and their struggles, the actors portraying them must commit wholeheartedly. No matter how trivial a scene may appear, if actors fully dedicate themselves, even the toughest audience will eventually buy into it. Take, for example, Christian Bale in American Psycho—he convinces you that Patrick Bateman would actually drive an axe through the face of a colleague who enjoys slightly finer things. You don’t question the logic; you marvel at the madness. That&amp;rsquo;s the power of an actor fully committing to their role, embodying their character&amp;rsquo;s beliefs and emotions without judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amaran</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/amaran/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:05:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/amaran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amaran is based on the life of Major Mukund Varadarajan, who died during an anti-terror operation in Jammu and Kashmir in 2014. Biopics like this come with a unique challenge: since audiences already know the outcome, there’s little room for surprises. Directors often leverage the emotional depth of such stories to create resonance, sometimes stirring complex emotions or evoking our deepest fears. Filmmaker Rajkumar Periasamy, as expected, focuses on these emotional elements, ultimately leaving the audience with a deeper understanding of the human conflict hidden beneath layers of turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lucky Baskhar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/lucky-baskhar-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:02:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/lucky-baskhar-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While promoting his latest movie, Lucky Baskhar, director Venky Atluri claimed that one of his biggest strengths is his talent in screenwriting. However, those closely following his filmography would tell you that his ability to assemble a stellar cast is his greatest asset. He once again showcases this strength with Lucky Baskhar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dulquer Salmaan is pitch-perfect as Baskhar Kumar, a working-class bank employee. In the late 80s, Baskhar, like millions of his countrymen, firmly believes that he could overcome his financial struggles by holding an honest, steady job. He is dedicated to his role as a cashier, showing up to work on time every day, the first to arrive and the last to leave. Known for his loyalty, respect for others, and charm, Baskhar embodies the ideal Indian man personality. He works hard for three years in hopes of earning a promotion that could alleviate his family’s middle-class challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:10:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Director Amal Neerad&amp;rsquo;s latest movie Bougainvillea is a slow-burning thriller that offers more strengths than weaknesses in its entertainment value. Set against the backdrop of an unreliable memory, the film borrows elements from classics like Memento and The Usual Suspects, while crafting a uniquely Malayalam narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What sets Bougainvillea apart is Neerad’s ability to command attention, even with minimal marketing. Filling half a theatre on a Thursday morning in Bengaluru for a Malayalam film speaks volumes about the anticipation surrounding Neerad’s projects, a testament to his loyal fanbase and established reputation. The film itself lives up to expectations, offering fans signature Amal Neerad moments: slow-motion sequences, intense visuals, and an atmospheric score by Sushin Shyam that keeps the tension simmering throughout.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:05:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vettaiyan brings together two cinematic legends—Rajinikanth as Athiyan, a top cop delivering swift justice, and Amitabh Bachchan as Justice Sathyadev Bramhadutt Pande, who questions the very foundation of that justice. Director TJ Gnanavel sets up a thought-provoking premise that wrestles with themes of morality, justice, and redemption, but unfortunately, the film struggles to deliver a compelling narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the heart of Vettaiyan is Athiyan, a law enforcer who is celebrated by the media and the public for his efficiency in &amp;ldquo;solving&amp;rdquo; cases. When he&amp;rsquo;s tasked with eliminating a fugitive, he executes his mission within 48 hours, and society hails him as a hero. But the entry of Justice Sathyadev turns the narrative on its head. The justice&amp;rsquo;s presence forces Athiyan to confront an unsettling truth: Did he really kill the right man?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
