<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein S02 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein S02 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:56:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:56:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first season of ‘Yeh Kaali Kaali Aankhein’ became an addictive watch in the way it bent one of the oldest genres in the book: being an obsessive lover is not just a male prerogative; women can do it just as well, if not better. It made up for all its nods to hoary Hindi movie heavies who lived in palaces overrun by armed goons, governed by old-style off-with-their-heads villainy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:17:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In January 2022, the Netflix series Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein introduced us to an unusual drama. The show, set in a small town, revolved around Vikrant (Tahir Raj Bhasin), who uncomfortably finds himself to be the object of affection for a gangster politician&amp;rsquo;s daughter Purva (Aanchal Singh). Instead of marrying his college sweetheart Shikha (Shweta Tripathi), he finds himself tied by matrimony to someone he doesn&amp;rsquo;t love. Sidharth Sengupta&amp;rsquo;s series took Vikrant to his limit as he found himself hiring a hitman to get rid of Purva. Now, nearly three years later, the series returns to pick up where it left off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yeh Kaali Kaali Ankhein S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 18:45:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/yeh-kaali-kaali-ankhein-s02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recap of Season 1: Purva (Anchal Singh), daughter of ruthless neta Akheraj Awasthi (Saurav Shukla), a don-like figure with the authorities at his beck and call and an army of goons, has always obsessed over and been a thorn in the flesh of good boy Vikrant Singh Chauhan (Tahir Raj Bhasin). To add to his misery, Vikrant’s father (Brijendra Kala) has always been a servile, loyal employee of the Awasthis, afraid to go against Akheraj even if it means pushing his son towards Purva. Vikrant had instinctively and steadfastly spurned Purna’s friendship even in school and could heave a sigh of relief only when she was packed off to the UK. He had a dream future planned with Shikha (Shweta Tripathi), the love of his life, when Purva returned as an adult, obsession intact and ready to claim him as hers once again. With Akheraj willing to go to any lengths to get her what she desires, getting rid of Purva was Vikrant’s only way out of a marriage he dreaded. It was, unwittingly, Vikrant’s first step towards turning himself into an unrecognisably dark person, no different from the Awasthis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
