<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shilajit Mitra on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/shilajit-mitra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shilajit Mitra on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 08:15:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/shilajit-mitra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dupahiya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dupahiya-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 08:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dupahiya-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gajraj Rao can act in his sleep. Quite literally. An agreeably slapstick moment in the new Prime Video comedy series Dupahiya finds Rao’s character, a kindly but superstitious school principal, snoring away on a cot, making sweet music with those silly, rumbling, guttural sounds. Rao has the training of theatre, of engaging a crowd with the bare tools of physicality and behaviour, and is so warm and winsome a comedian that we tend to forget his nastier roles (he played the menacing, mysterious caller in 2008’s Aamir). Perhaps Dupahiya could have harnessed Rao’s lurking nastiness to lend itself some zing. Built around a stolen motorcycle in a village, this is a ‘Panchayat’ lite, a sweet, soporific series that passes the time, exceedingly flaky and forgettable. Director Sonam Nair, who made the charmingly zany short film Khujli once upon a time, is decidedly out of her depth in the rural setting. The writing (by Chirag Garg and Avinash Dwivedi) is vacant and amateurish, the texture crumbly and second-hand. The oddball cast exhausts its whimsy in the first three episodes; indulged for six more, they verge on annoying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dabba Cartel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dabba-cartel-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 08:08:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dabba-cartel-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shabana Azmi is the fiery queenpin of a female outfit. They ply a disreputable trade. Her underlings feel the heat of her glare. She suffers no fools. I’m talking, of course, about a film called Mandi, directed by the late, great Shyam Benegal and released in 1983. Its coolness remains unsurpassed, 42 years on. Dabba Cartel, a new Netflix crime series with Azmi again at the helm, tries its best to be cool. Co-created by Shibani Akhtar, the show has a novel core: a home chef’s dabba (tiffin) delivery business spirals into a perilous drug operation. The pin-balling narrative is tugged along over seven episodes. The characters are stock, but, coming at you in numbers, they keep up a busy rhythm, like players on a revolving stage. It has the mark of an Excel production: ample efficiency, not a lot of excellence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hisaab Barabar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/hisaab-barabar-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:11:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/hisaab-barabar-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some films suffer from a surfeit of ambition. Others—like Ashwni Dhir’s Hisaab Barabar—have none to begin with. A middling comedy about the middle class, it tracks a common man’s crusade against fraudulent banking practices. A modest, toothless satire, the film boasts sitcom staging and visuals, lacking cinematic bite. No wonder it’s streaming on ZEE5, a platform with a near-magnetic affinity for mediocrity. It’s like one of those spec scripts that lie around in production offices gathering dust; until, one day, for some inexplicable reason, they are hurriedly greenlit. Radhe Mohan Sharma (R Madhavan) is a senior ticketing inspector with the Indian Railways. Blessed with an accountant’s eye (and ethics), he spends hours pouring over his bank statements, fishing for discrepancies. When an alarmingly high sum of ₹27.50 doesn’t tally up in his books, Radhe raises a complaint with the bank. The officials he corners first feign ignorance, then try to fob him and other customers off with compensatory gifts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paatal Lok S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/paatal-lok-s02-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reunions are always bittersweet. And then there is Sudip Sharma’s idea of a reunion. In the new season of Paatal Lok, Hathi Ram Chaudhary (Jaideep Ahlawat) first catches sight of his old pal Ansari (Ishwak Singh) at a morgue. Ansari was once his junior at their inconsequential Outer Jamna Paar police station. Now, though, as a hotshot IPS officer working the big cases, he commands respect. Hathi Ram stands off and stares, resisting contact. A team-up is imminent, but the morbidity of the setting makes it poignant. The Hathi Ram-Ansari friendship is our anchor in Season 2. Created by Sudip Sharma, the first season of Prime Video’s crime series was a pandemic hit—a grim, coruscating procedural, kaleidoscopic in its scale and scope, picking up hot-button topics like caste violence and Islamophobia. The second season is subtler and less combative, subduing commentary in favour of human relations. At times, it becomes a touching meditation on male bonds. When Hathi Ram’s name comes up during a briefing, Ansari corrects his higher-up that he is not an ‘SHO’, just an ordinary inspector. He isn’t being cruel or conceited, just realistic about their differing vantage points.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Warrant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:20:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the 1920s, a young George Orwell was posted in Burma, as part of the Indian Imperial Police. In a famous essay titled A Hanging — written, in all likelihood, from lived experience — Orwell describes the morning of a prison execution. His unnamed narrator contrasts the minutiae of prison life with the moral shock of capital punishment. “It is curious, but till that moment I had never realized what it means to destroy a healthy, conscious man,” he writes. There is a touch of the young Orwell in Sunil (Zahan Kapoor), a rookie jailer finding his feet in Tihar, Asia’s largest and most dreaded prison. Set in the 80s, Vikramaditya Motwane and Satyanshu Singh’s series is based on the non-fiction book Black Warrant: Confessions of a Tihar Jailer. The real Sunil Gupta, who co-authored the book with journalist Sunetra Choudhury, was a former superintendent of Tihar, while doubling as its press relations officer and legal adviser. In his decades at the jail, Gupta oversaw the execution of several high-profile criminals, including Delhi child murderers Billa-Ranga and Kashmiri separatist Maqbool Bhat. He spoke candidly to Choudhury about his experiences. Once you put a face to the stat, how long can you look away?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:14:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“I won’t allow anything more than a friendship,” decrees Anila (Kani Kusruti), a very mom thing to say. She is sizing up a tall, sweet boy, Srinivas (Kesav Binoy Kiron), who’s drawn her daughter’s affections at their elite, hillside boarding school. The girl, Mira (Preeti Panigrahi), stands at the door and listens. The camera mimics her watchful gaze. It is a simple domestic intervention, yet it thrums with suspense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a charged, decisive moment in Shuchi Talati’s Girls Will Be Girls, which won two prizes at the Sundance Film Festival. Anila is a fussy, controlling parent, turning up annually from Haridwar to tide Mira through her exams. She is also lonely and emotionally desolate. Her choice of dress to meet Srinivas gives it away: a bright, oversized pink top with puffed shoulders, likely purchased at a younger age.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Sabarmati Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-sabarmati-report-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:25:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-sabarmati-report-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an interview that went viral ahead of The Sabarmati Report, actor Vikrant Massey, briefly turning political analyst, reflected on the state of the nation. “People say that Hindus are in danger, that Muslims are in danger. No one is in danger; everything is going fine. This is the best country to live in the world,” he declared in a podcast. The nervous naivety of Hindi film actors ahead of a controversial release is always enlightening to witness. It’s a balancing act no gymnast or slackliner can fathom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 10:19:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a time, not long ago, when Hindi blockbuster cinema could stand on its own — distinguishable, say, from mythological soap operas and tacky non-fiction programming on satellite TV. But the laziness and opportunism of the last few years have all but vaporized that distinction. It leaves the theatre-going audience in two minds. Adipurush (2023) was laughably inept yet insistently pious and grim. The same applies to Singham Again, ostensibly an action potboiler and an Avengers-like ‘team-up’ movie but playing like an ad for the tourism ministry’s Ramayana trail.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Sitara</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/love-sitara-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:21:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/love-sitara-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Love, Sitara begins with a nod to Anna Karenina: “All happy families are alike; each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way,” says Sitara (Sobhita Dhulipala). Unlike Leo Tolstoy’s great novel — whose opening line these words are — the writing in Vandana Kataria’s film isn’t as quotable, though it tries hard. You can assemble a slim volume of pithy self-help slogans from Abbas and Hussain Dalal’s dialogue: “Happiness lies in honesty.” “Dysfunction means they are making an effort.” “I’ll fix myself, before I can fix my relationships.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:18:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Movies can shape us in silly but significant ways. Growing up in the 1990s, for instance, I developed an irrational and premature fear of foreign travel. This had little to do with any growing awareness of geopolitical realities and everything to do with a schlocky Bollywood film starring Sridevi and Sanjay Dutt. Directed by Mahesh Bhatt, Gumrah (1993) — a jailbreak drama set between Mumbai and Hong Kong — was shivery B-movie fun, and it left me with an enduring anxiety. If I clutched my cabin luggage a little too cautiously on my first international flight, nervously looking over my shoulders, I had Bhatt and the duplicitous face of Rahul Roy to thank.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ulajh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ulajh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 10:26:18 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ulajh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What sort of a spy movie is Sudhanshu Saria’s Ulajh? It begins as a Raazi (2018) in pantsuits: patriotic female protagonist, driven by loyalty and legacy, enlists to serve her country on foreign turf. Indo-Pak diplomatic relations, as fraught and fragile as they were in 1971, inform the narrative stakes. Both films hail from Junglee Pictures, and the editor, in each case, is Nitin Baid. If that weren’t enough, the new film even has a song with ‘watan’ in its title — plastered, ineffectually, over the opening credits and thereby fast forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gyaarah Gyaarah</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/gyaarah-gyaarah/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 10:22:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/gyaarah-gyaarah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gyaarah Gyaarah, out on ZEE5 and adapted from the Korean series Signal, is a time-warping thriller of the dour, soulless kind. Tumbling across timelines, director Umesh Bist always makes sure to hold his audience’s hand. Bland letters appear on screen to indicate the precise date, year, location. Lest we lose our bearings, the pop-culture references are even more plain: Dil for 1990, Kapoor &amp;amp; Sons for 2016. This is a fairly unimaginative way to summon a period, to evoke a mood. It’s unlike the scene in Back to the Future where Doc in the 1950s exclaims to Marty, who’s traveled back from the 80s, “Ronald Reagan! The actor?! Then who’s vice president? Jerry Lewis?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wild Wild Punjab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wild-wild-punjab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 10:30:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/wild-wild-punjab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was evident, even before Varun Sharma clambered onto the roof of a car, unfastened his fly and shot out a tall projectile of piss, that Wild Wild Punjab was not a serious film. But is it even that wild? The aforementioned scene is probably the looniest thing that happens — a nod, perhaps, to Fukrey 3, which had an entire pee-based plotline dedicated to Sharma. The rest of Simarpreet Singh’s film is oddly strained and docile, a blur of ham-fisted hi-jinks and inane one-liners. “Respect, dude,” someone tells Sharma’s character, a compliment I cannot extend to the film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barzakh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/barzakh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 10:28:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/barzakh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The past is not dead. It’s not even past,” wrote William Faulkner. Everything in Barzakh — images, ideas, sounds — responds to that famously Faulknerian sentiment. The title refers to a kind of limbo, an earthly purgatory, where the dead move amidst the living. The six-part series has been shot in the ravishing Hunza Valley, in Northern Pakistan, and is drenched in a despairing, deciduous beauty. Characters converse in pseudo-spiritualistic fragments and heartsick hokum (and also do shrooms). Mountains, as usual, hold the key to everything. Watching the series, I found myself nervously wondering if, across the border, the director Imtiaz Ali was paying attention. What if he feels a little bested, and takes it up as a challenge?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
