<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taaza Khabar S02 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/taaza-khabar-s02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taaza Khabar S02 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:48:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/taaza-khabar-s02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taaza Khabar S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/taaza-khabar-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:48:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/taaza-khabar-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Taaza Khabar Season 2, there’s little that’s taaza (fresh). There’s ambition, but not enough drive. There are those next big things, but not the smoothest ways forward. A show, often oscillating between past, present and future, lacks the ‘vardaan’ (blessing) of staying afloat - something that, both the series and Bhuvan Bam’s character Vasant Gawde desperately need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who’ve watched the first season will understand when we say - far bizarre things happen to Gawde in the follow-up. In the first season, a sanitation worker stumbles upon his magical powers of getting updates about future events and his life changes overnight. But everything that rises must eventually have a downfall. The new season takes off from where the last one ended - only this time, the ‘taaza khabar’ is that of Vasya dying. Will he rise from the dead? Or can he possibly avert his death?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taaza Khabar S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/taaza-khabar-s02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 10:53:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/taaza-khabar-s02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bhuvan Bam&amp;rsquo;s Vasant Gawde, Mr. Vardaan to the world owing to his ability to see events before they come to pass, is back seeking to make a killing from the prescient news updates that he receives on a mobile phone app. This time around, the Taaza Khabar protagonist is either on the backfoot or, worse still, down on his haunches. His plight necessitates desperate measures as he faces new challenges hurled at him by a man who will stop at nothing. But the show, notwithstanding a series of dramatic confrontations, struggles to skirt around the pitfalls of an idea that is beginning to wear thin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
