<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greedy People on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/greedy-people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greedy People on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 14:28:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/greedy-people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Greedy People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/greedy-people-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 14:28:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/greedy-people-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A brisk opening that holds some promise, a meandering middle that scuttles much of the early potential, and an overly rushed climax make Greedy People a mixed bag – an action comedy that never kicks into top gear despite all the scampering that it does in search of a sweep spot. Greedy People, premiering in India exclusively on Lionsgate Play and available in English and Hindi, is frequently enlivened by dashes of deadpan humour. With Joseph Gordon-Levitt imparting immense charm and chutzpah to his flamboyant cop and punchlines flying thick and fast between him and his partner in ‘crime&amp;rsquo;, the film has its share of passably bright moments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greedy People</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/greedy-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:11:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/greedy-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set in a small, quiet American town where nothing really happens and everyone knows everyone, Greedy People is a feature film told from many perspectives. Starring Himesh Patel, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, and Lily James, the crime comedy quickly moves from laughs to backstabbing, some quite literal in this crazy narrative. While the story simply must be seen to be believed, the actors&amp;rsquo; performances sell the absurdity of the fast changing plot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
