<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Recruit S02 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-recruit-s02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Recruit S02 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:18:59 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-recruit-s02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Recruit S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-recruit-s02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 13:18:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-recruit-s02-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Noah Centineo returns as the bumbling but charming CIA lawyer Owen Hendricks in the new season of The Recruit. We left him in Season 1, kidnapped in the Czech Republic, and miraculously, Owen survives. Although he lands himself in an entirely new scrap that could have international implications. Alexi Hawley&amp;rsquo;s series is two episodes shorter than the first, but the South Korea-set story remains entertaining in round two. Initially benched, Owen can&amp;rsquo;t sit still and do nothing at the CIA, so he finds himself pulled into a new threat that takes him to Seoul, where he meets NIS agent Jang Kyun (Teo Yoo). Jang blackmails him to get something personal of his in return. Battling past demons with his late father&amp;rsquo;s memory and his own time in Seoul as a child, Owen must use his quick-thinking skills to get what Jang wants. Additionally, Owen is also laying low against an internal investigation that could have him disbarred. Hawley makes good use of the baby-faced but earnest Noah as the protagonist Owen in The Recruit. This season, with new and old characters, the series has a good mix of the pending storyline and a new mystery to take the story further. The show continues to lean into the lawyer jokes, and there were several scenes that made me laugh out loud more than once.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
