<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Miranda Brothers on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-miranda-brothers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Miranda Brothers on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:52:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-miranda-brothers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Miranda Brothers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-miranda-brothers-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 14:52:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-miranda-brothers-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Julio, the son of a single parent Susan Miranda, requests his mother to adopt an infant who’s left stranded on the streets. Braving past several financial challenges, Susain raises Julio and Regalo, who are extremely fond of one another. As adults, they hope to make a career in football. However, when a personal setback tests their equation, Regalo has a tough choice to make.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Harshavardhan Rane’s toned body is the only good excuse to distract you from the superficiality of his performance. However, the role doesn’t offer him anything substantial either. Much like him, Meezan Jaffri fares no better, creating little impact as an actor despite his good looks. Both female leads – Jeniffer Piccinato and Sahher Bamba – are offered inconsequential roles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Miranda Brothers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-miranda-brothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 23:55:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-miranda-brothers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sanjay Gupta’s The Miranda Brothers revolves around two hunky brothers named Julio (Harshvardhan Rane) and Regalo Miranda (Meezaan Jafri), rising football stars in a Josh-coded Goa where orphaned babies are picked up from garbage dumps outside churches; arrogant cricketers cackle and say: “Cricket has two C’s: Cash and Chicks”; football scouts exclaim: “if we select both brothers, it’s like an earthquake and typhoon becoming one!”; bronze-bodied dance tracks called “Be My Mehbooba” pop up on a beach; and mourners at a funeral walk together in slow-motion as if they’re teleported to Sanjay Gupta’s Kaante (2002) instead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
