<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raghu Thatha on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/raghu-thatha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raghu Thatha on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 14:27:47 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/raghu-thatha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Raghu Thatha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raghu-thatha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 14:27:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raghu-thatha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The opening stretch of Raghu Thathatakes us back to the ‘60s. Even as the opening credits roll, we are shown newspaper clippings of important developments in that period. Anti-Hindi slogans and protests are rampant in Tamil Nadu, a state that is furiously vocal against the imposition of Hindi. Indira Gandhi has taken over as the first woman Prime Minister of the country, something that should ideally given women across the country a lot more confidence and freedom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raghu Thatha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raghu-thatha-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 22:43:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/raghu-thatha-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Keerthy Suresh&amp;rsquo;s teaser and trailer for Raghuthatha were released on social media, they generated a positive buzz around the film. The intriguingly cut trailer suggested that the film would address Hindi imposition in Tamil Nadu. Additionally, Kayavizhi’s (Keerthy Suresh) attempt to challenge patriarchy with her bold and upfront attitude piqued everyone’s interest. Did Suman Kumar manage to weave a successful story around these two sensitive topics? Let’s find out! Kayal (Keerthy Suresh) and her grandfather (MS Bhaskar) protest against Hindi imposition and are responsible for shutting down the Hindi organisation Ekta Sabha in their village, Valluvanpettai. She is a feminist who slams everyone who says, “ponna adaka odukama iru” (Be coy and obedient like a woman). One day, her grandfather’s cancer diagnosis and his three wishes push her towards marriage, which she has never been interested in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
