<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brahma Anandam on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/brahma-anandam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brahma Anandam on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:16:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/brahma-anandam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Brahma Anandam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/brahma-anandam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:16:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/brahma-anandam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Brahma Anandam presents an intriguing premise — real-life father and son, Brahmanandam and Raja Goutham, portraying an estranged grandfather-grandson duo named after the legendary comedian. Director RVS Nikhil builds on this quirky concept but overcomplicates it with excessive subplots, ultimately diluting its impact. Brahma is a rare protagonist who can laugh at himself. Once a celebrated child artist, he struggles to evolve into a skilled theatre actor, finding little success. His fractured family dynamics, unresolved grief over losing his father, and his lack of commitment to his girlfriend, Tara, add to his emotional turmoil. His only constants are his cousin Raasi and childhood friend Giri, grounding him in an otherwise chaotic world. When a promising career opportunity knocks, Brahma rekindles his relationship with his estranged grandfather, Ananda Rammurthy. As the story shifts from the city to a sleepy hamlet, hidden agendas unravel, and chaos ensues. The director, however, takes too long to get to the point, stalling with unnecessary detours to conceal a predictable plot twist.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
