<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vishal Menon on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/vishal-menon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vishal Menon on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 12:48:06 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/vishal-menon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ponman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ponman-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 12:48:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ponman-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ponman seems like a silly title for the film this turned out to be. The title translates to ‘kingfisher’, but it’s also a play on the phrase ‘pon’ meaning gold and man, because it&amp;rsquo;s about a man who deals in gold. By the end of the film, though, one might find other reasons to justify this title, but to begin with, you understand that it’s referring to the character played by Basil Joseph, a strange character named PP Ajesh. Going by the term the film uses, he runs what is called a “Madiyil Jewellery”, the kind of mobile jewellery in which the gold, literally, ends up on your lap. I’m not sure if this business is specific to Kollam, where the film is set in, but from my understanding of the trade, Ajesh is a broker who supplies gold to brides right before they get married, expecting to be repaid using the money they earn in the form of gifts during the wedding. It’s a peculiar practice, something many of us will discover as we watch Ponman. It is also ideal as a plot device in a film that talks about dowry, that too within the fascinating Latin Catholic community of the region. So, when we first meet PP Ajesh, he’s supplying 25 sovereigns of gold to a bride named Stefi Graf (Lijimol Jose), a night before she gets married to the “big, mountain-like” Mariyano (Sajin Gopu).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:23:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/glrMsiklFfw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mithya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:08:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much does a young boy have to go through to be allowed the freedom to have an emotional breakdown? When we first meet Mithya (Athish Shetty), what we see is his back turned towards us as he travels on a train from somewhere to somewhere else. We later learn that he’s not travelling out of choice. He’s being displaced from his home in Mumbai to Udipi in Southern Karnataka where he will live with his uncle, aunt and their two daughters. Like Mithya, the film about him too has its back turned towards us. It’s not a film that grants you the solace of having empathised with its broken protagonist. Instead, it reveals these broken pieces so sparsely that we feel as lost and helpless as he does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 14:52:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhal-enbadhu-podhu-udamai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first 30 minutes of Kadhal Enbadhu Podhu Udamai (Love Is Common Property) is not an easy film to sit through. It’s frothy and hollow and you’d be surprised that you’re watching the work of writer-director Jayaprakash Radhakrishnan, known for intense psychological dramas such as Lens (2016) and Thalaikoothal (2023). It begins with Sam (Lijomol Jose) confessing to her mother (Rohini) that she’s in love and wants her to meet this person. With the flowery set-up you’d find in silly rom-coms, we get scene after painful scene of the mother, preparing to welcome her future son-in-law. We learn that they hail from the upper middle class, and we also learn that Sam&amp;rsquo;s parents separated years ago. The film uses this time to introduce us to a handful of characters, including Sam’s father (Vineeth), Sam’s bestie Ravi (Kalesh) and Deepa (Deepa Shankar), the cook who is more than family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Painkili</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/painkili-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 14:49:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/painkili-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Sreejith Babu’s debut Painkili, cringe isn’t the after-effect as much as it is the aesthetic the film aspires for. It is self-aware and loud and made by a director with such an original style that he hasn’t yet found ways to bring it under control. How else would you describe some of the wild ideas that are dime a dozen? Take the example of a character named Jaffer, one of the many “gundas” in the film. Not only does Jaffer introduce himself each time he runs into a friend, but he goes on to call everyone around him Jaffer too. It doesn’t make any sense and oftentimes ideas like these are so strange that we’re unsure if we’re expected to laugh or wince. But in the odd instance one of these wild swings begin to make sense, it’s next to impossible to stop laughing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vidaamuyarchi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vidaamuyarchi-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:56:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vidaamuyarchi-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lovely additions Magizh Thirumeni makes to Breakdown (1997) to humanise what was otherwise a straightforward Hollywood action movie. This begins right with the way he re-interprets the title ‘Breakdown’. Not only does this mean that Magizh’s version begins way before Arjun’s (Ajith Kumar) car breaks down in the middle of nowhere as he travels with his wife to Tbilisi, but the title also alludes to the ‘breakdown’ they are experiencing in their marriage. It&amp;rsquo;s middle of the road in a sense, but the not the kind you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about. They’ve been together for 12 years and they’ve lost the magic that had once brought them together. In another awkward meet-cute that we’ve now come to expect from Magizh Thirumeni, we’re told that Arjun once sent “Happy Birthday” messages every day to Kayal (Trisha) for six consecutive months. But after 12 years, Arjun doesn’t even remember the date anymore, even when the world stays up to wish Kayal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dominic and the Ladies&#39; Purse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dominic-and-the-ladies-purse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 12:57:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dominic-and-the-ladies-purse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;10 minutes into Gautham Vasudev Menon’s Dominic And The Ladies’ Purse is all it takes for one to fall in love with CI Dominic (Mammootty), the eccentric, pompous detective with a serious cash-flow issue. We meet him through Vicky (Gokul Suresh), Dominic’s new “Watson” on his first day of work, in what can best be described as a “zero introduction” scene. Dominic works out of his dilapidated home-office filled with props and furniture (his office chair is an abandoned salon seat) well past its glory days. So when he hires Vicky in a matter of seconds, it’s probably not because he’s finally found an intellectual equal, it’s just that Vicky has enough money at home to not ask for a salary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rekhachithram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/rekhachithram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:20:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/rekhachithram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speaking purely as a whodunit that begins with the discovery of an unidentified corpse, Rekhachithram is particularly pedestrian. The movie starts with a confession, and we cut to a person who could predictably be one of the murderers. It is not a film written for suspense or leading towards one major climactic twist. Still, nothing prepares you the way Rekhachithram takes you deep into a crime that took place so long ago — back when Mammootty hadn’t yet become the megastar he is today. This is partly because the whodunit is always in service of a spectacular amount of cinephilia. Right from the title font which reminds you of classic ‘80s cinema (as though Bharathan himself was the calligrapher) to the way the lost art of fan mail gets integrated into this crime, the love for cinema isn’t merely a flavour in Rekhachithram as much as it is a part of its soul. Even the wordplay of its title, which could be read both as “composite sketch” as well a movie about Rekha, reveals the film’s dual personalities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kadhalikka Neramillai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhalikka-neramillai-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:15:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kadhalikka-neramillai-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right from the casting of the delightful Nithya Menen as Shriya, to the picture-perfect houses; from AR Rahman’s youthful score to the way these songs are shot, coded in shades of red and blue; there’s a dotingly recreated design in Kadhalikka Neramillai that is meant to evoke Mani Ratnam’s O Kadhal Kanmani (2015). Like the 2015 romance, Kiruthiga Udhayanadhi’s film also is set around two hyper-individualistic protagonists, each with their own sets of rules and quirks. If OKK was about a couple that was marriage-averse, Kadhalikka Neramillai is about two people who do not believe in commitment. But what if you add an extra layer of conflict into their midst by throwing in the idea of having children? That is what makes Kadhalikka Neramillai a cultural update of O Kadhal Kanmani, like a thought exercise that was born when someone mooted, “What if Tara and Aditya from OKK met, but later, when they are in their 30s?” It’s this bit of tweaking that makes for a more complex film. In a casual breakfast scene set at Shriya’s house, we see her correcting her mother (lovingly called Kanmani!) when she assumes Shriya to still be a virgin. This isn’t a movie about glossy love-at-first-sight moments or syrupy meet-cutes. Well into their adult lives, both Sid (Ravi Mohan) and Shriya (Nithya Menen) have been through enough heartbreaks to realise that love is… a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Madha Gaja Raja</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/madha-gaja-raja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 17:52:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/madha-gaja-raja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sundar C’s long-delayed Madha Gaja Raja is not the sort of film you enter expecting complex interpersonal relationships or technical finesse. Even if we’d watched the film in 2012 — when it was originally set to release — we may still have found its scenes dated or objectionable. It’s as though we’re forced to remind ourselves that this film is a product of its time, urging us to be kinder because none of us knew any better. Simpler times we no longer have the patience for; like that scene that follows when Raja (Vishal) learns that his friend’s wife has misplaced her gold necklace. Instead of launching an investigation, Raja offers his own gold chain and urges his friends to pool in to make up for the lost necklace. Or the other scene in which Raja deliberately loses a race, just so his rival feels respected in his hometown. Or even the over-the-top nobility with which Raja moves to Chennai to get a corporate honcho to return ₹ 52,20,350 to his broke bestie. It’s all sickeningly sweet, but you’d be shocked at how badly we want to buy into all this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/identity-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:49:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/identity-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a 10-minute-long sequence in Identity, in which an important character explains a medical condition called prosopagnosia—a rare cognitive disorder where damage to a particular part of the brain affects the patient’s ability to identify faces. The scene itself is loaded with exposition, almost like a TED Talk, but it is effective in explaining the condition of the film’s most important character. As a detail, it sounds just about right to make the character appear mysterious, vague and, of course, human. But on a screenplay level, it forms a solid base to explore the unreliable narrator trope—where the only person whose observations matter, is the one who cannot be relied on at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanangaan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vanangaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 23:46:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vanangaan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bala probably forgot that he is Bala. Why else would a director with an obsession for the same pet themes begin a film with a song like ‘Irai Nooru’? The song composed by GV Prakash, isn’t the issue. It’s another one of those mirthful songs about a brother and the unending love he feels for his sister. They have fun, they go to the beach, they go to temples, they go to church, and they are obviously very happy. The year is 2025 and by now, we have a 100-year history of movies telling us that something terrible is going to happen when a film begins with such a lazy, happy montage. And then we must remember that this movie is being made by Bala, a man who has built his brand around tragedies. The remaining runtime of Vanangaan, then, isn’t so much about what’s going to happen and why, as much as it is about how many people are going to die and if we will care when they do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viduthalai Part 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 11:35:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/viduthalai-part-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first part of Viduthalai, you’d remember the long trek Kumaresan (Soori) undertakes to reach the camp where he is posted as a police constable for the first time. Even for a story that takes more than five hours to unfold, you’d remember the slow pace with which he treks across terrains, water bodies and hills to finally get to the top. Until today, I felt the pacing was intentional because we needed to understand how remote and challenging it was going to be for Kumaresan to work there. Narratively too, it was important for us to register the hostile terrain everyone in this movie was fighting over, right from the locals to the police and the mining corporation that wants to set up shop there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/marco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 23:23:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/marco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blood begins to flow even before the first scene in Marco. For a film about a bastard son avenging the murder of his adopted brother, it’s appropriate for even the opening credits to show his family tree in the form of a (literal) bloodline, as blood flows from one generation to next. Haneef Adeni, after the unwatchable comedy Ramachandra Boss &amp;amp; Co, returns home to a world he is most familiar with, in Marco. All his obsessions return too, including the Biblical references, Christian symbolism, Malayali men dressed for black tie events in peak summer, and the cringiest of English dialogues that are too lethal even for TikTok.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rifle Club</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/rifle-club-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 13:49:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/rifle-club-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Aashiq Abu’s Rifle Club, manliness is next to godliness. It’s set in a hyper-violent world with no room for peaceful resolutions or around-the-table diplomacy. An eye for an eye is the only diktat, and it’s the meanest, most frenetic Western you’re likely to see from one of our Southern-most states. It takes place in 1991 and this gives the film a pre-woke recklessness that’s rare in a film set in today’s time. Instead, the film’s allegiance to machismo is so on-the-nose that it doesn’t even try to hide the many phallic symbols that “rise” from subtext to text. In a chilling scene, when an outsider asks Itty (a killer Vani Vishwanath) if he can speak to the man of the house, she forces him to look down, pointing at her loaded pistol. This is not your average household in which women are valued based on their looks or their ability to cook. For members of the Rifle Club, what matters most is the ability to shoot, gender notwithstanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miss You</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/miss-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/miss-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a tiny, two-minute stretch towards the end of the cloyingly sentimental Miss You, when we finally get a semblance of an idea that’s actually worth one’s time. Until then, Miss You is about Vasu (Siddharth), a man who cannot remember two years of his life, including his unhappy marriage. But as the film resolves Vasu’s battle with amnesia (albeit conveniently), he gets a call from a movie producer who approves of a script he had narrated a year ago. He’s been through so much during this period that he no longer remembers what he pitched and begins to frantically look for the forgotten idea. Getting a project greenlit, as we all know, is so close to impossible that we quickly sympathise with Vasu. Imagine looking through all your notes to piece together a script you’ve forgotten. Imagine having to trace your steps to go through the emotional and creative journey that made you a writer in the first place. Like learning to play the violin again, or trying to remember the recipe to your signature dish, there’s so much one can do with the concept of a man with amnesia. But Miss You is entirely satisfied chasing the one aspect of it that every single film before this has already addressed…love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushpa 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:17:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/pushpa-2-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sukumar, the writer-director of the Pushpa franchise, is something of a genius when it comes to staging setups and their rewarding payoffs. At certain points in Pushpa 2, you sense how he’s working towards a series of payoffs, some that were set-up in the earlier portions of the first film, which is set 20 years before the events of the sequel. At other points, the payoffs are immediate, giving these scenes an elegant beginning, middle and an end that is so good, they can be developed into standalone short films capable of amassing millions of views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sookshmadarshini</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sookshmadarshini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:43:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sookshmadarshini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first 20 minutes of Sookshmadarshini may be used as a textbook to learn the art of writing a setup. Writers Athul Ramachandran and Libin TB are preparing their viewer for a film that falls into an unusual genre but instead of rushing towards the plot, they take their time to focus on establishing their protagonist: Priyadarshini (Nazriya), a 20-something mother who admits to feeling bored of domesticity. She lives in a regular middle-class neighbourhood, filled with regulars who know everything about each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Her</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/her/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:40:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/her/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s not fair to call Lijin Jose’s Her, written by Archana Vasudev, an anthology. On the surface, these are the stories of five women taking place across five households in and around Thiruvananthapuram. The timelines are jumbled and these stories are set across different genres with at least one comedy, one satire and parts you can broadly call drama, each with its own mood and theme. Yet you feel conflicted by the thought of calling it an anthology because it never stops feeling like a unified whole, with the narrative smoothness of a well-written feature film (it’s edited by Kiran Das).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorgavaasal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sorgavaasal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:38:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sorgavaasal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There couldn’t have been a more fitting title for the film that Sorgavaasal has turned out to be. When translated, it could be read as “At Heaven’s Gate”. This isn’t merely ironic, given how almost the entire film is set within the walls of a high-security prison. But the idea of being at arms length from heaven, as close as you are far, gives Sorgavaasal the illusion of it taking place in some sort of a purgatory. For some inmates, this idea of heaven is the day they’re released back into the outside world. For others, the exit sign points only towards death. But then there’s the third kind, like the man they all lovingly call ‘Cooker’ (Balaji Sakthivel), whose belief falls somewhere in between. When Parthi (RJ Balaji, as never seen before) cooks a delicious meal for the inmates, he asks Cooker why this isn’t the norm. Cooker replies, “If you start enjoying the food you’re being served here, you will feel no need to leave.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanguva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanguva-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:59:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanguva-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1ZdAbciBrN8?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amaran</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/amaran-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:57:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/amaran-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In one of the many interesting segues in Rajkumar Periasamy’s Amaran, an officer talks to Major Mukund Varadarajan (an earnest Sivakarthikeyan) about the Kashimir women these officers refer to as “half widows”, stuck in perennial conflict as they wait for their husbands to return, unsure if they&amp;rsquo;re still alive. This is explained in a rush, as though someone is reading aloud a Wikipedia entry, but one can still make a connection between these women and the film’s narrator,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 08:04:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amal Neerad and his co-writer Lajo Jose (whose story this film is based on) know how far to push the unreliable narrator trope. Not only is their protagonist Reethu (Jyothirmayi in her return) suffering from both retrograde and anterograde amnesia, but we’re seeing the film through her perspective for the most part. What makes this film even more complex is how quickly we get the feeling that we cannot rely on the people Reethu relies on to make sense of her chilling universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bougainvillea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 08:02:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bougainvillea-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_eQDsBPZvzI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vettaiyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 08:12:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vettaiyan-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Journalist-turned-director T. J. Gnanavel doesn’t seem to care much for any sort of filmmaking subtleties. It’s as though he enjoys dialling up the volume knob to underline his already-dramatic writing, and doesn’t let you rest until you feel the full weight of a scene’s emotions. This was obvious in the way he didn’t stop by just showing you a police officer dragging a beaten-up Manikandan K. into the back of a police jeep in Jai Bhim (2021).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
