<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Real Pain on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/a-real-pain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in A Real Pain on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 22:29:27 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/a-real-pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 22:29:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“This will be a tour about pain,” cautions James, the earnest British guide shepherding a group of American Jews on a tour of Poland. The small group includes David and Benji, two cousins from New York on a visit to Poland to honour their recently deceased grandmother Dori, a Polish Jew who survived the Holocaust. Best known for this starring role as Mark Zuckerberg in The Social Network, Jesse Eisenberg writes, directs and stars in this holocaust comedy playing David, who like Eisenberg, suffers from OCD and anxiety disorder. David has a regular job, a wife and child and uses pills to deal with his anxiety. He’s socially awkward and envies Benji’s ease and charm. Benji road-rolls his cousin and trivialises his life choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 09:23:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time we meet Benji (Kieran Culkin), he’s aimlessly floating around in an airport. Seated in the waiting area with his ear pods plugged in, one can immediately spot the melancholy in his eyes. He appears to be curious about people – observing them closely. There’s a good chance that if someone around him was in need, Benji would be one of the first persons to help. But he’s also a wildcard, who wouldn’t respond to his cousin David’s (Jesse Eisenberg) voicemails, and that too on the day they’re supposed to travel to Poland together. Has he woken up? Has he left? Is he on time? Where is he? Does he remember they have a flight? No response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 17:52:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Real Pain, starring Eisenberg and Kieran Culkin as cousins, is exactly the kind of film you imagine if Eisenberg and Culkin played cousins. It’s funny, awkward, edgy, poignant, light, chatty, alert, minor-key and Sundancey (an adjective for the brand of tragicomic American quirk that the snowy festival loves to showcase). There are echoes of the uptight mom and no-filter teen from the actor’s directorial debut, When You Finish Saving The World, in the uptight David (Eisenberg) and the free-spirited-but-troubled Benji (Culkin). Family man David and drifter Benji head to Poland to process their Jewish heritage through a guided Holocaust tour and, more importantly, visit their late camp-survivor grandmother’s childhood home. As in most movies, it’s the interiority of the oddball journey that matters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 09:12:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesse Eisenberg&amp;rsquo;s written and directed Oscar ready film A Real Pain has been released in India. Filled with humour, depths of human experience, trauma and moving on from it, it explores the story of two brothers from different walks of life. Led by Jesse as well as Kieran Culkin, the film is worthy of his international praise for its performances as well as the brilliant yet simple writing of the story and screenplay. A Real Pain begins with two cousins meeting at an airport to head on a trip together. The two, who hardly meet once or twice a year go on a journey together to honour their late grandmother, a survivor of the Holocaust. Billy and David decide to take a tour in Poland, visiting sights of historical significance during World War II and the Holocaust. Along with four others in the group and a tour guide, there is much talk about survivors, generational trauma, the struggle of immigrants and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
