<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Board on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Board on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/guild/board/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anupama Chopra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/anupama-chopra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/anupama-chopra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anupama Chopra is a film critic, national award-winning book author and journalist. She is the editor of The Hollywood Reporter India, founder of Film Companion Studios and chairperson of the Film Critics Guild. She has covered cinema since 1993 in multiple mediums – print, television and digital. She has worked with India Today, NDTV 24x7, Star World. She has also written about cinema for various international publications including The New York Times and Sight and Sound. Anupama has authored several books, including King of Bollywood - Shah Rukh Khan and the Seductive World of Indian Cinema, which was featured on the Editor’s Choice list of the New York Times Sunday book review and translated into German, Indonesian and Polish. Anupama received an M.A. in journalism from Northwestern University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sucharita Tyagi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/sucharita-tyagi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/sucharita-tyagi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sucharita Tyagi is a prominent Indian film critic who now splits her time between Mumbai and New York. With nearly 10 years of experience as a film critic, she is best known for her popular movie reviews on YouTube, where she has built a community of dedicated fans. Tyagi also has extensive experience in broadcast radio. Utilising her unique voice, she reviews and discusses South Asian pop culture with honesty and passion through a contemporary, feminist lens, breaking down complex issues in relatable ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bharathi Pradhan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/bharathi-pradhan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/bharathi-pradhan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bharathi Pradhan is a Columnist, Critic &amp;amp; Author with over 50 years of experience. She currently reviews English &amp;amp; Hindi films for Lehren.com and is a Sunday columnist with The Telegraph.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rohan Naahar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/rohan-naahar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/rohan-naahar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rohan Naahar is based out of New Delhi, India, and has been reviewing films and television shows for over a decade. He has written for the Hindustan Times and currently writes for the Indian Express.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anuj Kumar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/anuj-kumar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/anuj-kumar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anuj Kumar is a senior film critic with The Hindu. He has written extensively on Hindi film trends, conducted interviews, and contributed nostalgia pieces. He has contributed to Housefull (Om Books), a collection of short essays on films made during the Golden Age of Hindi cinema.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arnab Banerjee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/arnab-banerjee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/arnab-banerjee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arnab Banerjee has been a film critic and journalist for over 20 years, and is currently contributing film reviews to The Asian Age and BBC Radio. Besides reviewing films, both Hollywood and Bollywood, he also writes on music, does book reviews and covers art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rahul Desai</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/rahul-desai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/rahul-desai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A film critic and columnist, Rahul Desai writes for The Hollywood Reporter India and OTTPlay. In his spare time, he runs a weekly movie podcast called IIF.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sachin Chatte</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/sachin-chatte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/sachin-chatte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sachin Chatte is a film critic based in Goa and has been writing about cinema for close to 30 years. He has been reviewing films for The Navhind Times, Goa for 25 years and occasionally contributes to other publications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shomini Sen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/shomini-sen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/shomini-sen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shomini Sen is a film critic and entertainment editor for WION with over 15 years of experience in film writing. She has previously worked with News18.com and Zeenews.com . She reviews and writes about Hindi, English and Bengali films.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stutee Ghosh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/stutee-ghosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/stutee-ghosh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stutee Ghosh, a film critic with nearly a decade of experience, has transitioned smoothly across various mediums — radio, television, print &amp;amp; digital. She has been associated with The Quint. Works with Hindustan Times. Currently Heads Programming at Fever FM Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Udita Jhunjhunwala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/udita-jhunjhunwala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 12:19:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/guild/board/udita-jhunjhunwala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Udita Jhunjhunwala has more than 25 years of experience as a film critic with national publications such as Mid-Day, Hindustan Times, Mint, Scroll.in. Her interviews, opinion pieces and industry insights have also appeared in moneycontrol.com, AFP, The Hindu, Vogue, Variety &amp;amp; Screen International.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
