<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Wild Robot on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-wild-robot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Wild Robot on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:32:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-wild-robot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:32:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE WILD ROBOT is about an all-purpose robot that turns sentient in the wilderness. After washing up on a forest island, Rozzum “Rozz” 7134 learns to feel and discern once it mothers an orphaned goose and befriends a red fox. I’d say it becomes human, but in the context of where we are today, “it grows a heart” is more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The premise is not earth-shatteringly original; cautionary and cute robot tales are the cornerstone of animated cinema and science fiction. A machine coming alive through motherhood is a familiar allegory. An unlikely ‘interspecies’ family is the core of cross-cultural comedy. Ecological fairy tales and deforestation metaphors featuring animals joining paws, claws and wings to defeat manmade evils — we’ve seen it all before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 14:48:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Wild Robot, inspired by Peter Brown&amp;rsquo;s 2016 novel of the same&#xA;name, is a film that skillfully balances its emotional elements, resulting in a gratifying experience for both children and adults. While the notion of a robot experiencing emotions is not entirely original, it is the narrative and its execution that truly set this film apart. Achieving the right emotional resonance, whether from a human or a robot, is crucial, and Chris Sanders has struck gold with this film.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 20:29:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DreamWorks Animation turns 30 this year, and its latest presentation, The Wild Robot, is a great example of what the studio gets right. Adapted and directed by Chris Sanders, the animated feature follows the adventures of Rozzum 7134 (voice of Lupita Nyong&amp;rsquo;o), who discovers a whole new side to herself after she reluctantly adopts a gosling. The family film is filled with humour and meaning, and it teaches you what it means to be kind and love another in need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 16:03:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Wild Robot was one of the most anticipated films since its first teaser dropped with the song &amp;lsquo;What a Wonderful World&amp;rsquo; and the film has lived up to its hype. Not only does it offer an adorable story for kids to watch but it also comes with heavy context and geological subtext that is enough to keep the adults engaged. The film unexpectedly also offers much humour and some emotional moments but best yet has been the artwork throughout the run time. From birds taking flight and colouring the sky, to the moving leaves that breathe life into the art, the film comes with a great re-watch value ready to turn it into a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
