<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Picture This on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/picture-this/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Picture This on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:54:59 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/picture-this/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Picture This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/picture-this-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 21:54:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/picture-this-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;College kids of a certain age would be familiar with the practice of filtering assignments through a very rudimentary anti-plagiarism software, mainly to avoid being caught cheating by professors. So worthless were the results of this scam that a kid might even be shamed into putting in the actual effort and writing their assignment themselves. Not only were they submitting something unoriginal, it was also impossible to read. Essentially the same route is now being taken by filmmakers. This week’s new romantic comedy, Picture This, isn’t merely a remake; it’s a remake that is happy to be released in the same week as the Oscars and actively aim for a 2/5.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Picture This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/picture-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 18:43:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/picture-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture This, led by Simone Ashley, is a remake of the Australian rom-com Five Blind Dates from star Shuang Hu. Relocated to London, director Prarthana Mohan&amp;rsquo;s film takes the same elements but places it within a dysfunctional but loving British Asian family. Amidst wedding planning, blind dating, and reconnecting with an old love, Ashley&amp;rsquo;s Pia finds herself again in this funny and enjoyable romantic comedy. The Amazon Prime Video feature is fast-paced and colourful, with plenty of laugh-out-loud moments. Ashley is Pia Jaswani, a talented photographer who owns her own photography studio, The Ninth Mandala, and runs it with her best friend Jay (Luke Fetherston). Her younger sister Sonal (Anoushka Chadha) announces she&amp;rsquo;s getting married with a month-long series of events. Their mother Laxmi (Sindhu Vee) calls an astrologer (Kulwinder Dhir) to check the groom and bride&amp;rsquo;s janampatris (birthcharts), when he suddenly predicts Pia will meet her soulmate after going on five dates. Her meddling family gets to work with unsuitable suitors, while her first love Charlie (Hero Fiennes Tiffin) walks back in her life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
