<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sanyukta Thakare on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/sanyukta-thakare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sanyukta Thakare on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:51:19 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/sanyukta-thakare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sikandar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 16:51:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sikandar, directed by A.R. Murugadoss, known for films like Ghajini, makes an honest effort with the story, but the execution doesn&amp;rsquo;t match up to its potential. The film essentially follows a good-natured man who aims to live up to his dead wife&amp;rsquo;s expectations and keep what is left of her safe. The makers take an emotional, very Bollywood masala approach with its story, but it still could have been enjoyable without the flimsy editing and screenplay. The film begins with Raja Sahab&amp;rsquo;s aka Sanjay aka Sikandar introduction through the film&amp;rsquo;s minor villain. When a politician&amp;rsquo;s son is blackmailing and harassing a girl on a flight, Snjay takes it upon himself to teach the kid a lesson. However, when a complaint is filed against him, the politician and his corrupt officer, Sanjay&amp;rsquo;s beloved praja, saves him from arrest. Rashmika Mandana is his fairly young and devoted wife. Indebted by his selfless act to marry her, he takes it upon herself to always be the one between him and any danger. After some goons are sent behind Sanjay, in an accident, Saisri passes away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:31:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/holland-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The mystery thriller is directed by Mimi Cave, who is best known for Flesh, a film focused on body horror. A glimpse of the same can be seen in Holland, but this is more focused on being a mystery thriller for its own characters. The trailer zeros in on the story, and the same narrative is explored during the almost two-hour-long film. Led by Nicole Kidman and Matthew Macfadyen, the film explores the dynamics of a family that looks perfect on the outside but something sinister is going on underneath. The film also stars a young actor Jude Hill and Gael García Bernal as the second love interest for Nicole. It begins with Nicole&amp;rsquo;s narration as Nancy Vandergroot, a teacher at the local high school where he kid also goes. She is respected around the town as the wife of Fred Vandergroot, a good church going man who is a life-saving doctor. Their kid, Harry, follows every word of his father, who ends up mediating their fights. Their life is perfect and good, but something remains off about Nancy as she gets obsessive and paranoid about little things. First, it is a missing earning which leads to her firing a babysitter and later, it is a receipt she finds in Fred&amp;rsquo;s pants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snow White</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/snow-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 09:37:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/snow-white/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Snow White is the new live-action version of Disney’s classic princess story. Unlike the previous versions the film does stick to some of its traditional roots. It is hard to ignore all the controversy that came before and after the film’s release but even with its overwhelming shadow, Rachel Zegler’s performance is commendable. Snow White is not the first time Rachel has been part of a musical and it shows, but the film does take some extra effort to present her as a princess. Most of the weight is carried forward by the young actress who played young Snow in the opening song. The film begins with the introduction to a happy Kingdom where the King and Queen are kind and loving people who believe in thriving along with the people of the village they rule over. The opening song talks about the royals teaching their young daughter Snow the right way to live and the kind of person she should grow up to be — Fearless, Fair, Brave and True.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tumko Meri Kasam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tumko-meri-kasam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 09:35:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/tumko-meri-kasam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written and directed by Vikram Bhatt, the film is a fictionalised version of the story of Ajay Murdia aka the founder of a chain of fertility clinics, Indira IVF. According to reports the film has incorporated some real facts about his life and career in the screenplay. The film explores a legal case, where he is accused of an attempt to murder one of his younger board members, while the memory of his dead wife gives him hope to not give up. With a run time of over two and a half hours, the film feels longer than necessary between, flashbacks, songs and more. Led by Anupam Kher as Ajay Murdia, the film begins with a news montage of how he is accused of attempting to murder, while a court proceeding grants him bail in the matter. His lawyer played by Eesha Deol is seen flying with him to Udaipur, so the family can decide how to move forward with the case. While Ajay wants to brave the storm along, he isn&amp;rsquo;t left behind by his kids who also decide to stick by him till the end. Soon it is evident, that the young board member is trying to frame Ajay Murdia in the case and his life was never in danger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electric State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-electric-state-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 09:41:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-electric-state-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Netflix film takes place in a dystopian past where the world was taken over by a war with robots and turned the world into a different kind of machine obsessed society decades ago. Set in the 90s the film explores what happens when robots take over everyday activities, gain conscious awareness and decide this is their world too. A war breaks out and one evil is replaced with another. The film is reportedly based on Simon Stalenhag&amp;rsquo;s illustrated book of the same name. However, reports have revealed that the makers took creative liberty with the tone and aesthetic of the film which is far from the original material. The film has its own version to offer but the source seems way more cooler. Netflix&amp;rsquo;s film is more focused on being a child&amp;rsquo;s film enjoyable by the adults while be wholesome and also sharing its deeper message of human bonding. However, if the reports are true and the film has been using AI without considering its impact and consequences, then the irony of the film loses its impact totally. Millie Bobby Brown&amp;rsquo;s film begins amid the war with machines, where her character Michelle’s brother is taking a test for college applications. He is deemed a genius who has the potential to save the world and humans from the war against machines. However, just as their lives were about to get better, the family ends up in an accident and Michelle is the only one who survives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Diplomat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 09:39:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John Abraham film is based on a true story but the makers do take liberties with the storytelling. Directed by Shivam Nair the film focuses on the thriller tone while exploring the victim’s story instead of the outcome since it’s already known. Inspite of the lack of action and punchy dialogues which is what John is known for in the recent years, the actor gives a commendable yet subtle performance. The film begins with a woman from the mountains of Pakistan being escorted to the Indian embassy. The makers from the first shot make it known that she isn’t coming from a good place, other women she comes across are beaten and bruised while the men carry guns and would use them as easier as their arms. She is taken to the embassy by her husband and another man along with him. They wait for the embassy to open and as soon as her husband leaves her side and the doors open, Uzma Ahmed presents her Indian passport demanding she be led inside and that she’s in need of dire help.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 23:03:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The film based on real incidents follows the group of friends who decide to bring real cinema to their small town after realising Mumbai is out of their reach. Directed by Reema Kagti, the film focuses on their progress as filmmakers but also their friendship. It keeps the film rounded and about the people which the story is meant to be about than the industry. However, through out the run time, the film does stray from the point long enough for the ending to feel out of place. In the end, it is the performances that win. The film begins with the story of a group of young boys in Malegaon who would drop everything to get a glimpse of the stars on the big screen. While one of them runs a theater, another is part of a wedding video team, one is a writer and more. However, not all of them are working towards their career is films but still are obsessed with the stories just as much. Nasir when asked to buy film reels for the theatre finds out how to make copies and decides to make his own cut of action comedies to show at his theatre. They become an instant hit in his town but are shut down because of piracy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crazxy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crazxy-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 23:01:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crazxy-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crazxy led by Sohum Shah follows after the actor&amp;rsquo;s biggest hit Tumbbad. While the new release is nothing close to the fantasy horror, it does bring a new and unique concept to the big screen. However, the promotional material from the film does not line up with the real concept nor does it bring the right expectations from the film. The misdirection adds to the mystery but doesn&amp;rsquo;t last long as the plot turns predictable early one. The film&amp;rsquo;s climax also leaves much to be desired despite the concept. The film begins with Sohum Shah getting ready with a massive bag on his way to the hospital, getting bombarded with calls about reaching on time. Early on, the makers establish that Sohum&amp;rsquo;s character Abhimanyu isn&amp;rsquo;t the good guy. He is set up at the obnoxious ex-husband, a terrible father and a doctor who does not care much for the patients. He is about to settle a big case, and pay for his life with the 5 crore in his car, and move on with his new girlfriend. However, one phone call changes it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daredevil: Born Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daredevil-born-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:59:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daredevil-born-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daredevil has returned once again to the small screen, making his office debut for his solo series. The show, led by Charlie Cox, will also be following the story of Vincent D&amp;rsquo;Onofrio&amp;rsquo;s Kingpin aka Fisk. Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s return to the MCU is after the long-running series and spin-off like Defenders on Netflix. The series was dropped a couple of years ago, but Cox made several appearances in other MCU films and projects including Spider-Man No Way Home, Echo, She-Hulk and more. Moving forward with Kingpin&amp;rsquo;s Arc through the MCU and Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s past in the Netflix show, the new series is all set to pit them against each other in a new setting. With Fisk as Mayor of New York, and Murdock hanging up his suit, the city brings out the worst in both of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Monkey</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-monkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:56:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-monkey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The film based on a short story by Stephen King gives a take of its own but twist of comedy and creativity liberties to cover for a feature film&amp;rsquo;s run time. Directed by Osgood Perkins known for his recent release Longlegs, has turned for another horror but this time it comes with a comedy twist. The film led by Theo James follows the story of twins, who didn&amp;rsquo;t get much from their father, but a haunted Monkey toy. But its not a toy, its like an &amp;lsquo;Evil thing&amp;rsquo;. Everyone is the safest when the monkey isn&amp;rsquo;t beating the drum it came with, but the amount of gore in the film, nobody is safe. The film begins with Adam Scott aka Petey Shelburn Sr trying his best to return the Monkey to a shop but is unable to as its next victim as soon as it plays the drums, a chain reaction ends up claiming the live of the shop owner. Leaving it behind isn&amp;rsquo;t enough for Petey and he decides to use a flame thrower to melt it down but years later it safely finds its way to Petey&amp;rsquo;s twin kids. It is unclear what happened to Petey, but with everything that goes on in the film, it really could have ended any way for him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:53:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nadaaniyan set to mark the debut of Ibrahim Ali Khan turns out to be a story about high schoolers and their troubles with love and life. However, the film sets off the story without a theme and attempts to use everything woke all at once, while treating its female character like apologetic pick-me-up girls. The film treats the adult actors as teenagers, but they behave like they are in college and are of age while also looking to get into university abroad. The film seems like it was written for US based audience, but forgets to cater to its own market. The film begins with Kushi&amp;rsquo;s self-indulged introduction about her character Pia Jaisingh, but with each line it gets harder to tell if she is talking about her character or herself. The film attempts to create this self-aware humour of their privilege, but it begins to feel more obnoxious with each scene. After a long summer vacation, Pia returns to Delhi&amp;rsquo;s most privileged school, which has screens in the cafeteria and hallways so the principal can talk to the students. Her friends are upset with her for not showing up at the bonfire before summer and for talking to a guy who is off limits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mere Husband Ki Biwi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mere-husband-ki-biwi-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 06:21:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mere-husband-ki-biwi-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written and directed by Mudassar Aziz, the film does bring tones similar to his previous releases like Khel Khel Mein, Pati Patni Aur Woh, Happy Bhag Jayegi series. While his previous films had some aspects working for them, Mere Husband Ki Biwi falls short on most of them. Led by Arjun Kapoor, Bhumi Pednekar and Rakul Preet Singh, the film attempts to explore a good concept about divorce and separated families but the message is lost somewhere between all the twists and turns that don&amp;rsquo;t add much. The comic timings often work but the screenplay doesn&amp;rsquo;t support or appreciate the comedy as much. The film begins with Arjun Kapoor&amp;rsquo;s Ankur Chaddha dreaming about his monstrous ex-wife, Prabhleen Dhilon played by Bhumi Pednekar. Ankur and Prabhleen have separated for over two years but she continue to haunt his dreams, and his reality. Her memories continue to get in the way of his new relationships, however, his one loyal friend refuses to give up even if it lands them in trouble. Ankur is finally able to move on when he visits his hometown to finalise a deal, where he meets his college&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;IT&amp;rsquo; girl Antara Khanna played by Rakul Preet Singh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invincible S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/invincible-s03-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:41:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/invincible-s03-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Invincible has been a fan-favourite show for years, and season 3 continues on the same track. Despite its popularity, the animated series still seems underrated as it brings a blend of gory but easy superhero genres. The makers struggle to balance the big picture and the street-level subplots, but season 3 ends on a powerful note. Steven Yeun&amp;rsquo;s voice acting keeps the tension rising throughout the 8-episode season and is expected to get more intense with the next one. The season begins in the middle of Mark&amp;rsquo;s aka Invincibles&amp;rsquo; character development, while for season 2 he struggled with his identity as a hero, the crisis remains in the forefront. After his fight with Amstrong, Mark is more worried about his own mentality and if he is turning into his father, but he keeps up his training with Cecil for months in prep for any Viltrumite attacks. Meanwhile, his responsibility towards his younger brother is keeping him moving forward. He continues to avoid Eve but eventually gives in and confesses his feelings for her.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chhaava</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:38:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laxman Utekar&amp;rsquo;s directorial Chhaava focuses on building up on Sambhaji Maharaj&amp;rsquo;s tales of heroism with slow-motion action sequences and dialogues backed by heavy music. Still, Vicky Kaushal&amp;rsquo;s performance adds agency to the character and urgency to the plot. The film explores parts of the long story while also building on the world around it, introducing the historic era and Indian warriors of the time. Akshaye Khanna&amp;rsquo;s Aurangzeb is one of the key performances that keeps the film hooked but we needed a bit more from the roots of the story. Chhaava begins with a long narration of Sambhaji Maharaj&amp;rsquo;s family, and the tales of valour of his father Shivaji Maharaj and his grandfather Shahaji Maharaj. Narrated by Ajay Devgn, the same fills in the essence of the Maratha Swaraj as building blocks for the film. We do not get to see much of Sambhaji Maharaj&amp;rsquo;s childhood or his training for the throne instead, the makers added a few scenes showing how the memory of his late father always drove him in the right direction, meanwhile, his greed to know more about his mother and to make her proud kept him moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dhoom Dhaam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:36:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dhoom-dhaam-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yami Gautam and Pratik Gandhi-led film is a Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day special release for Netflix. The film directed by Rishab Seth also borderlines on the love connection of a newly married couple. The two only begin to find out about each other after their wedding night is interrupted by goons. The thriller comedy focuses more on the latter in the second half and the performances also shine the best then. It also stars Pavitra Sarkar, Eijaz Khan in pivotal roles which adds most of the fun element in the film and would have been beneficial if also used in the first half. The film begins with Veer and Koyal meeting each other for the first time with their parents. While Koyal&amp;rsquo;s mother is bragging about her skills and how sanskari she is, Veer&amp;rsquo;s mother is bragging about how he is the protector and can provide for anything. Neither of the two seems to have any issues with each other and the family agree on their union but is informed that the wedding has to take place in two weeks or they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to get married for two years. As the festivities begin the two get to know each other a little bit through social media and even less through phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Captain America Brave New World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:34:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Captain America took on a new face back in 2021 with the release of The Falcon And The Winter Solider. Sam Wilson decided not to go through the same treatment as Steve Rogers to become a Super Solider and this is about him and fans doubting his decision. It still feels like a good idea for Wilson to take the serum but he won’t in the coming years to justify the ideology — which the film does on more than one occasion even when the decision feels like a bad idea to our new Cap himself. The film does bring in some familiar faces for cameos which makes the second half worthwhile, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t build up to much. The film’s plot remains wafer thin as the government’s high-level prisoner goes rouge (surprise-surprise) and ends up taking over anyone and everyone he wishes including the President. While the tech may already be a real thing IRL, the film fails to see how a prisoner as big as the one introduced in the film gets away with it without raising any red flags or real alarms. Meanwhile, Sam returns to the MCU as the saviour of USA by going on a mission to retrieve a secret package being sold on the down low. And President Ross is working on trying to get the USA some Adamantium found in the celestial island aka Tiamut&amp;rsquo;s body left behind by the Eternals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:31:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bridget Jones Mad About The Boy explores a new chapter in the life of Bridget Jones after the death of Mark Dary. The film doesn&amp;rsquo;t do well for Renee Zellweger&amp;rsquo;s character as it continues to progressively not age throughout the series. However, the second half of the film focuses on a typical rom-com setting which works well for the film. It also brings more closure to all subplots and concerns that Bridget and her kids have. The film is as goofy and silly as earlier films in the series were and it is the nostalgia and emotional closure for the audience that keeps the film engaging. The film begins with Bridget going to visit Mark&amp;rsquo;s friends on his death anniversary. When he thinks about bailing her son reminds her, that it is the one day she leaves the house. At the party, it becomes obvious that even four years after his death she has not been able to move on, nor does she plan to do it. However, her friends demand that she return to work to be able to live a normal, healthy life. After recalling her father&amp;rsquo;s last wish that &amp;lsquo;she lives and not just survives after the death of her husband&amp;rsquo;, Bridget begins to take an interest in returning to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mehta Boys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-mehta-boys-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:21:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-mehta-boys-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Directed and co-written by Boman Irani, the film also stars him as one of the leading characters alongside Avinash Tiwary, who plays the role of his son Amay. The Mehta Boys follows the father-son duo exploring the complicated relationship and the underlying care and love in it. The film&amp;rsquo;s music and direction keeps the experience raw and relatable, however the writing in the second half begins to falter a bit. Nonetheless, the message comes across well, and it is the performances that keeps you going. The film begins with Amay&amp;rsquo;s journey as an architect who isn&amp;rsquo;t able to assert himself at his workplace, everyone is seen trying to support his vision and his work. But he often ends up giving into the high authority of his seniors even if he doesn&amp;rsquo;t agree with him. But things begin to change for him when a meeting in his office is interrupted to inform him that he received a call about his mother&amp;rsquo;s passing. Without a second thought, Amay leaves for his home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conclave</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/conclave/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:17:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/conclave/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a sense the ending in brilliant where the audience ends up judging themselves on the reaction as they were judging each character through out the runtime of the film, but it may not be enough. Directed by Edward Berger of All Quiet On The Western Front, the film is based on a book by Robert Harris released in 2016. The story sets forward a simple premise but stirs up major socio economic discussion in a religious setting. Conclave isn&amp;rsquo;t about ideology how much to maintain it while also trying to exist in the same world filled with national and economic borders. The film follows Dean Lawrence arriving after the death of the Pope and then tracking his last moments of the day. Early on the film builds suspense around his death but instead of turning into a crime thriller or drama the film explores several plots and subplots at the same time with much fineness. Much of it can be seen through the screenplay while other can be seen in the performance of the actors and through the direction aka Edward Berger&amp;rsquo;s point of view. He also explores the contradiction in Vatican&amp;rsquo;s world, the orders it operates on, the way it is perceived and even tries to break down those notions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re Cordially Invited</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/youre-cordially-invited-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:24:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/youre-cordially-invited-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest Prime Video release is the romantic comedy titled You&amp;rsquo;re Cordially Invited led by Reese Witherspoon and Will Ferrell. Directed and written by Nicholas Stoller, the film focuses on the story of two supporting characters at two different weddings aka the bride&amp;rsquo;s sister and another bride&amp;rsquo;s widowed father. They cross paths at the accidently double-booked wedding venue and the fight for the venue ensues. While the plot seems easy to explore in the comedy genre, the makers did present a new take on the situation. Instead of the fight going on before the wedding proceeds, the arguments go on throughout the wedding and after, taking away the urgency of the incident. The film begins with Will Ferrell&amp;rsquo;s character finding out that his young daughter is getting married to her boyfriend. While he isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly happy about it, he agrees because it would mean his daughter moves closer to home. On the other hand, Reese finds out her sister is getting married to her erotic dancer boyfriend. Supportive of the decision and wary of how the family would react, she agrees to look after the wedding planning. Both weddings are accidentally booked at the same resort on a small island for the same weekend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 08:26:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Directed by Rosshan Andrrews led by Shahid Kapoor, the action thriller brings back the actor in his action avatar. The music and Shahid’s presence keep the movie going for most of its runtime. The writing in the first half is one of the biggest plus points for the first half but the second half falters taking away the film’s impact, but it doesn’t take away from Shahid’s performance. Deva’s silent hero remains a simplistic dialogue that doesn’t force punchlines but lets the actors put their best foot forward. The film begins with Deva revealing that he has found the killer and the case has been solved but before he can share more information he meets with an accident and loses his memory. Upon waking up he finds out he is a cop who was working on a very important case and now he is the only one who can trace back and find the killer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 08:29:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sky Force directed by Sandeep Kewlani and Abhishek Anil Kapur is led by Akshay Kumar and introduced a debutante star Veer Pahariya. The film based on real incident follows the story of Air Force officers O.P. Taneja and Ajjamada Boppayya Devayya. The makers have fictionalized the characters for their onscreen portrayal but the almost raw performances are. The film begins in 1971 when a Pakistani pilot attacking on Indian soil is capture. The Group Captain played by Akshay Kumar aka Ahuja meets the pilot to question him about his plans, and Pakistan&amp;rsquo;s plans to attack India. However, during a very civil interrogation, Ahuja finds out that he is the same pilot who may have attacked his former colleague who has been missing in action for over six years. The film then turns to a flash back in 1965 where Veer&amp;rsquo;s character is introduced as Vijya his call name Tabby.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fateh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/fateh-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:14:31 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/fateh-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fateh marked Sonu Sood’s directional debut as well as his first all-out lead action role. The film attempts to talk about social issues as well as presents a hero with a bad boy image but has good intentions. With easy and comic dialogues the film does have much to offer to easy-going audience and can be relatable despite the action-heavy extravagant plot. Sonu Sood also gets a chance to show off his charm but his stoic demeanour works for him more. The film kicks off with an action packed scene where Sood walks into a room full of gangsters working for the cyber mafia and takes them down effortlessly. Though the scene is long it does brings one of the best action sequences in the film. Sood looks effortless during the action sequences even when the camera is slow to track the movements. The plot however takes a flashback as Sood is taken down recalling his life and his mission.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 09:08:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kangana Ranaut directorial is a fictional account of Indira Gandhi’s personal life experiences as a daughter, wife, politician and a woman of the nation. Led by Kangana in the leading role, the film does take creative liberties but impresses with writing that provides full-circle moments and character-focused direction. It is important to emphasise that the film is not a biopic or documentation of the real political personality but fiction an account of her life. The makers before the film began emphasized the film is based on two books. Emergency begins with Indira’s childhood and how she was inspired by her grandfather’s vision and understanding of Indraprastha, a play in ancient Indian history and its equivalent Delhi in today’s time where a constant struggle remains for power. Since childhood Indira focuses on winning the big battles and the same remains throughout her political career. The film also gives glimpses of her personal life her little interactions with her husband and her children through flashbacks and presently as her career progressed. The first half feels rushed as the story progresses through her political career with only a few incidents in the foreground. From the death of her father, her feeling betrayed by him to taking control of the party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 09:12:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jesse Eisenberg&amp;rsquo;s written and directed Oscar ready film A Real Pain has been released in India. Filled with humour, depths of human experience, trauma and moving on from it, it explores the story of two brothers from different walks of life. Led by Jesse as well as Kieran Culkin, the film is worthy of his international praise for its performances as well as the brilliant yet simple writing of the story and screenplay. A Real Pain begins with two cousins meeting at an airport to head on a trip together. The two, who hardly meet once or twice a year go on a journey together to honour their late grandmother, a survivor of the Holocaust. Billy and David decide to take a tour in Poland, visiting sights of historical significance during World War II and the Holocaust. Along with four others in the group and a tour guide, there is much talk about survivors, generational trauma, the struggle of immigrants and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sonic the Hedgehog 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 08:36:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sonic-the-hedgehog-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After two successful releases, the series is nowhere close to its end and isn’t bad. Featuring an ensemble cast of Jim Carrey, Keanu Reeves, Idris Elba and many more the film does justice for its young and adult audience. The makers manage to strike an almost balance between entertaining both of its audiences. Unlike many sequels, this one stays true to its core and explores a more chaotic version of Eggman, taking it to the next level. The writing and performances keep the films from falling into the same trap as all other sequels. The makers don’t waste time setting the story or the gap between the films. Just as the family of three aliens and two humans is celebrating Sonic’s Earth Birthday another catastrophe befalls their world. On the other side of their world, another alien is wreaking havoc. A sinister and darker version of Sonic called Shadow has broken out of a 50-year-old prison and is out for revenge. As Sonic, Tails and Knuckles begin to investigate they wonder if they know the full truth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kraven the Hunter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kraven-the-hunter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 08:39:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kraven-the-hunter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kraven the Hunter finally saw its release in Indian theaters but despite the delays and built-up anticipation this film has turned out to be another disappointment like Madam Web. The film explores the story of Spiderman Universe villain Kraven the Hunter. The titular role of the film is played by Aaron Taylor Johnson, who is known for his looks physique and charm but none of it transfers to his on-screen character Kraven the Hunter. The film begins with Kraven’s latest task at a Russian prison. The man of honour and code walks into the jail to kill his target but on his way out does not hesitate to take a few guards down. Kraven isn’t a hero, he isn’t good but the film works on proving that he is with his every decision until it serves right for the plot. After a quick introduction, much of the film takes place in the past as Sergei and Dimitri’s toxic childhood is explored — more like explained. We also get a montage of how he trains in the jungle as a child while honing his powers, super strength and other abilities. He also takes down many animal poachers but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really add any dept to his role in the film. It could serve as his connection to the animal world, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t as effective due to a lack of authentic interaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 08:42:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dune: Prophecy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dune-prophecy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:46:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/dune-prophecy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;HBO has wrapped for the first season of Dune Prophecy which also starred our very own Tabu in the role of a Sister working with The Sisterhood aka Bene Gesserit, widely known in the Dune Universe. The show takes place 10,000 years before the current films directed by Denis Villeneuve. But the prequel is still connected to the current storyline as it explores the lore of how the Bene Gesserit prophecy about Paul Atreides came into being. The show begins with the story of two Harkonnen sisters who have been accepted into the sisterhood. One of them, Valya Harkonnen had special powers which let me control the will of others on her command, she goes on to teach the same to others in the sisters who followed the same values as her. Meanwhile, another has her own secrets to protect. The sisterhood also has factions, while one believes in nurturing the good in humans and use the power of truth sense to lead humanity towards a better future after the War with Thinking Machine which destroyed the world. The other faction believes, that humans need a genetically enhanced leader to take them to the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What If S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/what-if-s03-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 08:44:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/what-if-s03-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What If&amp;hellip;? returned with season 3 sharing a deep dive into the 5th dimension and hinted at what we can expect from the future of the multiverse. The show does show Sam Wilson as the new Captain America on a world saving mission with Bruce Banner and others. Meanwhile, more magical and mystical creatures come to life as the Watcher guides more superheroes to save their universes. With every season of What If&amp;hellip;? Marvel continues to surprise their fans with something unexpected, the same is true for season 3 as the multiverse gets more weird and messy. Each episode shared a piece of a story from a different universe and what canon event may have shaped it. It also reveals how The Watcher sees it, and experiences it, the changes he would have expected and wished for. In the past seasons, The Watcher had gotten himself involved in the multiverse by saving lives and reshaping the world. As he continues to do so, it leaves The Eminence unhappy. That too shapes a path for the mortals to move on to a new dimension and turn their fate over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mufasa: The Lion King</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 09:02:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mufasa-the-lion-king-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mufasa is the prequel to the Disney&amp;rsquo;s iconic film The Lion King. However, the film takes a different route than a typical prequel, we also get to see a follow-up plotline for Simba, Nala and their kids along with what&amp;rsquo;s going on at Pride Rock aka Milele. The Hindi Dub remains as close to the original names and essence of the characters while also adding a bit of a twist. While Simba and his family remain the prideful ruling family of Pride&amp;rsquo;s land, Timon, Pumbaa and some supporting characters get a twist with the Hindi Dub adding more comedy to the screenplay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 20:31:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Singham Again made quite the impression with its short film for a trailer. It also led to the perception that the film won&amp;rsquo;t have much to offer after everything was revealed in the teasers and trailers. And yet the film surprises with its comedy and its Ramayan connective direction. Rohit Shetty does warn his audience and the religious critics that the film is not meant to disrespect anyone&amp;rsquo;s faith or any religion with a two-minute long disclaimer and what follows is a cameo-filled film with a run time of 144 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel: Honey Bunny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 20:31:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The show fits right into the style of Raj and DK sans the comedy, the rawness and the drama will keep you hooked for a while. Set in the 90s and early 2000s it focuses on the lack of technology and old-school espionage. Its sequences set in the 90s will remind audiences of old movies like the action remains grounded to today’s time. The makers find a good mix of old aesthetics, cinematography and modern writing for spy thrillers. The show has ups and downs, but performances like that of Kay Kay Menon will bring you back to the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 23:44:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Co produced by Kriti Sanon and Kanika Dhillon the film suffers from lack of consistency possibly from the writing stage. The film aims to spread awareness about women and domestic abuse, it attempts to express the turmoils of abuse trauma, its generational history but fails to do it through out the run time. The film tries hard to be It Suspect X (Jaane Jaan), It Ends With Us, Gone Girl and The Girl In The Train all at once with a crime thriller genre — it ends up being none of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Shameless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-shameless/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:22:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-shameless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Shameless became highly recognizable after its Cannes 2024 victory. The film&amp;rsquo;s leading star Anasuya Sengupta made history and became the first Indian actor to win the Best Actress Award at Cannes. The film explores the story of two polar women stuck in the world of prostitution finding hope in each other, but the bleakness and grim reality of the world is always just around the corner to take it away. The film though dramatic and dark has much appreciative theatrical performances with wit of Sengupta&amp;rsquo;s abrasive character. Devi and Renuka keep the story balanced but the outcome is left for the audience to endure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Santosh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/santosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:19:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/santosh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Santosh which has been making rounds in the top film festivals including Cannes is by the British-Indian director Sandhya Suri. Focusing on the state of rural India through the eyes of a young femal cop, the film is is Suri&amp;rsquo;s first fiction feature, which can be seen in its rawness and sincerity. The film is led by Shahana Goswami and Sunita Rajwar as cops on the other side of the law, and their performances are unforgettable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 20:16:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Girls Will Be Girls is helmed by first time feature film director Suchi Talati. It follows the story of a high school top student in a coming of age story. But the story isn&amp;rsquo;t just about Mira played by Preeti Panigrahi but also about her mom Anila played by Kani Kusruti. Their complex relationship amid Mira&amp;rsquo;s rebellious romance with NRI boy Sri (Kesav Binoy Kiron), the tense environment in strict school. The film offers a change for millennials to live through some of their most embarrassing and traumatizing memories but also gives a chance to many more in building a better and more nutriting relationship with their mothers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apprentice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-apprentice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 20:15:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-apprentice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Apprentice is one of the film that no one asked for but now that its here you can&amp;rsquo;t look away from it. The direction, cinematography, lighting, sets and most of all the performances all are worth praising but the film majorly avoids taking sides. For first half it makes you like Trump and for the other the pre-existing hate returns, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really add to his public narrative, the reason for its existence left questioning. But the film is worth the watch for its art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Robot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 16:03:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-wild-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Wild Robot was one of the most anticipated films since its first teaser dropped with the song &amp;lsquo;What a Wonderful World&amp;rsquo; and the film has lived up to its hype. Not only does it offer an adorable story for kids to watch but it also comes with heavy context and geological subtext that is enough to keep the adults engaged. The film unexpectedly also offers much humour and some emotional moments but best yet has been the artwork throughout the run time. From birds taking flight and colouring the sky, to the moving leaves that breathe life into the art, the film comes with a great re-watch value ready to turn it into a classic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel Diana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-diana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:08:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-diana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citadel Diana is one of the many spin-offs set around the American Citadel led by Priyanka Chopra. The series explores the world of a covet organisation across the globe trying to take down the world&amp;rsquo;s most evil organisation Manticore. While Citadel carried the story more straightforward, Citadel vs Manticore, we get to see a different side in Diana. The Italian show led by Matilda De Angelis, Lorenzo Cervasio and Maurizio Lombardi explores more on the side of how things are done at Manticore. Released in Italian, with few dialogues in English, the show is expected to have a stronger opening than Citadel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vicky Vidya Ka Woh Wala Video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:05:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rajkummar Rao and Triptii Dimri’s latest release Vicky Vidya Ka Woh Wala Video is a social comedy that focuses on the length of the story more than logic. With a shorter, more crisp story the film would have managed to give the very serious and important message it wishes to. The film is a cautionary tale in the 1990s but the fear is very relevant and still prevalent given the growing use of AI, instead of finding a way to incorporate the fear throughout, the story focuses a bit too much on the comedy punch lines and hopes a long monologue will make up for the rest. But it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
