<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crime Beat on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/crime-beat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crime Beat on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:17:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/crime-beat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crime Beat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crime-beat-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:17:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crime-beat-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fine line between journalism and sensationalism is fast becoming wafer-thin. Even those not privy to the world of journalism are aware of the falsehoods the media propagates in search of truth. So, what can the showrunner of ‘Crime Beat’, Sudhir Mishra, tell us what we already don’t know, or go beyond what Hansal Mehta’s ‘Scoop’ or ‘The Broken News’ offered? ‘Crime Beat’, like Mehta’s ‘Scoop’, is very much an insider account of investigative journalism. Based on the novel ‘The Price You Pay’ by Somnath Batabyal, who spent a decade covering crime, it takes us into the heart of news gatherers. Set in 2011 in New Delhi, a journalist, Abhishek Sinha (Saqib Saleem), in pursuit of page one stories even recreates the drama for a story. Of course, before we meet the protagonist of the series, we are introduced to Binny Chaudhry (Rahul Bhat). Hailed as a messiah, he is on the verge of surrendering to the police but before we get to know who he is, he is shot dead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crime Beat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crime-beat-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 23:19:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crime-beat-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A significant addition to the small canon of Indian media industry dramas, Crime Beat, like Scoop before it, is based on a book written by a journalist who was in the thick of the action that forms the core of the series. Even its fictional elements largely flow from fact. The Zee5 series is marked by realism, an attribute that stems from its abjuration of overt generic flourishes. The dialogues co-written by the author of the novel (The Price You Pay, published in 2013)—scribe-turned academic Somnath Batabyal—contribute conversational authenticity to the show. Crime Beat investigates the Delhi underworld, the media&amp;rsquo;s attritional brushes with it and with men in uniform charged with keeping crime in check in the city. The lines that separate the three domains from each other as well as from party politics are frequently blurred, even erased.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crime Beat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crime-beat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 17:26:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/crime-beat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve seen Broken News. You know how rival channels work, ethics versus TRPs. You’ve seen Dhamaka and newsroom ambitions that prevail over national security. You’ve seen Despatch, the print medium giving way to digital. You’ve also seen umpteen movies and shows centred around a dreaded criminal, cops, journalists and politicians. You know that cops on the take, on the payroll of businessmen, ministers and opposition leaders, contribute to regular cinematic fodder. The show begins with someone with a huge following stepping out. Binny Chaudhry has surrendered, scream assorted TV anchors. And Binny is shot. The rest is a flashback to return to this moment at the end. Sudhir Mishra who takes the credit as showrunner and director (along with Sanjeev Kaul), picks up a book titled The Price You Pay and proceeds to build Binny Chaudhry (Rahul Bhat) as an uncatchable criminal with hawala rackets, kidnappings and ransom money that he showers like confetti over Indirapuram, the place he grew up in Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
