<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bandish Bandits S02 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bandish-bandits-s02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bandish Bandits S02 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:31:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/bandish-bandits-s02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bandish Bandits S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 12:31:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When ‘Bandish Bandits’ streamed on Prime Video in 2020, it was a breath of fresh air wrapped in melody and a master class in classical music. As it enters the second season, there is good news and a bit of bad news. First the downside: what it did not succumb to in the first season, it has done so in the second outing and turned into an ‘Indian Idol’ of sorts. Here, the major part of the series is devoted to the India Band Championship. Of course, on the sunny side, it is still an ode to music, now of various hues, and the master class continues. You will still learn more than a thing or two about ragas. Only, this time, we get to hear and see the exponents of contemporary music too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandish Bandits S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:30:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our autograph books way back in school, a favourite verse was, “East is East, West is West. When they meet, it’s the best.” Bandish Bandits makes the same point, embellishing it with blended, mood-elevating music. There’s usually an ambience-fatigue when a fresh premise goes into a second season and struggles to say something new. Kota Factory, Mirzapur, Undekhi and Aarya are prime examples of ambience-fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anand Tiwari who writes, creates and directs, manages to duck the syndrome even as he continues to root for the Rathod gharana in Rajasthan while exploring new locations like Himachal Pradesh. With successor Radhe (Ritwik Bhowmik), opponent Digvijay (Atul Kulkarni), parents Mohini (Sheeba Chadha) and Rajendra (Rajesh Tailang) and on-off girlfriend Tamanna (Shreya Chaudhry) in their respective roles, new entrants, mentor Nandini Singh (Divya Dutta), students Ayaan (Rohan Gurbaxani) and Soumya (Yashaswini&#xA;Dayama), plus poet Imroz (Arjun Rampal), add their own musical notes to the main theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandish Bandits S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:27:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second season of the Prime Video series Bandish Bandits opens in Jodhpur, three months after Radhe (Ritwik Bhowmik) has been crowned Sangeet Samrat. In the previous season, battle lines were drawn between rival gharanas represented by Radhe and his grandfather Radhemohan (Naseeruddin Shah) on the one side and Radhemohan’s estranged son Digvijay (Atul Kulkarni) on the other. With the passing of the patriarch, the responsibility for the Rathod gharana rests on Radhe’s shoulders. Radhe is also contending with new and confusing feelings after Tammana (Shreya Chaudhry) walks away from their fusion band Bandish Bandits, and her relationship with him, to find her own voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandish Bandits S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 12:51:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The face-off between tradition and modernity, past and present, the strict rules of gharana-and-parampara vs doing-your-own-thing, which were the key notes of the first season of ‘Bandish Bandits’, are back again in the second. As are many of the actors, reprising their roles, along with new faces, as the story takes off from where it left off, back in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four years is quite a gap between the two seasons, but it is reassuring to see that the show, directed by Tiwari, who has a co-writing credit with Atmika Didwania and Karan Singh Tyagi, has kept its focus on music and musicians, even as it has added new strands in the plot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
