<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Udita Jhunjhunwala on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/udita-jhunjhunwala/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Udita Jhunjhunwala on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:48:16 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/udita-jhunjhunwala/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Snow White</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/snow-white-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:48:16 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/snow-white-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yet another remake of yet another often retold Disney classic is revisited as the Marc Webb-directed musical Snow White. Featuring a mix of new and old songs, a fresh cast, the same story by the Brothers Grimm rehashed by writer Erin Cressida Wilson, and some new but questionable creative ideas. Snow White is thus named by her perfect parents, the King and Queen, because she was born on a snowy night. They lead a happy life, spreading joy among their happy subjects. Young Snow White (Emilia Faucher) makes delicious apple pies for all the townspeople as they sing along merrily. But after her mother dies, her father remarries a beautiful woman who turns out to be singularly evil. This spells the end of the kingdom’s days of plenty, and long-term servitude for Snow White. Gal Gadot, with all the regalia, is the menacing Evil Queen, adorned in gems and drenched in complex vanity and greed. She repeatedly seeks validation from the magical mirror. But her evil reaches a new high when she is threatened by Snow White’s beauty and grace, condemning her stepdaughter to death. However, Snow White manages to escape and finds shelter in the unlikely company of seven dwarves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Happy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/be-happy-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:32:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/be-happy-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After playing the chronically ill father of a young girl in I Want to Talk, Abhishek Bachchan plays a different kind of dad in Be Happy. In this dance-drama, streaming on Amazon Prime, the actor plays a widower raising a daughter who has an unshakable passion and talent for dance. Helmed by choreographer-director Remo D’Souza, Be Happy, written by D’Souza, Kanishka Singh Deo, Chirag Garg and Tushar Hirandanani, is built on the foundations of a father-daughter relationship and dance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Captain America Brave New World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 19:05:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/captain-america-brave-new-world-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Bruce Banner—The Hulk—is looking for a cure for his unusual rage transformation, he seeks help from maverick scientist Samuel Sterns. Their collaboration faces resistance from General Thaddeus “Thunderbolt” Ross, who is hell-bent on stopping Banner because the giant, angry, green Hulk is dating the general’s daughter, Betty. Ross also wants to harness the gamma tech to his own advantage to create an adequate foil for The Hulk. The resultant creation, dubbed the Abomination, clashes with The Hulk, leading to the destruction of Harlem and a permanent scar on Ross’ reputation. This summary of the 2008 film The Incredible Hulk, which starred Edward Norton as Bruce Banner, Tim Blake Nelson as Samuel Sterns, Liv Tyler as Betty Ross, and William Hurt as General Ross, is crucial to understanding Captain America: Brave New World.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridget Jones: Mad About the Boy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:51:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bridget-jones-mad-about-the-boy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Author Helen Fielding’s first novel about a single, thirty-something woman living in London was released in 1996. The novel was adapted into a movie in 2001, with the heroine of Bridget Jones’s Diary returning in a movie sequel titled Bridget Jones: The Edge of Reason in 2004. American actress Renée Zellweger has starred as Bridget Jones in all four films based on Fielding’s writing, which, in part, is the writer’s homage to Jane Austen’s Pride and Prejudice. It’s no coincidence that Bridget’s love interest is called Mark Darcy, played by Colin Firth, who famously portrayed Mr. Fitzwilliam Darcy in the 1995 TV adaptation of Austen’s novel. The latest, Bridget Jones: Mad About The Boy, is the fourth film (the last was Bridget Jones’s Baby, from 2016) about the life and loves of Bridget Jones. Michael Morris directs a screenplay by Fielding, Dan Mazer, and Abi Morgan. The film explores themes of loss, resilience, and self-discovery while still delivering the trademark awkwardness and comedic situations that have defined Bridget’s character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Storyteller</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-storyteller-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:37:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-storyteller-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Director Ananth Narayan Mahadevan, in partnership with writer Kireet Khurana, has extended Satyajit Ray’s short story Golpo Boliye Tarini Khuro into The Storyteller, a 116-minute drama available on Disney+ Hotstar. Tarini Bandopadhyay (Paresh Rawal) is a recently retired writer, whose longest assignment lasted 13 weeks. He’s a widower who is content with his Calcutta life and takes meticulous care of his Ambassador car. Conversations with his fellow comrades, over fish fry and fish curry, are rarely without mention of Capitalism and its ills and almost always end with ‘Tarini tales’. Tarini is a wonderful storyteller. Even after his wife gifted him a pen to encourage him, Tarini never recorded his imaginative and original stories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Dreams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sweet-dreams-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 08:39:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sweet-dreams-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the title itself, it’s a giveaway that this romcom is going to be rife in clichés and oozing cheesiness. In that sense, writer-director Victor Mukherjee’s 107-minute-long film does not disappoint. Kenneth ‘Kenny’ Fernandes (Amol Parashar) is a recycle artist and social media influencer who is nursing a broken heart and often posts philosophical and pensive posts about dreams, feelings etc. These read like memes or the kind of ‘good quotes’ one could Google up. But what is baffling Kenny at this time, is a recurring dream featuring a date with an attractive young woman in a coffee shop. Said woman does exist. Somewhere else, an aspiring and ambivalent musician called Diya Jaisingh (Mithila Palkar) is experiencing the same dream, featuring Kenny and the same coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Real Pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 22:29:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/a-real-pain-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“This will be a tour about pain,” cautions James, the earnest British guide shepherding a group of American Jews on a tour of Poland. The small group includes David and Benji, two cousins from New York on a visit to Poland to honour their recently deceased grandmother Dori, a Polish Jew who survived the Holocaust. Best known for this starring role as Mark Zuckerberg in The Social Network, Jesse Eisenberg writes, directs and stars in this holocaust comedy playing David, who like Eisenberg, suffers from OCD and anxiety disorder. David has a regular job, a wife and child and uses pills to deal with his anxiety. He’s socially awkward and envies Benji’s ease and charm. Benji road-rolls his cousin and trivialises his life choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Girls Will Be Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 08:49:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/girls-will-be-girls-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writer-director Shuchi Talati’s debut feature is a simmering and sexually tense coming of age drama. Set in a boarding school, the story is centred around Mira, a school topper, head prefect and teacher’s pet. She’s driven to excel and considers herself the model student, upholder of school rules and moral gatekeeper. So, it’s confusing for the obedient and righteous Mira to be faced with challenges outside of the curriculum and to realise that book-learned knowledge might be no match against street smarts, life experience and generational patriarchal conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bandish Bandits S02</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:27:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bandish-bandits-s02-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second season of the Prime Video series Bandish Bandits opens in Jodhpur, three months after Radhe (Ritwik Bhowmik) has been crowned Sangeet Samrat. In the previous season, battle lines were drawn between rival gharanas represented by Radhe and his grandfather Radhemohan (Naseeruddin Shah) on the one side and Radhemohan’s estranged son Digvijay (Atul Kulkarni) on the other. With the passing of the patriarch, the responsibility for the Rathod gharana rests on Radhe’s shoulders. Radhe is also contending with new and confusing feelings after Tammana (Shreya Chaudhry) walks away from their fusion band Bandish Bandits, and her relationship with him, to find her own voice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Judy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/judy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 10:50:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/judy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a child star is not a thing to envy. Judy, a musical drama, is both a warm and loving tribute to the actor and singer Judy Garland as well as a cautionary tale about the pressures and impact of celebrity. Born Frances Ethel Gumm, Garland worked as an actor, dancer and singer for 45 of the 47 years she lived. The film opens with a 14-year-old Judy (Darci Shaw) being cast to play what would become the iconic part of Dorothy in The Wizard of Oz. The pressure of early stardom and humiliation fuelled insecurities as a harsh studio executive listed out her physical flaws. He described her as above average but exceptional because of her singing voice. A studio minder offered her pills to suppress her appetite and pills to help her sleep at night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent of Happiness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agent-of-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:59:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/agent-of-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the late 1970s, the king of Bhutan coined the term “gross national happiness&amp;quot;. GNH parameters are used to measure progress, well-being and happiness, placing their importance over economic pursuits alone. This programme has been pivotal in shaping development policies and governance in Bhutan, a landlocked nation in eastern Himalayas that is often ranked as one of the happiest in the world. Happiness surveyor Amber Kumar Gurung of the Happiness Centre is the subject of a new documentary, &lt;em&gt;Agent of Happiness&lt;/em&gt; (in competition at the MAMI Mumbai film festival 2024).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Singham Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:57:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/singham-again-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even before a gun is fired or a car destroyed in director Rohit Shetty’s latest cop-and-terrorist saga, a disclaimer is read out in two languages—about mentions of a Hindu god and respect for beliefs. When you consider that Singham Again is built on the bedrock of the epic, Ramayana—with Ajay Devgn’s Bajirao Singham likened to Lord Rama—, the disclaimer seems like a safe bet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:23:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/bhool-bhulaiyaa-3-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2007, Priyadarshan directed Vidya Balan as the ghostly apparition Manjulika in Bhool Bhulaiyaa, with Aneez Bazmee taking over the reins of this comedy-horror franchise in 2022. Akshay Kumar was replaced by Kartik Aaryan, who played Ruhaan—a charlatan masquerading as a psychic, who communicates with and channels spirits. Tabu stepped into the dual roles of the trapped spirit, Manjulika, and her twin sister, Anjulika.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In part three, Bazmee reinvents the wheel, casting Vidya Balan and Madhuri Dixit as the (maybe) Manjulikas. However, the presence of these two seasoned actresses in one film does not amount to much. In fact, it’s a wasted opportunity. While you have two times the Manjulikas, Bhool Bhulaiyaa 3 is half the fun. Even Kartik Aaryan comes across as fatigued, with his character Rooh Baba’s fake ghostbusting antics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mithya: The Darker Chapter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-darker-chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 11:07:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mithya-the-darker-chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first season of the ZEE5 series Mithya, Hindi professor Juhi Adhikari (Huma Qureshi) was locked in a dangerous battle with student Rhea Rajguru (Avantika Dassani) after she failed her the young woman for plagiarism and branded her a cheat. The entitled daughter of a tea estate owner and college trustee, Rhea became obsessed with seeking vengeance, sometimes with violent results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It emerged in season one that Juhi and Rhea were half-sisters. Rhea’s vendetta has now become as much about getting back at Juhi as it is about gaining the acceptance of her father, the author Anand Tyagi (Rajit Kapur).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vicky Vidya Ka Woh Wala Video</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 13:48:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/vicky-vidya-ka-woh-wala-video-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year is 1997. The setting is Rishikesh. It’s a time just before mobile phones, when DVDs were still predominant. Writer-director Raaj Shaandilyaa’s film opens with a shoddily executed computer graphic of a train hurtling towards a forlorn man on the tracks. This is the eponymous Vicky, played by Rajkummar Rao. It’s much like Rao’s year which has been speeding along strongly, but will eventually have to come to a halt. Unfortunately, the Rao train has been derailed by this most unintelligible 152-minute-long romantic comedy that is built around a slim plot line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sector 36</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sector-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 11:27:55 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sector-36/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sector 36, based on the gruesome murders of Nithari village in Noida, which were uncovered in 2007, follows a serial killer who lives in plain sight. In Aditya Nimbalkar’s crime drama, Prem (Vikrant Massey) is the house-help of Balbir Bassi (Akash Khurana), an affluent businessman from Karnal. Bassi rarely visits his palatial bungalow in Delhi’s Sector 36, but when he does, his actions are also creepy. Prem, taking advantage of his unsupervised existence, far from his own family that lives in a village, abducts children from the neighbouring migrant settlement, mercilessly killing them to satisfy his deviant appetite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
