<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daredevil: Born Again on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/daredevil-born-again/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daredevil: Born Again on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:59:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/daredevil-born-again/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daredevil: Born Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daredevil-born-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 22:59:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daredevil-born-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daredevil has returned once again to the small screen, making his office debut for his solo series. The show, led by Charlie Cox, will also be following the story of Vincent D&amp;rsquo;Onofrio&amp;rsquo;s Kingpin aka Fisk. Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s return to the MCU is after the long-running series and spin-off like Defenders on Netflix. The series was dropped a couple of years ago, but Cox made several appearances in other MCU films and projects including Spider-Man No Way Home, Echo, She-Hulk and more. Moving forward with Kingpin&amp;rsquo;s Arc through the MCU and Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s past in the Netflix show, the new series is all set to pit them against each other in a new setting. With Fisk as Mayor of New York, and Murdock hanging up his suit, the city brings out the worst in both of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daredevil: Born Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daredevil-born-again-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 20:13:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/daredevil-born-again-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first Daredevil series was launched nearly a decade ago on Netflix and lasted for three seasons. Much has changed in the Daredevil universe, and we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Matt Murdock, aka Daredevil, pop up in the MCU to interact with other characters. However, it is great to see him back in his own show, Daredevil: Born Again, tackling new cases and standing up to Kingpin, aka Wilson Fisk, again. The actors who play these characters step right back into it as the nine-episode series sets up a new collision course for Daredevil and Kingpin. The relative peace of the law firm Nelson Page and Murdock is shattered by a tragic event in the premiere, which spurs Matt (Charlie Cox) to retire his Daredevil persona for a bit. Meanwhile, Wilson Fisk (Vincent D&amp;rsquo;Onofrio) returns after an assassination attempt with a renewed sense of responsibility and decides to run for mayor of New York City. A more sober Matt is focused on his law firm, while Fisk wants to be the people&amp;rsquo;s politician who wants to rid the city of all its vigilantes. The former rivals have their radars set on high again as events keep pulling them back in each other&amp;rsquo;s orbit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
