<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The White Lotus S03 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-white-lotus-s03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The White Lotus S03 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:13:56 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/the-white-lotus-s03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The White Lotus S03</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-white-lotus-s03-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:13:56 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-white-lotus-s03-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The White Lotus Season 3 returns after two years with a new group of guests that converge at a luxury resort for a getaway. Of course, their stay is eventful as the looming murder of one of the group is hinted at from the start. Mike White&amp;rsquo;s Emmy Award-winning series moves to Asia for the latest installment as Thailand is the setting for this story. Even though White&amp;rsquo;s narrative moves along glacially, there is enough to keep viewers intrigued. This year&amp;rsquo;s guests include a trio of best friends, played by Leslie Bibb, Carrie Coon, and Michelle Monaghan; a rich white family led by actors Jason Isaacs and Parker Posey; and a mismatched couple, both in age and temperament, played by Walter Goggins and Aimee Lou Wood. The only familiar face for viewers is spa worker Belinda (Natasha Rothwell), who was present in the first season. With each day, White shows another facet of their complicated relationships with one another as well as their hopes for the future. But which one of these guests is the fallen victim? Mike White is once again the creative force behind this season, which focuses more on individual characters than on an overall arc. The Western guests&amp;rsquo; storylines have more prominence this time. However, the narratives for the Thai staff, security guard Gaitok (Tayme Thapthimthong) and hotel worker Mook (Blackpink&amp;rsquo;s Lisa), are promising. Lek Patravadi also stands out as resort owner Sritala. However, so far, without giving away too many spoilers, most of the characters are circling around one another, hiding away true motives. It&amp;rsquo;s the same story structure as previous seasons, like some of the guests being resistant to wellness programs, just in a new aesthetic setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
