<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>L2: Empuraan on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/l2-empuraan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in L2: Empuraan on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 16:04:15 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/l2-empuraan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 16:04:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Empuraan, the sequel to the 2019 Malayalam film Lucifer, is a high-budget, globe-trotting actioner reminiscent of productions from YRF or the Tamil and Telugu film industry. The success of its predecessor has elevated the scale and ambition of this installment. However, with such ambition often comes the risk of overlooking essential elements in favor of a grander vision. In this instance, the screenplay suffers due to an emphasis on extravagant action, where style frequently overshadows substance.&#xA;At nearly three hours in length, the film initially packs in a great deal of content but later tends to meander. Prithviraj, who has transitioned from actor to director, possesses the vision necessary for a project of this magnitude, yet the foundational material must be robust. The film clearly aims to appeal to mass audiences, featuring slow-motion sequences and other stylistic choices. While there is nothing inherently wrong with this approach, it occasionally aspires to get serious,, and the fusion of these elements does not always produce the desired effect. It is helpful to recall key details from Lucifer, which was released five years ago. The narrative reintroduces international crime syndicates and the underworld, with Khureshi (Mohanlal) returning to the fray. Regrettably, the local character Stephen Nedumpally, also portrayed by Mohanlal and central to the action in Lucifer, takes a back seat in this sequel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:28:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much solemn politics is too much solemn politics in an out-and-out action movie that aspires to be much more than just a vehicle for three of Kerala&amp;rsquo;s top male stars? No matter what L2: Empuraan, toplined by a superstar who has ruled the roost for decades and helmed by another who pulls out the stops both as director and actor, packs into its three hours by way of larger commentary, the gap between intent and result not only refuses to go away, but also fluctuates wildly. There is, of course, no known limit to what degree, and sort, of topical relevance a thriller must attain in order to break free of its genre confines and assume elevating social significance. L2: Empuraan, a Malayalam tentpole production whose Hindi dub is in theatres nationwide, is anything but frugal with its barbs at the abuse of power and the pitfalls of personality cults. The second part of a planned trilogy that began with the 2019 hit Lucifer, this Prithviraj Sukumaran-directed potboiler mixes up its visceral chops, ultra-violent spirals into excess and visual pizzazz with all-out attempts to show up forces that are out to destabilise Kerala in a fictional world that intermittently mirrors the real one in which those in authority lay down the rules to suit their immediate agendas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:14:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EWdhYsOcQos?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 09:50:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was 2019. It was when actor Prithviraj Sukumaran turned director for the first time. When Lucifer, starring Mohanlal, one of the big Ms of Mollywood, hit theatres, it transcended borders. Lucifer found love not just in Kerala, but in other parts of the country, thanks to its layered storyline, which helped audiences find new details with every re-watch. Five years later, Lucifer&amp;rsquo;s sequel Empuraan has hit theatres with a big budget and bigger expectations. Kerala Chief Minister Jathin Ramdas (Tovino Thomas) is facing multiple charges of corruption and failure to uphold the values of his late father Ramdas (Sachin Khedekar). Meanwhile, the people of Kerala are disappointed, and he is facing opposition from a new political party with Hindutva ideals. Then there is Khuresh Ab&amp;rsquo;raam (Mohanlal), with his mysterious persona tackling the Kabuka clan. The local unrest in Kerala and the dwindling political climate make room for Ab&amp;rsquo;raam&amp;rsquo;s entry into the state to set things straight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 09:47:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A movie becomes more violent the further it gets from movie violence. Movie violence insulates. It excites, titillates, comforts. It reassures audiences that what they’re seeing isn’t real and need not be taken too seriously. A realistic punch in the face registers more strongly than a hero sending half a dozen bodies flying through the air. Movie violence has no wish to distress or dismay, or to remind you of violence in the real world. The opening credits of Prithviraj Sukumaran’s L2: Empuraan, a sequel to his Lucifer (2019), show the burning of a train compartment with Hindu passengers in 2002, as had happened in Godhra, Gujarat that year. The sequence that follows shows the bloody reprisal, as Hindu mobs go on the rampage. It has the hallmarks of Indian movie violence—a truck barreling through a gate, sword-wielding goons leaping through the air, speed ramping, various things on fire—but the idea is to disturb and reckon with history. A group of Muslims offered shelter by a Hindu landowner are ambushed, sexually assaulted, burnt alive and otherwise brutally murdered. The reference to the Naroda Patiya massacre, in which 97 Muslims were killed in a day, is made clear by naming the chief perpetrator Baba Bajrangi (one of the actual accused was Bajrang Dal leader Babu Bajrangi).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:26:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The genius of Lucifer and Empuraan is that, despite spanning more than six hours of runtime (two films put together), the filmmakers continue to maintain the suspense about the origin of Stephen Nedumpalley (Mohanlal). What’s more impressive is the way director Prithviraj has scaled up this character. Stephen is not just a political kingmaker anymore. In Empuraan, he becomes much more, and to be honest, the conflict in Empuraan seems to be too small for him. That’s the downside of the film, as the villains are no match for the powers of Stephen. The first part, Lucifer, ended with a major reveal that Stephen Nedumpalley is a crime lord named Khureshi Abraham, a most wanted leader of an international syndicate. While Lucifer showed us, Stephen, Empuraan unravels his other facet: Khureshi Abraham. The film opens with a flashback to a violent riot in India. Director Prithviraj is clever in not delving into the details of the riot. Yet, the animated sequence of a burning train that kills Hindu pilgrims is enough to deliver the intended message. The aftermath of the riot leads to bloodshed and we find a kid named Zayed Masood, a lone survivor of a small Muslim community, which gets butchered, raped, and killed by Balraj (Abhimanyu Singh) and his bloodthirsty mob.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:23:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/glrMsiklFfw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:20:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/z_dakM5YuWw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:18:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;L2: Empuraan is the sequel to 2019’s Lucifer and the second instalment in a planned trilogy. The movie, which is now in theatres, continues the tale of the dreaded criminal Khureshi Ab’ram (or Stephen Nedumpally), who we learned in the first movie is not the axis of evil as many had thought. In fact, he and his gang fight injustice all over the world. The movie’s ending and that post-credit scene leave more questions than answers. Here is all you need to know about L2: Empuraan, its plot, ending, cast, release date, trailer, and a review. The film brings superstar Mohanlal back in the titular role. The film is once again about the intersection of politics, religion, and crime. The plot is set about five years after the original. Five years is also the length of a Chief Minister’s full term in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:16:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Symbolism in art is inherently indirect, but in Prithviraj Sukumaran’s Empuraan it is thrown at your face, one ‘L’ at a time, to remind us of the omnipotent anti-hero Lucifer. Part of a broken cross atop a rundown church falls down, landing in slow motion as an ‘L’. Later, a burning tree branch falls perfectly as an ‘L’. If the ‘L’eft bottom corner of the screen were ‘L’it up, one could have savoured an ‘L’ for the whole ‘L’ength of the film. Part of Empuraan’s many problems lies in this over-reliance on the internationally notorious, shadowy figure of Khureshi Ab’raam aka Lucifer while relegating his local avatar Stephen Nedumpally (Mohanlal), the central figure of the first part, to a mere guest appearance. Now, Lucifer (2019) was a flawed film which in its post-release afterlife was turned into the holy grail of Malayalam commercial filmmaking, although it pales in comparison with the best of commercial entertainers of the 1980s and 90s. Yet, it had something going for it. Empuraan has hardly anything going for it, except for the richness of its production design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Lucifer universe, created and written by Murali Gopy and directed by Prithviraj Sukumaran, one of the most exciting characters is Baiju Santhosh’s Murukan. A party worker and spy as well as a stand-in for occasional outsider commentary, his quips and nonchalance offer breathing space in the two films that otherwise are busy and eventful. In the sequel, L2: Empuraan, he lists a three-point spiel to accompany a tertiary character’s ascendance. It is momentous, funny and pointed, and has little to do with either Mohanlal or Prithviraj, the pair that forms the pivot for this film, but that is also why it is joyous and spellbinding within the larger philosophy contained in the story. A quickfire lesson in politicking dispensed with ease. The rest of L2: Empuraan is not as lean. It is packed with backstories and details, with word pairs that sound like they were picked from a raffle, like God Axis and Shen Triad. Mohanlal’s Stephen Nedumpally aka Khureshi Ab’raam teleports and levitates. One day he is in Iraq, another day he is somewhere in central Africa. And a few minutes later he is in a developed country in the west. And then makes a grand appearance in Nedumpally, Kerala.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 18:38:41 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मलयालम सिनेमा के जाने-माने ऐक्टर पृथ्वीराज सुकुमारन ने साल 2019 में फिल्म लुसिफर से निर्देशन में कदम रखा था। दिग्गज अभिनेता मोहनलाल की मुख्य भूमिका वाली इस फिल्म ने तब रेकॉर्ड कामयाबी हासिल की थी। फिल्म को सिर्फ केरल ही नहीं, अन्य राज्यों के दर्शकों ने भी खूब पसंद किया था। इसलिए, पृथ्वीराज सुकुमारन अब इसका सीक्वल L2 : एम्पुरान पैन इंडिया लेवल पर पांच भाषाओं हिंदी, अंग्रेजी, तमिल, तेलुगु और मलयालम में लेकर आए हैं। एम्पुरान का मतलब ही होता है- ऐसा महान राजा, जिसका दर्जा बस भगवान से ही कम हो। लिहाजा, इस बार फिल्म का स्केल भी कहीं ज्यादा बड़ा है। दुनिया के अलग-अलग लोकेशंस पर बड़े-बड़े शॉट्स फिल्म का आकर्षण है। लेकिन इस स्टाइल, भव्यता, चमक-दमक के बीच कहानी कमजोर रह गई है। इस बार कहानी में लुसिफर वाली गहराई और पकड़ नदारद है।&#xA;कहानी लुसिफर का टैग पाने वाले स्टीफन नेदूंपल्ली उर्फ कुरैशी अब्राम (मोहनलाल) के एम्पुरान यानी और ताकतवर बनने की है। उसकी दुनिया केरल से निकलकर इंटरनैशनल हो चुकी है। अपने दत्तक पिता रामदास (सचिन खेडेकर) के निधन के बाद सत्ता उनके पुत्र जतिन (टोविनो थॉमस) को सौंपकर स्टीफन एक अंतरराष्ट्रीय गैंग के सरगना के रूप में सक्रिय है, मगर यहां भी नशे के खिलाफ उसकी जंग जारी है और वह ड्रग रैकेट चलाने वाले काबूगा गैंग का सफाया करने में जुटा हुआ है। इधर, केरल की राजनीति में अलग उथल-पुथल शुरू हो जाती है। पांच साल मुख्यमंत्री बनने बाद जतिन तरह-तरह के भ्रष्टाचार में लिप्त हो चुका है। यही नहीं, आगामी इलेक्शन के लिए वह अपने पिता की पार्टी छोड़कर सांप्रदायिक ताकतों को बढ़ाने वाले नेता बाबा बजरंगी (अभिमन्यु सिंह) से हाथ मिलाकर नई पार्टी बना लेता है, जिसके विरोध में उसकी बहन प्रियदर्शिनी (मंजू वॉरियर) खुद राजनीति में उतर जाती है। वहीं, अपने राज्य को बचाने के लिए स्टीफन को भी केरल लौटना पड़ता है। अब स्टीफन की यह घर वापसी क्या गुल खिलाती है, यह जानने लिए सिनेमाघर जाना होगा।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
