<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robinhood on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/robinhood/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robinhood on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:34:17 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/robinhood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robinhood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/robinhood-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 10:34:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/robinhood-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robinhood movie review: Director Venky Kudumula loves making films that have a simple premise, a convincing lead, enjoyable songs, and a convoluted narrative seamlessly tied together with a lot of laughs. In his latest, Robinhood, all of these are in place, but with the laughs not enough, and the ambitious narrative not being supported by the writing, Venky’s dreamy house of cards crashes down. Remember Ravi Teja-Surender Reddy’s Kick? The film that was about a do-gooder thief who tries his best to outwit the system and a tough-as-nails cop, and serve the needy by robbing from the rich. The same film was remade in Tamil with Ravi Mohan, Kannada with Upendra, and Hindi with Salman Khan. Did you ever think what would happen if Nithiin starred in the rehash of the 2009 film? No, right? Neither did many others, but Venky had other plans, and he mixes elements of yet another Telugu film that Salman Khan remade in 2011 — Ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robinhood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/robinhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 19:39:08 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/robinhood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is one thing to not take yourself too seriously when you are making a comedy and another when the irreverence serves as a mask to camouflage a lazily-written and a casually-executed film. To make up for a shallow plot and the limitations of its leads, the film is desperate to elicit laughs. Apart from Nithiin and Sreeleela, the presence of multiple comedians, actors from at least half a dozen film industries, an in-form composer and a cameo by Australian cricketer David Warner try to salvage a mess. The Telugu film Robinhood, much like its title, leaves little to your imagination. An orphaned protagonist, Ram (Nithiin), takes inspiration from a school pledge to claim that the entire country is his family. In his childhood, he uses this excuse to rob the rich and helps run orphanages that are starved of funds (which is reminiscent of the Ravi Teja-starrer Kick). It is amusing that it takes the cops over a decade to focus on this case and nab the culprit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
