<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loot Kaand on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/loot-kaand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Loot Kaand on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:39:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/loot-kaand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loot Kaand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/loot-kaand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:39:20 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/loot-kaand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Latika and Palash, siblings in Purulia, a small West Bengal town, attempt a bank robbery to prevent the loss of their ancestral home. Their plan quickly spirals out of control, attracting gangsters, police officers, and robbers. Hidden secrets from their past resurface, creating further chaos. They navigate a treacherous landscape of betrayals and altering alliances and face tricky situations. Tanya Maniktala is undoubtedly a promising young talent in the digital space, but one wonders if she’s consistently underselling herself by picking a series of mediocre projects (how good was she in A Suitable Boy and Kill?) She’s good in Loot Kaand, but can’t salvage it from its chaotic execution. Sahil Mehta, as the on-screen sibling, is effective, reflecting his evolution with every opportunity. Loot Kaand, as the title suggests, is the drama woven around a robbery. Director Ruchir Arun and the writers create a situation where two flawed protagonists – siblings Latika and Palash – resort to a crime out of financial necessity, only to realise they’re not alone. They find themselves entangled in a web of an arms scam, a kidnap and run for their lives amidst deceitful, dangerous men.loot-kaand&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
