<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citadel Diana on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/citadel-diana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Citadel Diana on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 23:42:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/citadel-diana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citadel Diana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-diana-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 23:42:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-diana-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citadel, an independent spy agency, is wiped out by Manticore, a powerful syndicate that’s desperate to take charge of the world. Diana, an undercover Citadel agent, works as a mole in Manticore. She forges an unexpected rapport with Edo Zani (the heir of Manticore Italy), who is keen on taking the mantle from his father Ettore, grooming himself to be a capable leader.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matilda De Angelis, as Diana, effectively portrays the transformation of an angsty girl to an intuitive, suave agent – both physically and psychologically. Lorenzo Cervasio, playing Edo Zani, has the more interesting character and there’s adequate mystery and conflict in his performance to justify the writing. Maurizio Lombardi has an ideal authoritarian presence to pull off Ettore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel Diana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-diana/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:08:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-diana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citadel Diana is one of the many spin-offs set around the American Citadel led by Priyanka Chopra. The series explores the world of a covet organisation across the globe trying to take down the world&amp;rsquo;s most evil organisation Manticore. While Citadel carried the story more straightforward, Citadel vs Manticore, we get to see a different side in Diana. The Italian show led by Matilda De Angelis, Lorenzo Cervasio and Maurizio Lombardi explores more on the side of how things are done at Manticore. Released in Italian, with few dialogues in English, the show is expected to have a stronger opening than Citadel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
