<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zindaginama on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/zindaginama/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zindaginama on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:59:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/zindaginama/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zindaginama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/zindaginama-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 17:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/zindaginama-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;मेंटल हेल्थ हमारे समाज में लंबे समय तक एक टैबू रहा है। हालांकि, अब कुछ साल से इसके बारे में खुलकर बातें होने लगी हैं। विश्व मानसिक स्वास्थ्य दिवस (10 अक्टूबर) पर आई एंथॉलजी सीरीज &amp;lsquo;ज़िंदगीनामा&amp;rsquo; इसी मेंटल हेल्थ के प्रति जागरूकता की ओर एक मजबूत कदम है। यह सीरीज 35-40 मिनट की छह कहानियों का गुलदस्ता है, जो ईटिंग डिसऑर्डर, गेमिंग एडिक्शन, सिजोफ्रेनिया, ओसीडी, पीटीएसडी, जेंडर डिस्फोरिया जैसी अलग-अलग मानसिक समस्याओं के प्रति लोगों का ध्यान आकर्षित करती है।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zindaginama</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/zindaginama/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:16:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/zindaginama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zindaginama tackles a set of mental health issues through six episodes, targeting a different one each time. What happens when a human begins believing in an alt reality? Purple Duniya’s protagonist, a terrific Tanmay Dhanania, sets out ostensibly to go to work, like regular folks do. But that’s all a sham. His total focus lies in the game he plays obsessively, constantly, forgetting to eat or drink. Or communicate with his sister. Therapy can help, but to what extent? And who wins finally, man or machine? Sahaan Hattangadi writes, and co-directs with Danny Mamik.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
