<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uday Bhatia on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/critics/uday-bhatia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uday Bhatia on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 18:33:17 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/critics/uday-bhatia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sikandar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 18:33:17 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sikandar-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Salman Khan can barely rouse himself to act anymore. Every director since Kabir Khan in Bajrangi Bhaijaan has had to work around the actor’s limitations, to coax brief flickers of star quality and hope the rest isn’t egregious. It can’t be easy for Khan’s fans to see him this way, complacent, over the hill, indulged and lied to. The paragraph you just read applies to Sikandar but wasn’t written with it in mind. Instead, I’ve taken a line each from my reviews of his last three solo releases: Radhe, Kisi Ka Bhai Kisi Ki Jaan andTiger 3. You might say that’s lazy and unprofessional, but if Salman won’t make any effort, why should I? There’s only so many ways to say: it’s over, move on, stop embarrassing yourself. Sikandar begins with Sanjay Rajkot (Khan) thrashing a Mumbai politician’s son, whom he catches harassing a woman on a flight. We then learn that Sanjay and his wife, Saisri (Rashmika Mandanna), are the Rajkot royal family, philanthropic, benevolent and much loved by their people (the film is strangely nostalgic for ruler-subject relations). Sanjay—also called Sikandar, after Alexander the Great—has a trained militia on standby but never seems to need them, singlehandedly decimating goons sent on the orders of the aggrieved minister (Sathyaraj).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L2: Empuraan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 09:47:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/l2-empuraan-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A movie becomes more violent the further it gets from movie violence. Movie violence insulates. It excites, titillates, comforts. It reassures audiences that what they’re seeing isn’t real and need not be taken too seriously. A realistic punch in the face registers more strongly than a hero sending half a dozen bodies flying through the air. Movie violence has no wish to distress or dismay, or to remind you of violence in the real world. The opening credits of Prithviraj Sukumaran’s L2: Empuraan, a sequel to his Lucifer (2019), show the burning of a train compartment with Hindu passengers in 2002, as had happened in Godhra, Gujarat that year. The sequence that follows shows the bloody reprisal, as Hindu mobs go on the rampage. It has the hallmarks of Indian movie violence—a truck barreling through a gate, sword-wielding goons leaping through the air, speed ramping, various things on fire—but the idea is to disturb and reckon with history. A group of Muslims offered shelter by a Hindu landowner are ambushed, sexually assaulted, burnt alive and otherwise brutally murdered. The reference to the Naroda Patiya massacre, in which 97 Muslims were killed in a day, is made clear by naming the chief perpetrator Baba Bajrangi (one of the actual accused was Bajrang Dal leader Babu Bajrangi).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Diplomat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 20:46:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-diplomat-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hindi cinema’s pathological obsession with Pakistan is so consistent that I just take it as a given now. Sometimes a film so virulent and stupid comes along—Gadar 2 (2023), Fighter (2024)—that it breaks the surface, but mostly it’s a lot of forgettable posturing and flag-waving. On some rare occasions, a film will introduce notes of doubt, or grace. I’ve come to expect it from Yash Raj’s action films, which treat cross-border matters with a strange mixture of cartoon villainy, human feeling and grudging respect. Sometimes it happens unexpectedly, like the recent war film Sky Force, which starts off strident but deescalates as it goes along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nadaaniyan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 08:53:30 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/nadaaniyan-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Star kid releases have become a toxic cycle in Hindi film. No one seems to derive any pleasure from them, yet there’s one every month. As soon as a trailer drops, thousands of angry posts appear, with nothing to go on but two minutes of promotion and a vague idea that sons and daughters of famous actors are the enemy. Even established stars who came through film families can’t catch a break; last year, the release of Jigra, starring Alia Bhatt, was marked by unprecedented negativity. But with the younger crop, there are problems beyond an apathetic and frustrated Hindi viewing public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brutalist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-brutalist-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 19:00:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-brutalist-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a short epilogue, The Brutalist finally shows us László Toth’s buildings. Brady Corbet’s film presents as a given that Toth is a genius architect of the Bauhaus school, but we are only shown one of his creations—a library—in full right up till the final 10 minutes. The format in which they’re presented is strange: a showreel for a biennale that looks like it’s shot on cheap video, with cheesy transitions. A film with startling pristine images spends its last moments looking like DTV. It&amp;rsquo;s a strange end to the film – and that’s without even getting into the whole Israel of it all. The Brutalist hits you several times with shots of roads and rail tracks zipping by, as seen from the front of a car or train. If the intention is to have the viewer recall the opening of Lawrence of Arabia, it worked on me. Corbet’s film has that David Lean sprawl, certainly in terms of runtime (202 minutes), but also in the ambition and density of its storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superboys of Malegaon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 23:17:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/superboys-of-malegaon-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Small cell carcinoma,” the doctor begins. Two blank faces stare at him. “Have you seen Anand?” he tries again. “What happened to Rajesh Khanna.” The simple point of Superboys of Malegaon is that, even at its bleakest, life can be made sweeter by cinema. The Anand reference softens the blow of a cancer diagnosis for two movie-crazy men who’ve travelled from the small town of Malegaon in Maharashtra. When they get back, the patient’s friends gently rib him about having a rich man’s ailment. Even the doctor’s life is made a little happier. He accepts a part in their upcoming film in return for home visits, saying he’d always wanted to be an actor but his father forbade it. Thirteen years earlier, Nasir (Adarsh Gourav) and Shafique (Shashank Arora) are on a motorbike, singing an improvised tune about not being too ambitious because they’ll end up dying in Malegaon anyway. It’s an early acceptance of the cards they’ve been dealt: Nasir to shoot wedding videos and work in his brother’s photo studio, Shafique in the mill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sabar Bonda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sabar-bonda-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 22:56:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sabar-bonda-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It speaks to the relaxed control of Sabar Bonda how animals freely roam the frame and steal our attention. An optimistic goat breaks away from the herd and approaches two humans eating their lunch; it’s shooed away unceremoniously. A cat draws our gaze as it walks across the screen before it’s spooked by yelling and runs off. As Anand (Bhushaan Manoj) talks to his friend Balya (Suraaj Suman), he glances at a nearby buffalo that’s lifted its tail and done its business. Rohan Parashuram Kanawade’s Marathi film, which won the World Cinema Grand Jury Prize at the Sundance Film Festival this month, is set in a village in Maharashtra. It’s close enough to Mumbai that Anand can take a bus there to perform his father’s last rites in his ancestral village. But it’s also a world removed, a place, in the local imagination at least, of opportunity and permissiveness, herbal shampoos and special friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chhaava</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 17:29:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/chhaava-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chhaava opens with a Maratha raid on a Mughal town. As he slashes his way through enemy ranks, Sambhaji (Vicky Kaushal) notices a crying boy caught in the skirmish. He returns the child to safety. I knew this image would return in some way and it did, about an hour later. A little girl herding goats on Maratha land wanders out of the frame. In the next shot, she’s staggering back, set on fire by advancing Mughal troops. There’s no such thing as a moral army, only propaganda and the tales we choose to tell ourselves. A French traveler to India in the early 18th century wrote about the devastation of one Maratha raid: “We camped out next to villages reduced to ashes… Women clutching their children in their arms, men contorted, as they had been overtaken by death… a sight of horror such as I had never seen before.” We see such a scene in Chhaava—but done by the Mughals. When the Marathas in Laxman Utekar’s film (based on a 1980 novel) burn down a town, there isn’t a human in sight, and the only casualty is property.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mehta Boys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-mehta-boys-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 10:49:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-mehta-boys-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boman Irani began acting in films in his 40s. From the start, it seemed like he’d always been there. He was a throwback to an earlier era of actors like Charles Laughton and Alex Guiness who were happy to disappear behind a wig, a fake nose, an accent. Irani could, of course, play it straight, like the father in Lakshya. But no one was better at going broad. His Khurana in Khosla Ka Ghosla and Asthana in Munnabhai M.B.B.S. are legend, but there’s a spectacular rogue’s gallery stretching from Darna Mana Hai to Don, Well Done Abba to Honeymoon Travels Pvt. Ltd to Jayeshbhai Jordaar. Irani stars in The Mehta Boys and does a fine, fussy, fretful job. It’s also his first film as director, co-written with Alexander Dinelaris (Birdman) and co-produced by his company, Irani Movietone. It’s a polite little film about a recently bereaved family, emotionally available, a bit shapeless. Not all directors start with a big swing, but this is closer to forward defence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mrs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 08:54:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mrs-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeo Baby’s The Great Indian Kitchen was intended for theatrical release in 2021, but likely benefitted from the covid restrictions that resulted in a digital-only release. With everyone stuck inside, it was the right time for a film about the value of domestic work. It was one of the most acclaimed films that year, and it seemed only natural to hear some months later that the Malayalam film would be remade in Hindi. What was surprising to me, though, was the director attached to the project. Arati Kadav has directed one feature (Cargo, 2019) and a handful of shorts. A slim filmography, and yet she’s one of the most distinctive voices working in Hindi cinema today. Her work till now has tended towards science-fiction with a warm, handmade quality. A remake never seemed like the right use of her capacity for whimsy and invention, though I was curious to see what direction she might take Jeo Baby&amp;rsquo;s film. Having watched Mrs., I’m hoping this is Kadav’s ‘one for them’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 11:47:27 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/deva-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When was the last time the hero in an Indian commercial film was introduced without any fanfare? Deva opens with downbeat credits composed of fractured surveillance images. And then its titular character just appears, riding his bike down a tunnel. No buildup. No flying bodies. No ‘Sparkling Star Shahid Kapoor’. Ten minutes later, Kapoor is, in effect, reintroduced: there are sundry hero shenanigans and a dance number. But the opening is enough to guess that this is a rare contemporary Hindi commercial film whose rhythms aren’t those of Tamil or Telugu cinema. Then again, its hurt, sombre rhythms aren&amp;rsquo;t classic Bollywood either—despite Dev being positioned before a mural of Deewaar while ‘Main Hoon Don’ plays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sky Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 21:49:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/sky-force-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week last year, a film released that seemed to epitomise popular Hindi cinema’s decline over a decade. Fighter might have set out to cash in on the success of Top Gun: Maverick, but it played like an advertisement for the sitting government at the centre. Releasing months before the general elections, the film—like Uri: The Surgical Strike in 2019—showed the prime minister as capable commander in chief while engaging in hysterical Pakistan-baiting. “Unhe dikhaana padega ki baap kaun hai (we’ll show them who daddy is),” the PM in the film says, a statesman-like sentiment befitting a Republic Day release. Sky Force also takes a ‘baap’ jab at Pakistan, but it’s a half-hearted swipe. As a fighter pilot film releasing on the weekend of 26 January, there are certain jingoistic beats directors Sandeep Kewlani and Abhishek Anil Kapur must feel they have to hit. And they do, but their heart isn’t in it. On the face of it, there’s not much to recommend this film—it&amp;rsquo;s underwritten, square and tries to pull off elaborate action on a clearly insufficient budget. But where Fighter tends towards rabid nationalism, Sky Force stumbles awkwardly in search of reconciliation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 08:24:36 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/emergency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were only two things I asked of Emergency. One was to literally see the presses stop (we’re shown this twice). The second was for Sam Manekshaw to call Indira Gandhi ‘sweetie’, like Vicky Kaushal does in Sam Bahadur (2023). This, surprisingly, wasn’t fulfilled. I&amp;rsquo;m certain the makers were aware of the legend of the army chief saying this to the prime minister, but chose to leave it out. Its absence says a lot about this curious film suspended between opposing impulses. Emergency isn’t what I was expecting. For starters, its focus isn’t the Emergency; the events of 1975-77 take up, at a rough estimate, half an hour in a 146-minute film. Instead, this is very much a Indira Gandhi biopic, progressing in linear fashion from her childhood to her assassination in 1984. Since it&amp;rsquo;s Kangana Ranaut—a BJP MP who has made a number of incendiary statements about minorities and protestors—directing, producing and playing Indira, I was expecting a crazed hatchet job. This too doesn’t happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Warrant</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:30:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/black-warrant-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“People say prison is a trashcan, but it’s really a circus,” DSP Tomar (Rahul Bhat) tells his new jailers. Black Warrant suggests that hangings are the circus’ circus. The sentenced are celebrities of the prison world. The visiting hangmen are celebrities for the Tihar staff. Inmates become nervy; reporters start asking questions. Everyone’s on edge—all except ASP Dahiya (Anurag Thakur), grinning broadly as he massages banana pulp onto a noose. The best Hindi streaming shows of the past few years are carefully built from the ground up, the longer runtimes allowing for more complex narratives but also challenge creators to populate and make believable specific universes—stock markets, village councils, counterfeit operations. I didn’t know hanging ropes were once smoothened with mashed banana. It’s not a vital piece of information; you’d miss it altogether if you weren’t paying attention for those three seconds in the second episode. But it&amp;rsquo;s sort of detail that gives me confidence, tells me the makers have burrowed deep inside their setting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baby John</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 13:09:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/baby-john-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A boy of maybe five or six stands over his dead parents. They’re in a row of bodies on the ground in front of a high-rise, construction workers who died because of low-quality netting. The builder at fault calls the boy over (he&amp;rsquo;s from the northeast—migrant labour!), gives him 10 rupees and tells him to buy some chocolate. In the next scene, John (Varun Dhawan) crashes the builder&amp;rsquo;s party, decimates his goons, and sends the man crashing through a window to his death. One of the onlookers is the young boy, who takes a triumphant bite of chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Despatch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 18:10:07 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/despatch-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a moment late in Despatch when Manoj Bajpayee looks, suddenly and disconcertingly, like his character from Kaun? (1999). It made me think of the giddy fun of that turn, driving Urmila Matondkar half-crazy with those nagging ma’ams. It also made me wonder—despite the obvious differences—what this film might have been like with that Bajpayee performance. Bajpayee once played heels with obvious relish, whereas his character in Despatch is wrapped in disgust and disdain, a bitter pill to spend two hours with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Want to Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 08:36:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/i-want-to-talk-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shoojit Sircar’s recent film work has been preoccupied with mortality. Shiuli’s freak accident and subsequent state determine the course of October (2018). Gulabo Sitabo (2020) is a comic look at death, with an ageing man hoping for the demise of his even older wife. And Sardar Udham is death-haunted, not just the historical fact of the protagonist’s execution but the guiding hand of the ghosts of Jallianwala Bagh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I Want To Talk, directed by Sircar and written by Ritesh Shah, introduces the possibility of death about 10 minutes in, and never lets it fade from view. Arjun (Abhishek Bachchan) is a marketing professional in California, highly successful if rather unfeeling and shallow. During a presentation, he starts coughing violently. The next scene is Arjun in hospital. The scene after that, a doctor tells him he has cancer and probably 100 days to live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Portrait as a Coffee Pot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/self-portrait-as-a-coffee-pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 11:21:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/self-portrait-as-a-coffee-pot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A portly white-haired man walks into the frame and, even before he’s sat, addresses the camera with some urgency. “Before he arrives, there are some things I just want to say. It’s about the nature of the structure of, and the destructure, and the non-structure of what we see.&amp;quot; He lists the disparate thoughts running through his head: a green cake he once ate in Naples, the fish pie he must take out of the freezer, a line from Mayakovsky, digging in &lt;em&gt;The Great Escape&lt;/em&gt; and as a young boy on the beach, a row of coffins for mass burial, the impending birth of his granddaughter&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom at Midnight</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:27:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/freedom-at-midnight-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s 1946, Partition is starting to look like a real possibility, and the Congress High Command isn’t a happy place. The visiting Akali leaders are militant, Nehru is getting worked up, and Patel’s biscuit, which he isn’t paying attention to, is getting soggy. At the exact moment Nehru asks the Akalis what they want, half of it disintegrates and falls into the tea. The next shot is Jinnah in his garden, snipping a rose stem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citadel: Honey Bunny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 16:28:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/citadel-honey-bunny-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you get what you want, but it’s not what you need. Since 2018, Raj &amp;amp; DK have been on a creative streak. It began with Stree, a horror-comedy sleeper hit they wrote and produced. The following year, their first series, The Family Man, premiered on Amazon Prime; they show-ran and co-directed it over two seasons (a third is in the works). This was followed by two more shows, Farzi (on Amazon)—my favourite of their long-form work—and Guns &amp;amp; Gulaabs (on Netflix). With each success, the possibility that Hollywood would come calling seemed likelier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Patti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 15:02:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/do-patti-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do Patti begins with scattered shots of paragliding gone wrong and a stakeout on a bridge, followed by a woman in a police station telling the cops her husband tried to kill her. Phir Aayi Hasseen Dillruba, released in August, also has a stakeout on a bridge, and its first scene is a woman in a police station telling the cops her husband is going to kill her. Both films are written by Kanika Dhillon, both are Netflix releases. Did no one think it was a problem that the films start the exact same way?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Real Superstar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-real-superstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 18:34:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/the-real-superstar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aman in red suede pants and jacket walks down a deserted road at night. Another man in a sky blue jacket over a black shirt races across a bridge as gunfire explodes around him. Yet another, in a deep blue shirt knotted at the waist, staggers out of a warehouse and is immediately carried off by a delirious crowd chanting his name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any Hindi cinema fan could read these descriptions and tell you they’re all the same man. Most could probably name the films as well — &lt;em&gt;Majboor&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Sholay&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Deewaar&lt;/em&gt;. What would these fans make of a new film in which all these scenes appear in the space of 10 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jigra</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 18:38:28 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/jigra-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Satya has been running from window to window in the anteroom of a maximum security prison. She’s desperate to see her brother before closing time, but there are forms to fill, procedures to follow. Finally, she ends up at the door to the visiting area, wheezing, frantic. The guard does her a kindness, says she isn’t late and will be let in soon. Satya catches her breath, but can’t wipe the worry off. “Do I look sad?” she asks the guard as she’s about to enter. “Little sad,” he replies in Malay-accented English. She puts on a strained smile. “Now?” The guard shakes his head. “Very sad, lah.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CTRL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 08:20:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/ctrl-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well into CTRL, we know the film&amp;rsquo;s protagonist only as Nella. While it’s certainly an Ananya Panday character name (past ones have been Tia, Tanya, Ahana and Bella), I did wonder if it was given by her Delhi Punjabi parents. But then we hear her father’s voice from offscreen calling: “Nalini”. And a little piece clicked into place: an assumed name, a username, a handle, in a film about unstable online identities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
