<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mukkam Post Bombilwadi on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mukkam Post Bombilwadi on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:11:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mukkam Post Bombilwadi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 15:11:46 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmmaker Paresh Mokashi’s Mukkam Post Bombilwadi is based on his own Marathi play of the same name. The story takes place in 1942 when World War II is in full swing. Adolf Hitler (Prashant Damle) is under pressure for not having won the war despite fighting it for years, especially from his wife Eva (Deepti Lele). Winston Churchill (Anand Ingle), the Prime Minister of Great Britain, is making things more difficult for him. Meanwhile, in Bombilwadi village in Maharashtra’s Konkan, Varvante (Vaibhav Mangle) heads a theatre group. He is struggling hard to rehearse for a play with the members of his troupe (Devendra Pem, Geetanjali Kulkarni and Ritika Shrotri). Vaidya Buwa (Sunil Abhyankar) and Bhaskar (Pranav Raorane), who are also a part of the theatre group, have made a bomb to blow up Britishers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mukkam Post Bombilwadi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 12:24:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/mukkam-post-bombilwadi-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around two decades ago, Paresh Mokashi gave the Marathi theatre audience a play called Mukkam Post Bombilwadi, which revolved around an absurd but hilarious story. For the big screen, Mokashi and team adapt the same premise on a cinematic scale. Set in 1942, Mukkam Post Bombilwadi unfolds in three locations – Adolf Hitler&amp;rsquo;s office in Germany, Winston Churchill’s war room in London, and the sleepy village of Bombilwadi in Konkan, Maharashtra. Amid mounting tensions of World War II, Hitler (Prashant Damle) gets a call about some innovation in Japan that can help him win the war. In no mood to waste time, Hitler decides to fly to Japan on his own (despite not knowing how to fly a plane). In the meantime, Churchill’s (Anand Ingale) spies tell him about Hitler’s plan and the British PM vows to stop Hitler come what may. The story then shifts to Bombilwadi, where multiple things are unfolding – a play is being rehearsed, a British police officer in love with Hitler’s partner Eva Braun is more focused on staging Shakespeare’s plays than maintaining law and order in Bombilwadi, and freedom fighters are plotting to send the Brits back with the ‘do or die’ slogan. In between all this, Hitler crash-lands in Bombilwadi. How, and what happens later is what the film is largely about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
