<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kanneda on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/mreviews/kanneda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kanneda on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:42:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/mreviews/kanneda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kanneda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:42:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nimma, a Punjabi immigrant, faces racism, forcing him into Sarab’s gang. He rises quickly, but Rawat’s mole threatens their empire. Gang wars erupt, demanding Nimma’s fierce loyalty. Sarab’s arrest leaves Nimma vulnerable, surviving an attack. A coma, addiction, and betrayal follow. Sarab escapes, leading to a vengeful confrontation between him and Nimma, fuelled by chaos and loss. Parmish Verma, the popular musician, bares his heart out to portray the angst and the chaos within Nimma. However, with more effort to internalise the role, he could have created a more lasting impact. Aadar Malik, as Nimma’s on-screen bestie and musician, has an impressive screen presence, helping him emote with precision. Kanneda is an important show, capturing the immigrant experience through an insider’s lens, reminding us that Indian stories needn’t always be home-soil bound. The series serves as a cautionary tale, depicting a 90s Punjabi life in Canada gone wrong – a musician lost in drugs, crimes, and gangs. Despite everyone’s attempts to help and transform him, redemption eludes him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanneda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:01:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;कन्नेडा&amp;rsquo; वेब सीरीज के नरेटर मोहम्मद जीशान अय्यूब के शब्दों में कहें तो इसे समझने के लिए कनाडा देश को समझना होगा, जहां दो देश बसते हैं। एक गोरों की फर्स्ट वर्ल्ड कंट्री &amp;lsquo;कैनेडा&amp;rsquo; और दूसरा थर्ड वर्ल्ड कंट्री से आए प्रवासियों का &amp;lsquo;कन्नेडा&amp;rsquo;, जिसके निवासियों को सेकंड क्लास सिटीजन समझा जाता था। यह कहानी इसी तबके के एक ऐसे बंदे निर्मल चहल उर्फ निम्मा (परमीश वर्मा) की है, जो कनाडा और कन्नेडा के बीच की इस दूरी को मिटाने के लिए कुछ भी करने पर आमादा हो जाता है। साल 1984 के दंगों के बाद अपना पिंड पंजाब छोड़कर वैंकूवर में बसा निम्मा पढ़ाई, खेलकूद, म्यूजिक हर चीज में अव्वल होता है। स्कूल में वह गोरों के खेल रग्बी में सिलेक्ट होने वाला पहला ब्राउन मुंडा बनता है, मगर गोरे साजिशन उसे ड्रग रखने के जुर्म में फंसाकर टीम से निकाल देते हैं। इसके बाद निम्मे को यकीन हो जाता है कि वह कितनी भी मेहनत कर ले, खुद को सुपीरियर समझने वाले कनाडा वासी उसे वह इज्जत नहीं देंगे। इसलिए वह ताकत और पैसा हासिल करके यह इज्जत कमाने का ठान लेता है।&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kanneda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 23:38:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reviews/kanneda/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kanneda, the title of this eight-episode drama, is “Canada” pronounced with a Punjabi twang. The theme is clear — an Indian immigrant story that unfolds in the awkward cultural gap between Kanneda and Canada. The setting is Vancouver in the 1990s; the narrator helpfully tells us that racism is rampant and Punjabis continue to be treated as second-class citizens. The central character is Nirmal ‘Nimma’ Chahal (Parmish Verma), a young and hotheaded chap who slowly mutates from fairytale to cautionary tale. It’s a familiar journey: Nimma starts off honest (a rugby scholarship to kickstart a music career), before losing faith in the system and getting into the drugs-and-gangster business. Flashbacks allegedly suggest that his family left Punjab during the 1984 Anti-Sikh riots, but his trauma looks anything but generational.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
